<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-03T08:27:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Liberty Belle Newsletter</title><subtitle>A day-by-day account of our time aboard the Liberty Belle narrowboat.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Idling on the Chesterfield</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/10/02/idling-on-the-chesterfield.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Idling on the Chesterfield" /><published>2021-10-02T17:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-02T17:01:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/10/02/idling-on-the-chesterfield</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/10/02/idling-on-the-chesterfield.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Boston along the Chesterfield (Canal not sofa)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19th - 29th July 2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n100map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210722-P1380917.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Along the beautiful Chesterfield Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived back in Boston on Monday 19th July to find Liberty Belle waiting patiently on the pontoon. We set off from there and followed the River Witham and Foss Dyke back to Torksey Lock, hoping to be let out again onto the River Trent on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather was hot and the water was covered in duck weed and fairy moss. We saw grebes, heron, terns and cormorants, as well as the usual ducks, moorhen and swans. There were pink swathes of campion and willow-herb interspersed with meadow-sweet. Relief from the heat came in the form of big, fat raindrops sounding like a very slow handclap on the roof of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony contacted the lock keeper at Torksey to book our passage. He was told that the tides were a bit awkward, so we should go through the lock on the Tuesday evening and moor on the pontoon immediately beyond the lock until 2pm on Wednesday, before heading off along the river. Complicated stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210719_103847621.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bye Bye Boston&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380743.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A bit of industry on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210719-P1380708cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lapwings, one of our favourites.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210719-P1380729.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another of our favourites, too busy nest building to notice us go by.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210719_204631845cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We see lots of damselflies, as well as meatier dragonflies, but this is the first photo.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380746.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The awkward turning into Bardney Lock on the River Witham.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380754cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sustrans' &quot;Water Rail Way&quot; Sculpture. This cycle route follows a disused railway line from Boston to Lincoln.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380760cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A heron enjoying the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our view of Lincoln Cathedral as we approach the city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380772.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Entering Lincoln's guillotine lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A red light means no entry,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Green means it is being operated for you.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Amber means do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380782.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing under 'Empowerment', the elegant sculpture over the river in Lincoln.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380791.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Showing the vaulting of the Medieval Glory Hole.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn't stop in Lincoln on the way back but we did draw into the side of the Foss Dyke Canal in Saxilby. I jumped off the boat and raced over the bridge to the shops. A man sitting on a bench alongside the moorings queried my rush. I explained that I was dashing to the ice cream shop. Seeing that Tony wasn't tying up the boat he suggested that he might go and leave me behind. I told the man that if that happened he could have Tony's ice-cream. He was disappointed, when I returned with two cones, that Tony was still there waiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210720-P1380811.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Emergency ice-cream on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210720_120916332.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New bridges can be good looking.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at Torksey Lock we found that there were so many boats waiting outside that it was difficult to find somewhere to moor. The first lock-load of boats went in and things seemed a bit heated with some frustration and angry shouting, the whole process seeming to take rather longer than necessary. We were curious but kept our heads down and thought it best not to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually they all left the lock, it was refilled and it was our turn along with another narrow boat and some cruisers. This time things proceded smoothly; down we went and out we popped. The space on the pontoon was tight, there were so many of us mooring there overnight, so we doubled up with the other narrow boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing notes, it came to light that the boaters had slightly differing ideas on what time we were meant to set off from the pontoon into the river flow on Wednesday. So, we checked again with the Lock keeper first thing in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boats travelling north on the river to Stockwith Lock on the Chesterfield Canal (that's us), were again told to leave at 2pm, but those heading south to Cromwell Lock were to leave earlier. The water would be high enough for us to travel by 2pm and we would go with the flow of the outgoing tide, arriving at Cromwell Lock at the turn of the tide (4:30), enabling us to turn into the lock at slack water. (I think...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the wait, Tony and I settled down to get some jobs done. Meanwhile we spotted a mink on the bank opposite the boat and a kingfisher flew past a couple of times. During the night the water level had gone down creating some interesting glooping noises around the boat and exposing a lot of mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the morning the mud gradually disappeared again as we were lifted with the tide. The boat numbers decreased as some headed for Cromwell Lock, leaving an increasingly fidgety set of skippers behind on the pontoon. Soon boats began to leave, far too early. Our fellow narrow boater could wait no longer and off she went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, at 13:45, finding ourselves on our own, we also jumped the gun and set off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210721-P1380818.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here we go, back onto the River Trent.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210721-P1380860.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Emergency radio at the ready.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As instructed, Tony phoned the Stockwith lockeeper as we travelled through Gainsborough. We were told that we were ahead of ourselves, the tide wasn't right yet and there were a lot of boats waiting so we were advised to slow down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally arrived at the lock, one of the cruisers ahead of us was bobbing around near the entrance, so we tried to do the same. It came to light that we had slowed down a bit too much and had missed the slack tide, so now the water flow had turned and was against us. Narrowboats are not designed to remain stationary on moving water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tide and the skipper fought each other for control of Liberty Belle, each one gaining and losing in turn. Eventually, after half an hour of this tussle, the lock gates opened and the cruiser entered the lock in a twisty, tossy, twitchy, second attempt sort of way. Then it was our turn. The water had pulled us a bit too close to the side, so Tony had to try and get further into the middle of the river before he could attempt the sharp left turn into the lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I desperately tried to help by tensing all my muscles and gripping the boat with my hands and feet. My knuckles turned white. I dared not turn around and look at Tony. I kept my eyes fixed on the lock keeper. Liberty Belle was being forced by the current towards the upstream wall of the lock but Tony managed to touch her nose against the opposite wall and the lock keeper shouted advice. Between them Tony and the lock keeper got us in there. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210721-P1380879.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Travelling straight through Gainsborough.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210721-P1380884cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A basking crocodile.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210721-P1380887.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A stressful wait outside West Stockwith Lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210721-P1380893.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Safely onto the Chesterfield Canal. Tony's face says it all!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we had moored up we went for a post-trauma pint in the Waterside Inn, overlooking the basin, and a walk along the nearby River Idle to release the tension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had all gone well. Thank goodness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were curious to see the River Idle because it is meant to be navigable, as long as you give the Environment Agency 48 hours notice because they need to raise the sluice gate to let you through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sluice gates looked formidable and the river seemed to be in a culvert without much of a view, so we weren't tempted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210721_190731016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Blurry drinkers!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210721_200226649_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Idle walk. The river is down a ditch on the left...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The sluice is in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210721_201545501_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The impressive old pump houses on the River Idle are now a private residence.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210728_194559715_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A not-so-peaceful overnight mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off the next morning, pleased to be on a canal again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chesterfield Canal is rural and pretty with clear water through which you can see that it is teaming with fish - we noted rudd, perch and pike but there were probably others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fields alongside the canal had ripe wheat, flowering beans and whispy oats, as well as fields of cows. The air smelt alternately of honey and things stirred up from the bottom of the canal - quite a contrast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our time there we didn't see much in the way of birdlife but we did see a mink chasing a rat in the water and a grass snake curled up on one of the piles of weed that had been dragged from the canal and dumped on the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210726-P1390007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony managed to take a photo of the fish...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210727-P1390056cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and Slinky Minky&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of shallow locks, some of them double or treble staircases, (locks, which share middle gates and feed directly one into another). However, some of the paddles weren't operating and there was a shortage of water, (it was about 10 inches down), both of which made progress slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210724-P1380978.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It is so lovely to be on a canal again.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210727_140850634.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Shifting the weed away from the lock gates.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210727-P1390036.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Such an expert!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210723-P1040693.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Skipper climbing out to help the crew.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we pottered along we met lots of friendly people enjoying the canal in the sunshine who stopped for a chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one lock there were a few people relaxing, including a young man, smoking weed. He politely asked if we would leave the lock full for him so that he could swim in it. We were going uphill so that would be the natural state of the lock when we left, so, having warned him of the dangers of getting stuck in the silt at the bottom of a lock we did indeed, leave it full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One morning we managed to complete 24 locks before lunch, helped by friendly member of the Chesterfield Canal Trust. He explained that the lack of water was caused by some work being carried out at the top of the canal, temporarily preventing the feeder canal from supplying enough water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210722-P1380902.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old engine house, outstanding in its field.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210722_193433412_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It seems as if it was a busy canal in its day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210724-P1380992.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This mooring sign isn't ideally positioned...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210722-P1380904.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....nor are these cows.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210728-P1390074.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This canal bridge capstone has a bearded face carved on it, but it is wearing away...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210725-P1390004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...this entire bridge is being braced from beneath.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our journey we stopped off in Retford which is a pleasant town with some old buildings and a beautiful public park with the River Idle flowing gently through it. There were plenty of people around, making good use of the park's secluded gardens, open fields, shady trees, play areas and of course, the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a dam across, forming a shallow paddling section and a slightly deeper area where people of all ages were swimming and cooling off in the sunshine. There was also a large field with a substantial covered stage and a sloping grassy bank. What a wonderful resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210725-P1040699.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Apparently it is a rampant chough... one of a pair featured on Retford's town crest.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210722_185659537.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Retford's Kings Park. The fingerposts are essential for finding your way around.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the end of the navigation. Well, not quite. We reached the final turning space on the Chesterfield Canal and moored. In order to claim the brass plaque declaring completion of the canal, you have to cruise to the end (and have photographic evidence) then reverse back to the turning space. This seemed to us to be a step too far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead we walked the final stretch of canal and went to explore Wales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were surprised too, but we weren't lost, it turns out to be the name of an old mining town, now with a large public park built where the colliery used to be. The park was very pleasant with some boards erected explaining the history of the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One in particular showed the instructions given to new miners explaining, in comical detail, how to use the facilities at the bath house - where to deposit work clothes and clean clothes and how not to lose your soap!&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A park doesn't employ people like a colliery does, so consequently the town itself was very run down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210724_141121149_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The end of navigation without a winding hole.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beneath is the unrestored Norwood tunnel which, one day, may take the canal another 15 miles to Chesterfield.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210724_143334923_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The colliery head office in Wales, still in use as a public building in the Community Sports Park.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst still moored at the end we decided to walk back along the canal towards Worksop hoping to see a horse drawn barge that had been advertised for that day in a leaflet given to us by the lock keeper at Stockwith. We took a small picnic and headed in the direction of the pub where the horse and barge were due to set off from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly there was no sign of the horse or anyone waiting for it to happen, so we assumed it had been cancelled and everyone knew but us and the lock keeper! We enjoyed the walk though and it gave us a chance to explore Worksop and have a canal-side beer to complement our picnic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210725_132654794_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Worksop Priory. We arrived just as it was being locked up for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210725-P1040701.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Old canal-side buildings in Worksop, re-born as a business and retail park.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Smart.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our walk, returning to Liberty Belle, we came across another boat that had been moored at the end, near us but was now at the moorings a little further down. The skipper was on the phone, complaining about the lack of water in the canal, presumably to the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust. Oh heck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that it would be a good idea to move our boat too, just in case we ended up stranded here, in the mud - we needed to run the engine for hot water anyway. We hoped to get through a lock or two before the end of the day. As we approached the top lock we met a CRT man who asked us to stop there whilst he checked the water situation. On his return he requested that we stay there until the pounds below us were refilled the following day. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, we waited all the following morning. We went for a walk and discovered that the pounds were in a similar state from when we had come up, low but not desperately so....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the promised CRT man turned up we recognised him as lock keeper who had seen us through the Stockwith Lock. He eventually gave us the go-ahead and we found that he had kindly left all the locks in our favour. With a team effort we made reasonable progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving at a small collection of houses between the locks we were pleasantly surprised to see a man with a windlass setting the next lock for us. How kind! It turned out to be one of the residents whose house is regularly in danger of flooding when boats come down the flight. He was letting some water through the lock instead of bailing out his cellar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210727-P1390038.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another outstanding (in its field) engine house.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210728-P1390079.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A tight turn.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a two day journey from there to get back to Stockwith, where we were expected for our booking through the lock back onto the river on 29th July. To focus our minds on getting there Tony booked us a table for dinner at 5pm on 28th in The Hart Inn, Stockwith for pie night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way, we came across the boat we had moored up against at Torksey Lock's pontoon. She and her friend on another boat had moored up at a lock landing, giving Tony nowhere to drop me off to work the lock. It was still early so we thought they might not have seen us so I went to the front of the boat, Tony brought Liberty Belle's nose forward to touch the gate and I managed to climb out onto the lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman on the boat realised what was happening and was very apologetic. They had been told they would get mooring there but only the lock landing was available. They had hoped to move on before anyone came along. To make up for causing us difficulty she helped to work the lock for us, so we forgave her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pie night was a success, with friendly, chatty locals at the next table, excellent beer brewed on the premises and delicious home made pies at extremely good prices. The landlord stressed that the pandemic had cost his business dear and he couldn't take another hit of any kind, so he might have to give up. We hope not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a lovely evening but Tony woke up the next morning to the stress of the impending trip on the Trent to Keadby. We were booked in for 12:30, so he had all morning to think about it and couldn't settle to anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out the turning of the tide was later than predicted and we had to wait for 2 boats travelling from Keadby to come up in the lock before we would be let down. We went to watch them come along the river with the lock keeper (now quite familiar to us) and another boating couple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind was strong. The lock keeper and other boaters were discussing the strength of it. The other people due to travel with us had cancelled because of the weather. We watched the two narrow boats struggle to turn into the lock. Golly, it looked choppy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last it was our turn. There was wind and there were waves. Liberty Belle's propeller buzzed whenever it left the water as we rose and fell in the waves, but all was well, her engine did us proud as we ploughed on through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard to see the lock as we approached it because a huge working barge was blocking our view, but we could see the welcoming green traffic light shining above it and Tony skilfully u-turned, facing the tide and powered us into the lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationtalk&quot;&gt;Keadby lock keeper - &quot;That was the best lock entrance of the day!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;conversationlisten&quot;&gt;Tony - &quot;Was it the only one?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;conversationtalk&quot;&gt;Keadby Lock keeper - &quot;Yes.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210729-P1390104.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Out of West Stockwith, back on the River Trent&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/20210729-P1390131.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our left turn into Keadby Lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
Parts of the instructions for miners!
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210724_142954154cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What to do on your first day at work.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n100/IMG_20210724_142959917cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... and on subsequent days!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What's Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here we are on the Lancaster Canal, wishing we hadn't taken our winter clothes back to the house. We had fully intended to be home before the weather turned...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are booked to go back across the Ribble Link to the Leeds and Liverpool Canal on 6th October. From there we will be making a dash for the ABNB brokers in North Kilworth Marina.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Boston along the Chesterfield (Canal not sofa) 19th - 29th July 2021 Our route</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hither &amp;amp; Thither</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/09/19/hither-and-thither.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hither &amp; Thither" /><published>2021-09-19T20:47:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-09-19T20:47:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/09/19/hither-and-thither</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/09/19/hither-and-thither.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Tamworth to Boston&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;25th June - 14th July 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n99map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210630-P1380221cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Yep, all of the above, and more...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG-20210625-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary at dinnette&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle waited at Fazeley Junction for us to fetch Mary in a hire car. We arrived back to find the boat just as we had left her, which is always a relief. Tony took back the car whilst Mary and I went to fetch our much anticipated fish and chips. It didn't disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to take Mary on a trip along the River Trent and the River Witham to reach Boston, but with a few diversions on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the network involves the tidal sections of the River Trent which can only be attempted when the tide is high enough. The locks entering and leaving these sections must be booked ahead with the lock keepers who operate the locks, count you onto the river and count you off again, as well as supervising your entry into and exit from the fast flowing, deep water.... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving out of flowing water to turn at right angles into a lock mouth is very unnerving, even with a lock keeper standing on the wall miming instructions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get to the River Trent we needed to turn onto the Coventry Canal and follow it until it joined the Trent and Mersey which would then take us to the junction of the rivers Trent and Soar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our lunch in Fazeley was over, we set off along the Coventry Canal to Lichfield. Well, as close as you can get by boat, which is a couple of miles outside the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three of us know Lichfield. Tony and I have been there on Liberty Belle and Mary's sister lived there for some years. We decided that we would like to go and spend some time there, if the weather looked ok for the walk, which it was, so off we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We couldn't go inside the Cathedral immediately because there was a ceremony in full swing involving local dignitaries, so we hung around outside for a bit, but it was worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210626_121308140.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Outside Litchfield Cathedral, the service is over and a procession walks to unveil the new statue of Saint Chad.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210626_122747443cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Chad reluctant to let go of his protection from the cold wind!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210626_132151956.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the Cathedral, a dedication to the Adams family, part of the history of Stoke's pottery industry.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210626_130043290.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Lichfield Angel, possibly part of the shrine of St Chad, was unearthed in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch in a local cafe, then, suitably fortified, wandered back to the boat. We moved on to Fradley Junction to moor for the night, which was very busy with boats, as it was last time we were there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a little wander around Fradley Pool Nature Reserve. The lake was originally built as a reservoir to feed the canal, in the 1780s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210627-P1040608.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pub beside the lock at Fradley Junction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210627_093056946_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fradley Pool has a beautifully constructed wooden, thatched bird hide.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210627-P1040601.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fradley Pool's pond dipping station.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210627-P1040604.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Somewhere to sit, or maybe climb.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Fradley we turned onto the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey Canal as far as Alrewas where we moored and had a wander around in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210627_143903754_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Outside All Saints Church, Alrewas, a hatch through which a leper could see and hear the service.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210627_144733531.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The same hatch from the inside, now fitted with a stained glass window.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Alrewas, Tony steered Liberty Belle, Mary walked ahead along the towpath and I did the locks. There was a noisy road running alongside this section of the Trent and Mersey, replaced eventually by a railway track along which very long and heavy goods trains ran in the early hours, (apparently..... ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite that it was pretty with the yellows of earlier in the year now replaced by pale roses, blackberry flowers and meadowsweet with the occasional purple vetch peeping out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at Burton on Trent and had a wander into town but there was disappointingly little to see, so we moved on to Willington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210628-P1040618.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle,
passing a traditional wooden barge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG-20210628-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ah!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG-20210628-WA0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary and Tony in a malt shovel was as close as we got to a pint of Pedigree...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210628-P1380118.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the locks onto the river with a sign warning us to check the water level before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210628-P1380120.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The water level on the gauge is 'in the green', so all is well.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first little diversion from our main route was a short trip down the Upper Trent as far as Cavendish Bridge. As we approached the end of the navigable section of the river, several people on the bank shouted to us not to go under the bridge in front of us. We already knew that we couldn't do that but had seen a section just before the bridge on the opposite bank which may or may not have been moorings, so we shouted back, asking about mooring. All responses were negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With difficulty, because of the water flow, Tony turned Liberty Belle and we left the way we had come. Rejoining the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey Canal, we finally moored in Sawley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210629-P1380170.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazards along the way:-&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;a sunken boat at the landing stage making collecting crew a bit tricky...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210629-P1380173cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...more underwater obstacles...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210629-P1380180.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and paddling cows....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;not what Mary was expecting to see so close up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210629-P1380214.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the plus side, the flood gates welcomed us with open arms.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210629_182805_889.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our view from the Sawley mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pretty in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than go straight onto the River Trent from Sawley Lock, our plan was to turn south onto the River Soar first and head to Loughborough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had already been there with Liberty Belle but had approached from the south and arrived just as both the rivers Soar and Trent went into flood so we hadn't gone beyond Loughborough. Now was our chance to fill in the gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way we saw swallows, house martins and sand martins swooping down to the water and I attempted (yet again) to try and distinguish between them as they darted around us. Tony's patience with my questions on flora and fauna appears to be infinite....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210630-P1380254.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Nowhere could we see the red light.... maybe it is more visible when flashing.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210630-P1380253cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Golly, it really would have to be an emergency to want to moor there.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210630-P1040628.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sluices open!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG-20210701-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A bit of better weather.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored in Loughborough Basin for the night and took Mary to see the sights the following morning. Tony and I are rather fond of the town, having been forced to spend so much time there, but really, a morning is all you need for sightseeing. So, after lunch we headed back along the river, the way we had come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210630_164720658.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the benches made to celebrate Loughborough's connection with
Ladybird books.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210630_164504548_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;My favourite sculpture, The Sock Man, dutifully wearing a mask.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210701_111950697.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary outside Loughborough's Carnegie library...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210701_113609520_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and Carillion Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving back at the junction of the Soar and Trent, we continued north for our next diversion onto the Erewash Canal. We had heard discouraging stories of the Erewash. Not many people travel along it because the locks are so difficult to operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met a boater who had been living on his boat for 15 years and had never attempted the Erewash because of the stories he had heard and he wished us luck with it. We decided that we would attempt it and turn around if it proved to be beyond our capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside the first lock was a pub. One of the customers called out to me that I would have muscles like Popeye by the time I had finished the journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We soldiered on and managed to complete the 4 locks to our first mooring in Sandiacre without too much difficulty, then 6 more to Ilkeston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we completed the last 5 locks and arrived at the end of the canal at Langley Mill. What was the problem? The canal was absolutely delightful and the locks had been no more difficult to use than most others around the country.

&lt;p&gt;On arrival in the basin we were encouraged to moor outside the boaters' services, alongside the water tap, which seemed very wrong but was apparently the norm for visiting boats. They get so few of them that we were unlikely to be disturbed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The return journey we did in one day, all 14 locks back to Trent Lock. Before leaving we promised one of the CRT volunteers that we would spread the word that the Erewash locks were no more difficult than on any other stretch of canal and was well worth visiting.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Like most canals it fell into disuse and was almost lost to us but in this case it was saved and restored by the Erewash Canal Preservation and Development Association, (ECPDA), formed in 1967 and still going strong.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Not without opposition though. One councillor wanted it filled in and is quoted as saying &quot; the hump back bridge over the canal causes unnecessary expenditure of energy to those walking to the local hostelry&quot;!&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;One of the ways the association fought back was to organise a Pie and Peas Cruise every winter from the pub which battles through even when the canal is frozen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210702-P1380277.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Waiting to go through Trent Lock onto the Erewash Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210705-P1380341.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sandiacre Lock cottages and toll house, now ECPDA HQ&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210702-P1380291.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Rural Erewash....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210702-P1380286.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and old industrial Erewash.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210705-P1380321.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Low bridges...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210705-P1380325.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and narrow sections.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210702_162503630_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lager and lime anyone?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving the Erewash, we joined the River Trent briefly but turned off again, this time onto the Nottingham &amp;amp; Beeston Canal, mooring for the night at Castle Meadow in Nottingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We treated ourselves to lunch out in Nottingham and then had a look around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary knows Nottingham as she used to work in Boots the Chemists there, but the city has changed a bit since then and is even now undergoing more changes. There were hoardings and barriers up, holes being dug, old buildings being demolished and new ones under construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210706-P1380353.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Right turn!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210706-P1380364.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Relaxed skipper on the River Trent&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210706-P1380365.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A sign of much higher waters.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210706-P1380371.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A cormorant weir warden.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210706-P1380373.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Safely off the river onto Nottingham and Beeston Canal&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380393.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New canalside buildings under construction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380385.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A raft of renovators. It's all go in Nottingham.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210706_141805077.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Robin Hood's rather over-generous thigh!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Nottingham we went back onto the river for a two day journey to Cromwell Tidal Lock, for which we had a booking, pausing at Hazelford Ferry and Newark on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stopping at Newark proved to be tricky. The mooring was on the right hand side just beyond a large, multi-arched bridge. Tony attempted to pass through the right-hand arch but the water flow was too strong and he had to reverse hard to prevent a collision with the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second attempt he went through the middle arch instead, turning in a wide arc to face the water flow, with another boat approaching mid-manoeuvre. With the water flow against him he had to drive hard back towards the bridge and into the mooring space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heart in mouth we made it and waved a thank you to the other boat who had waited patiently for us to sort ourselves out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a little look around and ran a few errands before setting off again and mooring in front of Cromwell Lock to wait for our passage the following morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380391.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kind people around here provide nest platforms for coots....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380389.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...using whatever comes to hand.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380422.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Teetering lambs...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380421.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and calves were a feature of the river banks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380457.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazelford Lock mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380455.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;51&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony checking for sand martins' nests.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210708-P1380461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;52&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazelford Lock weir is a pretty sight...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210708-P1380477.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;53&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....but there seems to be nothing to stop you heading straight over it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210708-P1380505.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing Newark Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210708_151311938_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;55&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;Moored facing the way we had come, with Newark's bridge in front of us.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210708_150715827.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;56&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Enjoying the sunshine in the grounds of Newark Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210708_145830000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;57&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A representaion of Newark Castle in its heyday.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380522.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;58&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cromwell Lock moorings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We were going to moor against the wall but sandmartins were nesting in holes where the shuttering bolts were missing, so we joined the other boats at the pontoon.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Cromwell Lock, the owner of one of the other waiting boats had only had it for a week and was taking it to Sheffield where she works. She had a friend coming the following morning to provide moral support for her trip on the tidal bit of the Trent to Torksey. A tricky bit of the network to attempt as a novice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 10 a.m. the following morning we were all released through Cromwell Lock onto the river. We chugged along, not really noticing the tidal movement until we tried to turn off the river into Torksey Lock, where we suddenly felt the water dragging us away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were pleased and relieved to be on a canal again. This time a Roman built one, the Foss Dyke. We stopped for lunch then carried on to Saxilby despite the warning from another boater that we might not find a mooring there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was too hot to just sit in the boat so moving along seemed to be the best option. We were lucky and did find a mooring, very close to a shop selling delicious local ice cream from Blyton's in Gainsborough. Ideal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380526cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;59&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We've got ourselves a convoy.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380548cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now what?? A sunken island to avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380560.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;61&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Torksey Lock has a display of teapots on one of its gates.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I don't really know what to say.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380565.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;62&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The lock is surprisingly manual with its old capstans still in use.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380567.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;63&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Foss Dyke side of the lock has this neat hedging sign.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380570.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;64&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; The Roman Foss Dyke is wide and straight, as you might expect.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210709_163056835.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;65&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Straight to the ice cream shop, which has a long list of flavour including a choice of four vegan ones!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210709_174030245.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;66&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We found a space just the right size for Liberty Belle in Saxilby.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210709_164809641.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;67&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We had a little look around Saxilby, but the threat of heavy rain stopped play.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was at the services just outside Lincoln. Tony pottered off on foot to check out the mooring situation and paid for us to stay at one of the visitor pontoons in Brayford Pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This expanse of water is a widening of the River Witham, used as a port by the Romans who connected it to the River Trent by constructing Foss Dyke; &quot;What have the Romans ever done for us?&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 'pool' is maintained and preserved by the Brayford Trust charity on a not-for-profit basis, so we were happy to pay to stay there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Mary was stationed at RAF Waddington she was involved in the parade through the streets of Lincoln, when they were first bestowed the Freedom of the City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hoped that meant she was allowed to walk along with her bayonet fixed, but apparently not. How disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210710-P1380576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;68&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored in Lincoln.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210711-P1040661cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;69&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is meant to be a water clock which rotates at the top and, on the hour, sends water cascading from one small pool to the next, ringing bells as it goes. Sadly, we didn't see it working.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210710_150848670.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;70&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lincoln Cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210711_123800832.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;71&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside showing one of the wooden walkways across an arch.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210710_163629012_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;72&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary with her new friend, the Lincoln Imp.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210711_111345941.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;73&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An ironwork arch at the end of Steep Hill, with various symbols representing the history of Lincoln.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210710_135942670.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;74&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Resting half way up the aptly named Steep Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210711_142248290.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;75&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That's helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210711_143802659_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;76&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;After going in All Directions, a sit down is needed, at the Museum of Lincolnshire Life.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210711_200801099_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;77&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;After passing over Wembley stadium, (to celebrate England's defeat in the final), the Red Arrows came directly over us!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I couldn't get to my camera fast enough so only caught the remains of their coloured smoke in the sky (they are quite fast....)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our stay in Lincoln, we continued on the River Witham to Boston via Tattershall. Boston was a pleasant surprise. An old market town which, compared to some places we had seen on our travels lately, looks quite smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210712-P1380585.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;78&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle just about to enter Lincoln's 12th Century Glory Hole.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210712-P1380614.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;79&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lincoln Cathedral spotted through the drizzle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210712-P1380617.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;80&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Every lock has its own character, some more than most.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210712-P1380629cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;81&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Socially distanced cormorants.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380696.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;82&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching the Boston Stump, looking sinister in this light.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we walked into town and visited the Stump, or, to give it its official title, the Church of St Botolph. This is a lovely, bright building which has impressive dimensions for a parish church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tower itself is one of the tallest Medieval towers in the country at over 80 metres, higher than the church is long. It looks impressive from a distance but it isn't until you stand right next to it that you can appreciate its height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market square was lined with some lovely old buildings of differing styles, some with Dutch gables. The next morning was market day, so we  went along to see what we could find. Mary bought a few items of food to take back home with her and we found a pleasant cafe for coffee and cake.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1040668.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;83&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside St. Botolph's&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1040681.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;84&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beyond the sluice, which is the end of navigation for us, is the tidal section of the River Witham.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380697.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;85&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;No longer looking sinister, the Stump takes on a different character in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380705.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;86&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Boston Belle, moored near Liberty Belle, presumably has less liberty...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Liberty Belle on her pontoon, overlooked by St Boltoph, we set off in the hire car to take Mary home.
&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380703.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;87&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle's home for a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had completed a lot of the network during Mary's visit and taken her down memory lane in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way we had seen plenty of birdlife, some of which stayed still long enough to have their photographs taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210709-P1380542.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;88&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cormorant&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210708-P1380495.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;89&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oyster Catcher&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210708-P1380518cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;90&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Little Egret&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210707-P1380448cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;91&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cormorants&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380685cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;92&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Great Crested Grebe and chick&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380673.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;93&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Great Crested Grebe on its nest&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210629-P1380160.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;94&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canada geese&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210701-P1380266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;95&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mute Swans&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380675cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;96&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heron&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210713-P1380676cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;97&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Most Herons do this when the bow of the boat reaches them&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210630-P1380258.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;98&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another Swan&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/20210712-P1380638cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;99&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Unidentified bird&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n99/IMG_20210711_111508074_HDRresized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;100&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
A picture of the explanation board underneath the Lincoln spandrel.
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must apologise for my slow progress lately; I am now two months behind on my newsletters. As Joe recently pointed out, they no longer qualify as newsletters, being more like historical documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our travels have been less leisurely of late, so time to sit and compose has become more difficult to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are heading towards the Lancaster Canal for our booking across the Ribble Link on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still plan to sell Liberty Belle soon and should be returning to the house before the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Tamworth to Boston 25th June - 14th July 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tentative Travels</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/08/24/tentative-travels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tentative Travels" /><published>2021-08-24T21:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-24T21:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/08/24/tentative-travels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/08/24/tentative-travels.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Birmingham to Tamworth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17th May - 23rd June 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n98map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210519-P1370813.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Can you spot Liberty Belle?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In the background is the Library of Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were moored in Birmingham ready to welcome Cathy and Will as our first visitors for quite some time. They had expressed an interest in visiting The Black Country Museum, so we journeyed there aboard Liberty Belle, taking things gently because we hadn't had her engine repaired properly yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored outside the museum for a couple of nights. Unfortunately not all of the exhibits were open but we managed to entertain ourselves there for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG-20210518-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Black Country Museum's Fish and Chips.
It's got to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG-20210519-WA0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A beer on the go. Cathy's turn to steer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travelled back to Birmingham by another route, to make the journey more interesting for our guests. We arrived just in time to have lunch in Damascena, my favourite place to eat in Brum. The following day we explored the Jewellery Quarter in the morning and then Cathy treated us to a fabulous lunch in 'Formosa Izakaya'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly it was then time for them to collect their luggage and make their way to the coach station for their journey home. Tony and I both set off with them to wave them off but I had forgotten my mask, so couldn't walk through The Mail Box and had to wave madly from there instead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG-20210520-WA0008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I take a turn at steering now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG-20210520-WA0007cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Will's turn!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG-20210520-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A fabulous lunch in 'Formosa Izakaya'&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hot on their heels were our next guests, Joe and Kirsty with Carter who arrived the following morning. We all had a little look around the city then travelled back to our usual mooring space outside the Black Country Museum. The following morning, Carter and I went off for an adventure to the local park whilst Tony, Joe and Kirsty went into the museum for a short visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we had decided to travel to Halesowen, which involves passing through the Netherton tunnel and turning onto the Dudley No.2 Canal, a section of the network that we hadn't done before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This journey proved to be a bit more exciting than we had expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG_20210521_104922681_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The mooring directly in front of the Canal House Pub was ideal for picking up our next guests.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG_20210521_190128568.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Rachel said I could have this bed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210522-P1370818.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Dogsitting.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1370847.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Dogstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All went well, passing through the long Netherton Tunnel and then turning left onto Dudley No.2 which was a pleasant stretch with interesting artwork by local artist Luke Perry, explaining some of the local history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040514.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Commemorating the day when circus elephants went missing and were found playing in the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040538.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Royal Doulton Sanitary Ware was made in Dudley.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040506.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The Dudley No.2 Canal...
...has seen the rise and fall of many ways of life and much change but still carries on connecting people.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040536.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Tollman was 'ere&quot; being spray painted by a Tollman. In his other hand is his notched stick used to gauge the height of the boat in the water and thus the weight of its load and the toll to be paid.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we arrived at our second tunnel of the day, Gosty Hill. As we ventured in it became clear that the size of the tunnel varied greatly and it was such a tight fit at times that we began to have doubts about ever reaching the other end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very nerve wracking with the tunnel closing in on us; we were in real danger of becoming wedged in. Of course, we had no phone signal down there so someone would have to swim for help..... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210522-P1370832.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching Gosty Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It looks like just another tunnel...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040474.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ooooooooo! Tight!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040491.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A sudden lift in height, with a portrait of Dracula...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Odd.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After what seemed a very long time, we finally emerged with great relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210522-P1370836.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;That is the smile of relief.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210522-P1370845.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning at the end of Dudley No.2 watched by a boatman sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued our journey to the end of the navigation in Halesowen. When we arrived it became clear that there was nowhere to moor, so we had to turn around and make our way back to a space that may or may not be a legitimate place to moor and stopped there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were secured we went to explore Halesowen, but there was not much to see. That evening Kirsty booked us a table at The Canal House in Birmingham for the following day, presumably as incentive for us to brave the tunnel again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Tony looked up some information on the Gosty Hill Tunnel. It seems that it is so notoriously tricky that any boat that passes through is entitled to purchase a brass plaque declaring &quot;I Survived Gosty Hill Tunnel&quot;. Maybe we should have found that out beforehand. Or maybe not, otherwise we might not have attempted it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing the next morning some fishermen arrived, intending to set themselves up where we were moored. We apologised and promised to move along as soon as we were ready. They were very chilled about it. Straight after breakfast we set off back to Gosty Hill Tunnel. The return journey was not quite as frightening now that we knew it was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1370855.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We're going back in....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1040502.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and emerging, safe and sound.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210523-P1370870.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Joe steering us around the corner back towards Netherton Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stopping off on the way at Joe's van to load up their belongings,  we made it into Birmingham and moored up in Cambrian Wharf, in plenty of time for our meal at The Canal House. Yet again the time had passed all too quickly and Joe, Kirsty and Carter set off for home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210525-P1370885.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored in Cambrian Wharf, with Birmingham's Arena in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We completed a full week of good company and dining by meeting up with Julia for a long awaited catch-up and a huge lunch at Damascena. Arriving back at the boat we could only sit and admire the gift of lemon cake that Julia had given us, we were so full!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Fear not, we had fully recovered by the following day and the cake quickly disappeared. Yum!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still had quite some time to wait before Liberty Belle was due at Alvechurch Marina for her repairs, so we went back to the house for a short visit then explored more of Birmingham. Tony serviced the engine and touched up some of the paintwork. We decided to trust the engine for one more short excursion with Liberty Belle, to complete some parts of the surrounding network that we had missed out before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210607-P1370893.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony getting a few jobs done.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1370918.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A toll island in the middle of the canal is the perfect place to bring up a goose family.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1370937.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning off to go down Spon Lane Locks, a new section of the Birmingham canals for us....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1370928.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....but there will be a short delay whilst we send some water down because there isn't enough to float Liberty Belle&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1370943.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Coming down off Spon Lane Locks to rejoin the New Main Line canal that we know so well.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1370957.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cruising along slowly above the frantic traffic below.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The canals were lined with yellow iris, wild roses, early purple orchids and elderflower which, although scented, did not quite cover the other smells Liberty Belle was churning up with her propeller!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw plenty of goslings and young coots as well as some tufted ducks and loads of beautiful, richly coloured damsel files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1040571.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from Birmingham's Aston Locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1040559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cruising along in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210609-P1370969.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Ok Baby, there is a big boat coming so I'm off....good luck!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210610-P1380002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We were treated to a pretty display of flowers all along the edge of Daw End Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210610-P1380020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Scooping up the weed from Daw End Canal.....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210610-P1380019.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and loading it into this work boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210610-P1380027cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Cheap Overnight Moorings, Entirely At Own Risk&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Not very tempting. There are plenty of free moorings which are frankly, much nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210610-P1040585.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fisherman sculpture alongside the canal. We photographed it last time we passed by. We like it too much to ignore it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210611-P1040595.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Why was this paddle ignored when the grease gun was in the area?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210611-P1380038.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This lock has a thriving population of weeds.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210611-P1380052cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Having fun stepping over the gap between the gates.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pottering around in this relaxed manner we found ourselves getting uncharacteristically hooked into the  EURO2020 matches!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were moored again in Birmingham's Gas Street Basin for one of England's earlier games and were thoroughly entertained by the noise and general jollity around us as people cheered on the team in pub gardens and on balconies around the canal. However, once we had decided it was bedtime, it was no longer quite so much fun from our point of view. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to get to sleep,  but Tony was woken up twice to shoo people off the boat who were prancing around on the stern taking selfies. Then, at about 5 a.m. he was again woken up by Liberty Belle bumping against something. The something turned out to be the opposite bank of the canal. Some fun loving joker had decided to undo one of our ropes and let us loose...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now it was time to set off for Alvechurch to get Liberty Belle's engine sorted out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as the engine mounts, Tony had given a short list of other things he thought should be attended to.
We were booked in for a full week because the marina is also a hire company, so the engineer would attend to us when he could but might have to drop everything to rescue a customer on one of their fleet. However, we were hoping that the work would be finished within a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way we passed through Wast Hill tunnel and met 5 boats going through in the opposite direction! After hardly seeing any boats moving for quite some time, this was rather a shock!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210614-P1380090.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wast Hill Tunnel&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG_20210616_090535447.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored at the boatyard, waiting patiently.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work began on Wednesday and the engine mounts were replaced successfully but that left the other little jobs, so work continued on Thursday...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the engineer had ordered all the parts required ahead of time, one of them had been the wrong size, so he had re-ordered it and it was due later that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this part did arrive, it too was wrong. As the engineer and Tony were discussing this it came to light that the engineer wasn't aware of one of the jobs Tony had requested, so he was another part short. The two parts were ordered from a different supplier and were due on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday arrived. The parts were delivered but the weather forecast was for heavy rain, so Liberty Belle (without a working engine) was punted into the painting 'shed', (with an accompanying beautiful rendering of &quot;O Sole Mio&quot;...), so that the engineer would be able to work despite the weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210618-P1380098.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle hemmed in by hire boats.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210618-P1040598.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Work begins...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG_20210615_091347_099.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Boatyard life.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG_20210618_155618320.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle suffering the indignity of being punted along.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were inside, another boat joined us and we were surprised to see that it was Nick &amp;amp; Margaret's &quot;Theodora&quot;! We had met them way back at the beginning of our Adventure in Stratford On Avon and had been in touch since. We contacted them and discovered that Theodora had been there for some time, having a new paint job and they were not due to pick her up until after we had left, so that was a shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little overtime on Friday, Liberty Belle was ready, so, on the Saturday, we were released! Thank goodness. Now we could travel around with confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/IMG_20210618_160318_574.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the painting tent.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210619-P1380101.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle finished and ready to go, with Theodora still in the painting tent, waiting for Nick and Margaret.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed to get to Tamworth, where we had a hire car booked on Wednesday. We were going to fetch Mary for a long awaited holiday on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a journey of 26 miles and 38 locks. We set off from the boatyard and did 11 of the miles on Saturday, mooring up in Birmingham where Tony put everything back into the engine bay that had been living in the front well whilst the work was being done.  We also got a bit of housework and some shopping done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then on Sunday we did a record breaking 11 miles and 34 locks, leaving the short journey of 4 miles and 4 locks on Monday, and we were there. As luck would have it we were able to moor in exactly the place we had hoped, near a convenient place to load and unload the hire car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having plenty of time before collecting the car on Wednesday we were able to have a good nose around the area and find a place to get fish and chips when we arrived back with Mary, because there would be no time to cook. (Good excuse, eh?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210619-P1380103.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the way Tony spotted this hedgehog balanced on a bag of rubble supporting the edge of the canal. Taking Liberty Belle to the side he walked back and rescued the little fella. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n98/20210620-P1380111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Somebody somewhere dislikes kilometres enough to go to all this trouble!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we will be heading for the Lancaster Canal, our finale with Liberty Belle before we part with her and she goes on to have another adventure with new owners.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Birmingham to Tamworth 17th May - 23rd June 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rattling Along</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/07/26/rattling-along.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rattling Along" /><published>2021-07-26T21:18:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T21:18:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/07/26/rattling-along</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/07/26/rattling-along.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Anderton to Birmingham&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;30th April - 16th May 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n97map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210501-P1040400.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Middlewich left behind, heading for Wheelock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Anderton and the River Weaver behind, travelling South along the Trent and Mersey Canal. We needed to stay in the Birmingham area because we had vaccines booked there, so we decided to circle around, completing some parts of the canal network that we had previously missed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having moved from one watercourse to another, we were still in the same area, passing the same industries along the way, but with a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210430-P1370448.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Eeek!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210430-P1370449.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;TATA Chemical Factory.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210430-P1370456.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Details from TATA's decorated pipe bridge...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210430-P1370459.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...that we passed underneath.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210501-P1370493.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Piles of salt alongside the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210430-P1370480.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The canal widens where the land has collapsed into an old mine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst on the Weaver we had enjoyed some pleasant spring weather. The air was still chilly but the sunshine had been warm. Once we were back on the canal, winter returned and extra layers of clothing were re-employed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we reached Middlewich we were cold and tired and the clouds looked threatening. As we rose in our last lock of the day we could smell chips cooking and as we closed the gate behind us we saw the door of the fish and chip shop opposite open up for customers. There was a free mooring straight in front of us so we drew in, bought our fish supper and settled indoors just in time before the rain came down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210501-P1370508.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A brand new gate waiting to be taken to its lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG_20210501_075957839.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking out of Liberty Belle's hatch at the grey day and the chip shop in the distance....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May was a month of travelling in the wind and rain and lighting evening fires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our planned route ahead involved passing back through the Harecastle Tunnel to Stoke on Trent. Being very long but only wide enough for one boat, it is open in the mornings to those travelling South, and the afternoons for boats going in the opposite direction. The day we hoped to pass through, we set off from Church Lawton, in the company of another boat we had joined the day before, with just six locks to do before we got there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hire boat was coming towards us through the lock ahead. Our partner boat helped them through whilst we waited to use the lock ourselves. Meanwhile I spoke to the couple on a boat ahead of us who seemed agitated. They explained that the couple on the hire boat were leaving paddles up in the locks and this had resulted in an empty pound ahead. The CRT had been informed but they were concerned that they wouldn't get to the tunnel in time to pass through. They were also on a hire boat and were on a tight schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two other boats ahead of us in the same position. Needless to say, tempers were fraying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much as we love the Canal and River Trust, I had to agree that they might not get there in time to fill the pound and get us to the tunnel before lunch, so, feeling brave, I set out to start the ball rolling (or the water flowing) leaving Tony and the crew of our friendly boat partners to get through as many locks as they could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up beyond the empty pound and opened up one paddle at each end of each lock until I reached the top in Kidsgrove, where two canals meet, the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey and Macclesfield. The water stolen from here wouldn't be noticed. It was rather nerve wracking because the space between the locks was a bit too far, so I couldn't keep an eye on them all at once. I had to keep walking to and fro between the locks to make sure all was well, so I was getting rather hot and bothered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the pound was almost full I walked back, until I was within sight of the top lock and I could see a CRT person waving at me. We met on the towpath and he took over whilst I returned to the first lock, lowered the paddles, opened up the gates and walked back to the boats where Tony met me with a very welcome cup of tea. In all the fuss I had become overheated and left some layers of clothing at one of the locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked the crew of the three boats in front of us to just leave the stuff there and I would collect it on my way through. It was all still there, not that anyone could possibly have taken a liking to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were the last of the boats involved to arrive at the tunnel. The tunnel staff quickly took our details, checked our light and the horn (which, thankfully, worked on this occasion. Tony had managed to get it working but it remains rather untrustworthy) and waved us all into the darkness. We had just made it. What a morning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed by Westport Lake, which was still very busy with boats and moored at Etruria for lunch before tackling the six more locks to Barlaston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210502-P1370510.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Finally looking back at the top lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210502-P1370512.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Relieved to have made it through the Harecastle tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210502-P1370518.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our convoy of boats passing by Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210502-P1370525.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the start of our lockdown at Westport Lake we had seen the beginning of a new bridge being built and had hoped to watch the progress. Some months later, not much has happened.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We battled on over the next few days in the wind and rain, turning onto the Staffordshire and Worcester Canal at Great Haywood and heading for Kinver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one occasion, as I jumped off the boat with the rope, my trusty leather hat blew off into the canal! It had some air trapped in the top so didn't sink immediately. Tony, despite the bad conditions, managed to manoeuvre Liberty Belle sufficiently well to get close enough to my hat to hook it out with the boat hook without sinking it! Phew! Well done skipper!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210504-P1370536.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Threatening clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210504-P1370548.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A family of swans tapping on each boat in turn in the hope of being fed.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we arrived in Kinver. As we went through the lock outside The Vine, the sun was out and the people sitting in the garden sipping their drinks tempted us! We moored as soon as we could and went to the pub for drinks and food. It was a bit too chilly really, but we enjoyed it just the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hoped spring was back but the following morning we had more rain. Oh well, onwards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210505-P1370559.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh good, that's reassuring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210505-P1370564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Made it!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210506-P1370580.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A break in the rain....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210506-P1370591.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sunshine!!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210506-P1370600.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Two rare things. Sunshine and blue paint on a lock!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210506-P1040406.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The crew's exit from a lock has a dramatic arch, making it feel quite regal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In reality it was to prevent the horse's rope from dropping between the walls.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210507-P1370638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Let's go to Stourbridge! Although we have passed by here before, we haven't been down this arm until now.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210507-P1370652.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the end of the Stourbridge arm is a reminder of times past next to a modern reality.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210507-P1370681.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony working the locks on the beautiful Staffordshire &amp;amp; Worcestershire Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210507-P1370664.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sometimes we share the water with others.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG_20210507_160843026.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading for Kinver in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG-20210507-WA0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A refreshing pint at The Vine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We joined the River Severn at Stourport (amazingly, despite all the recent rain, the river was still navigable), but before we had travelled far we turned sharply onto the Droitwich Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210508-P1370692.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A landslide. Luckily it hasn't affected navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210509-P1370696.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stourport Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210509-P1370700.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Proceed With Caution&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Okie dokie, will do!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG_20210509_103944478_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tea and biscuits on the River Severn.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(That counts as proceeding with caution.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210509-P1370717.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exiting the River Severn onto the Droitwich Canal, with a little help from people passing by.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving in Droitwich, we dismissed the first set of moorings we came to and continued on, opening the two stubbornly tricky swing bridges and closing each one behind us, until we came to the lock where we discovered that there were no more moorings ahead. We turned and went through the double swing bridge performance back to the mooring we had first seen. We should have known all this, having been here before, but for some reason it wasn't quite as we remembered it...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210510-P1040430.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the Droitwich swing bridges that we became very familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210510-P1040427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Droitwich mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finally mooring up we pottered off to look at the following day's problem. The M5 was built over the Droitwich Canal when it was no longer navigable, so no consideration for boats was needed. When the canal was restored, a culvert was used as passage underneath the motorway. The headroom available varies with the water level, so we wanted to check to see what our chances were of progressing further. It looked perfectly possible...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210509-P1040417.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Droitwich salt spring at the end of a garden.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210510-P1040424.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looks as if we should fit under there....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before setting off the following morning, Tony left early to check again. It still looked OK, so we risked it and breezed through. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210510-P1370728.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hold your breath....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210510-P1370734.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and.....breathe!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to Worcester we saw our first Kingfisher since early April at Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At our final lock before mooring in the town we met a rather inebriated, very friendly and chatty chap who apologised for not helping us but he hadn't brought his windlass out with him today. It was probably a blessing, but we thanked him for his kind thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We heard from another boater that the River Severn was now closed below Digilis Lock and it was chaos before there. He and his boat had been washed against the floats blocking the weir and had to be towed off. We decided that we might not do that bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wandered around Worcester doing a bit of shopping and sight-seeing, then sat watching the river for a while in the sunshine. It was pleasant but, like all towns and cities at the moment, it doesn't have the same appeal as in pre-covid times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day Tony caught a train to Birmingham for his second vaccination and I did a bit more shopping. It's not the same experience now but it's still possible to spend a few quid if you are determined enough!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving Worcester, Tony checked the river again, to see if he was tempted to try and turn onto it. The number of scullers out there sealed the deal, so Liberty Belle went straight back up the canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first destination was Blackpole's Revolution washing machines in the forecourt of a petrol station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG_20210512_191110588_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sharing a tub of ice-cream on a wall outside a petrol station. We know how to live.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, washing all sorted, we moved Liberty Belle to the bottom of Tardebigge locks, a flight of thirty locks, ready for a full days locking the following day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off full of determination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210514-P1370758.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The first of the Tardebigge flight of 30 locks. Here we go...!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210514-P1370759.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five locks went well, and the sixth seemed no different until Tony put Liberty Belle into gear to leave through the open gates and nothing happened. We towed her out using the ropes and pulled her over to the side of the pound between the locks. Tony assumed that the gear cable must have stretched, so off came the board over the engine bay and it was immediately obvious that things were a bit more serious than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a gap of about 2 inches between the engine and the propeller shaft. The bolt of one of the engine mounts had sheared right through and the engine had jumped clear of the propeller shaft, presumably damaging the other mounts in the process....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This solved the mystery of the rattle in the engine bay. It was the engine itself. Tony could now stop re-tightening the straps used to hold the folding bike in place....)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG_20210514_093303399.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hmmmm....not good.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG-20210514-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here's your problem, Mrs.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony contacted River Canal Rescue! (It sounds to me like a children's cartoon series, like Paw Patrol....) Apparently their best engineer was in the area and would be with us in the afternoon to assess the situation but probably wouldn't be able to do the repair immediately....we resigned ourselves to a weekend moored between the locks at Tardebigge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Tony put on his overalls to clear stuff out of the engine bay and I put on mine so that I could assist, holding onto a large oil container whilst Tony decanted old oil into it. A Canal &amp;amp; River Trust man tried to entertain us with his jokes relating to dogs useful in a breakdown situation; Jack Russells for jacking up etc (sadly, we didn't commit any others to memory...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about midday the engineer rang to say he would be there in half an hour, so Tony walked out to meet him. Arriving from the opposite direction, he addressed me (still in my overalls) with his questions. For a few seconds I kept a straight face and answered knowingly but then I panicked and rang Tony, who came swiftly back and took over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony recognised the engineer as one who taught the boat engine servicing course he had been on. He confirmed the sad diagnosis. The good news was that we happened to have the type of engine which he could lift without special equipment but the bad news was that he didn't have a replacement part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony declared that he had a spare engine mount  in the box of bits which came with the boat. The engineer was amazed! Thus he was able to patch us up enough to get us through until we could get all the engine mounts replaced, either by them or in a boatyard. He warned us that the boatyards were very busy at the moment and gave us a very heavy hint as to which one to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210514-P1370765.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;River Canal Rescue to the rescue!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suitably patched up, we were now able to move, so by 3 o'clock we were on our way and with the help of a lock volunteer, continued up the flight of locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/20210514-P1370769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On our way again!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Tardebigge we stopped off at the recommended boatyard in Alvechurch to see if they could fit us in. June or July they said, which was weeks away. Oh flip! Tony emailed the details to them as well as The River Canal Rescue, asking for a quote and a date.To cut a long story short, we booked in to Alvechurch boatyard for 14th-18th June, for one of their engineers to fit our repairs in around his other duties. So we had to remain in the area until then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Boris was allowing overnight guests from Monday 17th May, Hurrah! Things were looking up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Cathy and Joe arranged to catch up with us, so we aimed for Birmingham as a nearby, convenient place to pick them up.
Cathy and Will were joining us on Monday for a short holiday (Cathy's boss had kindly arranged a few consecutive days off work for her) and, at the end of the week we were expecting Joe and Kirsty, who were coming to stay for a long weekend! Perfect. Let's hope the engine allows us to take them on a trip or two...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the engine was properly fixed and we were able to travel a little further, we were planning to collect Mary for a longer stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n97/IMG_20210515_163354340_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mooring opposite the Canal House pub in Gas Street Basin, Birmingham, feels like our second home.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently travelling north, completing bits of the network as we go. Our next major stop will be in Sheffield, followed by York and Ripon.

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Anderton to Birmingham 30th April - 16th May 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Well-Seasoned Waterway</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/18/well-seasoned-waterway.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Well-Seasoned Waterway" /><published>2021-06-18T14:36:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T14:36:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/18/well-seasoned-waterway</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/18/well-seasoned-waterway.html">&lt;h2&gt;The River Weaver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;24th - 30th April 2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n96map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210430-P1370423.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching The Anderton Boat Lift from the Weaver Navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Anderton in plenty of time for our trip down in the boat lift. We had filled our water tank at the facilities, moored overnight and were ready and waiting at the designated mooring, chatting to our fellow travellers and reading the information board. One of the notices informed us that, from a certain date, it was no longer necessary to book passage through the locks on the river but they had specific opening times which were detailed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was good news, it made travelling easier if we didn't have to get through to someone on the phone before arriving at each lock, we could just turn up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; member of staff came along to greet us with safety information for our trip in the lift. She informed us that we would be expected to contact each lock keeper in turn to book our passage through. Tony pointed out the poster behind her and she seemed slightly confused but no explanation was given. We decided that the dated, printed version was probably correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210430-P1370435.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The top of the Anderton Boat Lift.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lift consists of two water troughs supported on hydraulic rams. Originally the hydraulic tubes were filled with canal water, counterbalanced each other and were powered by steam engine. After several closures due to problems with corrosion the pistons were filled with distilled water. This delayed the corrosion but it remained a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later the lift was altered to work using a system of ropes, pulleys and counterweights, each trough working independently and with electricity supplying the power. A stronger frame was built around the original to take the weight of all this equipment. The lift could now be repaired when necessary by closing one trough at a time, keeping the waterways open and saving money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the 1970's, due to the decline in canal traffic, the lift was only used for pleasure boats. Then, in 1983 it was declared unsafe and closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2002 it was reopened after being restored. Again it was hydraulic but this time using oil rather than water and keeping the troughs independent. Now it has both frames still in place as well as the redundant overhead pulleys. The counterweights have been removed and used to build a maze in the visitor centre's garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelling down in the lift is quite an event. Looking at the construction it is difficult to see immediately which parts are currently responsible for the operation so the untrained eye doesn't know where to settle. Add to this the need for looking at the view and, despite it being such a slow process, it's hard to know quite what happened!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210430-P1370437.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from the lift of the river, the visitor centre and the counterweight maze.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210424-P1370144.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The lift from below, with our fellow narrow boat emerging behind us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the first lock, the lock keeper expressed surprise because he hadn't been expecting us and gave us the phone numbers to use to book ahead..... Good grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From then on, we phoned ahead to book passage through each of the locks. There were very few boats moving around so we didn't have to wait around for other boats to join us which often happens on rivers. Some of the locks are electrically operated but others are manual. Given the size of the gates, working them must take quite an effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock keepers were very cheerful and welcoming but during the course of our conversations they expressed their frustration with poor communication, changing responsibilities and lack of staff. It seems that things in the CRT garden are not all rosy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370399.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching one of the locks with the gates open ready for us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210428-P1370323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This shows the toothed hinge of a lock gate, the gears wound manually from above (not by me, thank goodness).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210428-P1370329.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Across one of the manually operated locks was a swing bridge, also manually operated. It must be exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210428-P1370325.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The foot holds in the lock walls look like Dr. Who characters.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370408.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the large swing bridges across the navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210428-P1370345.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Most of them have lots of headroom for narrow boats but this one was an exception.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Weaver Navigation packs plenty of variety into its short length;  enormous chemical factories and salt mines, views of the River Mersey and the Manchester Ship Canal, interesting towns as well as peaceful stretches of beautiful countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210424_142746328_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Relaxing at our mooring in Devil's Garden.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210424_160343792.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Testing the water.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cold.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the history of the industry around the River Weaver goes something like this:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;The surrounding area has always been associated with salt. Brine percolates naturally to the surface in places where it dries out and forms crusts of salt. The Romans exploited this valuable resource and eventually mines were sunk to extract it straight from the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;In 1734 the Weaver Navigation was built, following the course of the river, giving a navigable route for transporting salt to the world via the River Mersey. By 1777 the Trent and Mersey Canal, (built by Brindley for Wedgwood to transport his crockery safely), was completed. Initially, salt was transfered from Trent and Mersey boats to Weaver Navigation boats via chutes at Anderton. To enable boats to travel between the river and the canal, the boat lift was built, opening in 1875.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;There are several swing bridges over the river (too tall for us to worry about). Two of them in Northwich date back to 1899 and were the first electrically operated swing bridges in Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;The Winsford Salt Mine dates back to 1844 when prospectors were searching for coal and established a salt mine instead. Eventually, too much salt was being produced so in 1888 The Salt Union was formed to control the market. The Winsford mine was forced to close in 1892 but, in 1928, it was re-opened when the last of the Northwich mines was flooded. The salt is still being mined here but interestingly they have also found a use for the resultant, ever growing, network of underground caverns. With the constant temperature and humidity levels together with the lack of UV light, vermin and water, excellent storage space is available for valuables including paintings and historical documents. Brilliant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;In 1873, making use of this local supply of salt, the Brunner Mond chemical works was established on the banks of the Weaver. In 1926, combined with three other businesses, it became ICI,  then broke away again to re-form Brunner Mond in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370375.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Winsford's salt mine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370382.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The mine shaft building.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210425-P1370224.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The chemical works looking like colourful children's play equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210426_161657551cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pictorial representation of local history.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first town we visited was Frodsham, a traditional market town not far from Runcorn. From the top of the sandstone hill behind the town you can see the River Weaver, The Weaver Navigation, The River Mersey and the Manchester Ship Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210426-P1040364.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A stroll into Frodsham.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210425_195415107.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our peaceful Frodsham mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210425_195145595.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The original gates to close the swing bridge to Frodsham traffic. Now a modern lifting barrier is used.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210425_190422748_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Frodsham's Grade II listed K4 telephone box with letter box and stamp dispensing machine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210426-P1040369.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An early morning&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; walk to the top of the sandstone hill towering over Frodsham&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210426_091936418_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony pointing to Liberty Belle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The delightful town of Northwich has many buildings which, on first glance look Tudor in origin but are, in fact, much more recent timber-framed buildings. The mines under Northwich became uneconomical to dig during the 19th century so the owners pumped water through the mines instead and extracted the salt from the resultant brine. This caused the land to subside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timber-framed buildings, designed by Victorians, can to be jacked up when the land below them sinks. I was amazed that we hadn't heard about them before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210426_160525885_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Brunner (of Brunner &amp;amp; Mond ) replaced the original library (damaged by subsidence) in 1909 with one which could be jacked up if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210426_160802681_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another example of an adjustable building is the 1914 purpose built Post Office.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our travels along the river, we spotted a heron colony. We were unable to count the nests but a passer by told us that the year before there had been 35 of them. He also told us of a rumour of a kingfisher nearby but sadly we didn't see it. We hadn't seen a kingfisher since we were moored at Westport Lake in Stoke!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370387cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of many heron nests in the trees alongside the navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370390cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heron overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210429-P1370405.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A waterside crane which looks as if it hasn't been needed for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210427-P1040380.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Two boats, moored side by side.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The one on the left will need some bridges to swing!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One morning we were running low on water and had plans to fill up as soon as we saw a tap but managed to cruise straight past one on the approach to a lock, simply because we were expected and the keeper had the gates open ready to welcome us. Once we were through we realised what we had done and hoped to be able to fill up at the facilities at the next town. We knew that repairs were underway there but hoped that we would still be able to use the tap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got there, it was busy with high-vis people but it looked as if we would be able to use the tap once they and their workboat were gone, so we hatched a plan to get up early and use it before the workmen returned the following morning. It turns out that these people get up very early, so we missed our chance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping we would find water later in the day, we waited until the next lock was manned at 10 a.m. and Tony rang them to book passage, but there was no answer. By this time the men working on the facilities opposite us had moved their boat so that it was straddling the canal in front of us. We walked over to talk to them from the bridge above. No notice had been given for a closure to navigation so surely they wouldn't be long.... Apparently they were laying electric cables and, if all went well, would be about 2 hours....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210427-P1370292.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of Northwich's historic swing bridges with the closed boaters' facilities to the right and a work boat blocking the navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony decided that, all things considered, we might as well turn around, return to the lock behind us, go through, fill up with water and come back. He phoned the lock keeper and booked passage both ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we got back, the workboat was out of the way and we progressed to the next lock, despite still not having got through to the keeper. The lock keepers were on the look out for boats and opened up, telling us that they didn't have a working phone, so we wouldn't have got through, however many times we tried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did manage to ring the keeper of the next lock but we were too late that day to pass through, so we moored on the pontoon as he suggested and went through as soon as it opened at 10 am the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening we moored at the end of the navigation in the lovely Winsford Flash, where there was a tap which wasn't marked on either of the maps of the river that we had. A very welcome surprise find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/IMG_20210428_115205_257.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A black swan is amongst the residents of Winsford Flash.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210430-P1370415.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A majestic heron concentrating on the matter in hand (beak?)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an enjoyable 6 days, we returned to the boat lift to ascend back onto the Trent and Mersey Canal. We were joined by another boat and travelled up side by side. The other boat was having trouble with his horn, so he asked us to go out first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a sharp turn when rejoining the canal so sounding a horn is important. Unfortunately, our brand new horn also failed to work and we crept around the corner in silence.... Luckily there was no-one coming, so we got away with it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210430-P1370429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Waiting outside the boat lift for our turn to go up...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n96/20210430-P1370431.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...with a chemical works behind us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
We have a battery powered alarm clock that is set to 7 o’clock. We hadn’t realised how much time it was losing due to a low battery. On this occasion it went off at what it thought was 7 in the evening, although, in reality it was half past six in the morning…. 
We had until 8 o’clock before it was a decent hour to run our engine and move.
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this we are waiting at the boatyard for repairs to be completed;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(a story for another day). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been here for several days now and the novelty has rather worn off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, we have the football to keep us entertained....Yes, it really has come to that!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">The River Weaver 24th - 30th April 2021 Our route</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Normal Service is Resumed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/07/normal-service-is-resumed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Normal Service is Resumed" /><published>2021-06-07T19:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-07T19:44:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/07/normal-service-is-resumed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/07/normal-service-is-resumed.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Marple to Anderton via Runcorn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12th - 23rd April 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n95map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210412-P1360763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving our mooring in Marple&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were expected to move around again we looked at our options and they were few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our route back south towards Birmingham was blocked because an emergency repair for a culvert in Macclesfield required part of the canal to be drained for an indefinite amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other, longer, route to Birmingham via Manchester, along the Bridgewater and the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey canals, had been blocked by a landslide at Anderton for some months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could head off to Yorkshire through the Standedge tunnel but we might not fit through and it would mean all our planning involving our vaccines in Birmingham would have to be altered and become rather complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This left us with the option of re-doing the Peak Forest Canal. Oh well....it is certainly pretty and there are plenty of walks to do, especially if you take the train further into the Peak District.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile we heard from the Canal and River Trust that they were attempting to make provision for boats to pass by the landslide. As there was now hope that we would soon be able to move, it was worth hanging around for further news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210414_165744_754.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Walking back to Liberty Belle along the Peak Forest Canal towpath.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210416-P1040324.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Edale Welcoming Committee representative.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210413_101250150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony considering a new abode.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210413-P1040320.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Enjoying the local walks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210413_121127415.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Picnics are a must.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210416_131430233.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;En route to Kinder Scout, just before the path disappears.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that week we heard from the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust that enough of the landslide in Anderton had been cleared to allow boats to pass along the canal with supervision. There was the possibility that the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey canal would have to re-close if the soil shifted again, so great care was needed. From 21st April a team would be there daily to ensure safe passage. So, things were looking up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a new plan in place, we set off towards Birmingham via Anderton. Although we had been in the lift before, we had only turned around and gone back up again without exploring the river. So we incorporated a trip on the River Weaver into our new plan and booked our passage on the Anderton Boat lift, going down on Tony's birthday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the boat lift had limited opening days so we would be spending a relaxed 6 days on the river, before returning to the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey Canal and dashing to Birmingham with limited time to get to Tony's second vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210417-P1360822.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving Bugsworth Basin, heading back to Marple...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210415-P1360786.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... past New Mills...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210417-P1040332.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... underneath the Disley lift bridge...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210418-P1040336.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...down the Marple lock flight...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210418-P1360872.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...then finally over the Marple aqueduct to freedom!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some beautiful weather, and even had to use suncream on occasions, but with it came the future threat of the lack of water in the canals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The celandine flowers looked cheerful in the sunshine but were soon outshone by glorious kingcups. With the spring flowers came the goslings, ducklings, baby coots and, Tony's favourite, moorhen chicks. We took great delight in seeing them, taking care not to get between them and their mothers; the poor things get so frantic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360909cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Proud mother.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Mallard fathers are not interested in family life.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210418-P1360877.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Expectant mother with her feather lined nest.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Expectant father is nervously pacing nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210421-P1370074cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another expectant mother.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Expectant father is somewhere out of sight, no doubt being aggressive towards someone or something that has no idea why.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way to Anderton we had to tackle Manchester, which always makes me a little tense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading into the city, we encountered an empty pound between two locks. Someone had left a paddle up in one of the locks, leaving the water to drain out overnight. It took time to rectify this before we could get very far, so that was a bad start....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after that, everything went smoothly and we found that the best mooring in central Manchester was there for the taking. It is the only pretty mooring there is, on an aqueduct in a neat residential area. The sun was shining and my coldness towards the city was warming slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1040339.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canals are often lined with bikes and trolleys but we don't get to see them until the water is drained.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360917.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Locking in the sunshine....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360923.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... taking it in turns....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360916.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;.... and sharing our one can of beer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wandered off to explore near our mooring and take a look at the locks we would be tackling the next morning. They are double locks, which were overflowing with water and go underneath the city. It all looked rather daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the weather was again sunny but we quickly disappeared under the city where the gloom and smell of stale urine dampened our spirits a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210420_082010325.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beneath Manchester....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360939.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... trying not to breath too deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the sturdy look of the locks, they were not too difficult to work and we emerged into daylight and fresher air soon enough. Lots of repair work was going on around us, with scaffolding and floating pontoons alive with fluorescent jackets and cheerful banter. All work had to stop whilst we passed by and some of the available muscle was applied to the lock gates, for which I was grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged from the locks into a low cutting alongside the Gay Quarter of Manchester, lined with trees full of blossom and Gay Pride flags waving in the sunshine, I suddenly felt a love for the city. How fickle I am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening we moored up and Tony noticed that we were surrounded by a film of diesel, glistening in the sun, which was concerning. He was puzzling over this when a man moored opposite us noticed his furrowed brow and assured us that the diesel had been there before we turned up. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360968.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Emerging into daylight. A lovely pair of sculptures hidden in a corner.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pink blossom in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Manchester behind us we were on the privately owned Bridgewater Canal. Dating back to 1761, it was the first British Canal that didn't follow an existing water course and so has plenty of history. However, we didn't hang around because this was our second visit and we wanted to make up enough time to divert to Runcorn before our date with the Anderton Boat Lift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360982.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A restored milestone at the start of the Bridgewater Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1370030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At regular intervals along the Bridgewater Canal are cranes, poised to slide wooden beams across the canal to isolate a section so that it can be drained and repaired.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A section of the Bridgewater Canal runs parallel to the Manchester Ship Canal then bends away to the South. Here a branch (added to the canal in 1776) turns off to Runcorn. We turned along this pretty stretch, lined with woodland carpeted with bluebells. Here, amongst the usual ducks and geese we saw a shoveller duck, which was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210422-P1370103.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The pretty Bridgewater Canal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1370009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...eventually runs parallel to the Manchester Ship Canal which can occasionally be glimpsed.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Runcorn the Bridgewater Canal, The Manchester Ship Canal and the River Mersey meet. Sadly the Bridgewater Canal now comes to an abrupt and disappointing end here where there was once a dramatic flight of 10 locks down to The Mersey. These were filled in and built over, so can never be restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210421-P1370095.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Waterloo Bridge at the end of the Bridgewater canal, where it used to travel down the locks to the river.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now it is just a turning space.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210421-P1040361.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Two bridges spanning the River Mersey and the Manchester Ship Canal between Runcorn and Widnes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The 1868 railway bridge and the 1961 road and foot bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210421_151723247.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The River Mersey on the left, with the tide out, alongside the Manchester Ship Canal and Runcorn on the far right.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210421_150113704.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Which came first, the building or the bridge?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having briefly explored Runcorn, we turned back and joined the Trent and Mersey canal, slipping carefully past the landslide and arriving at the Anderton Boat lift ready for our descent onto the River Weaver, a whole day ahead of schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210422-P1370123.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210422-P1370129.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The landslide which has blocked the canal since Storm Christoph in January, now partially cleared.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210422_155055_083.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Relieved to have passed the landslide and finally be in Anderton.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently we are moored in Cambrian Wharf, central Birmingham, which we love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to catch up on newsletters.....well, this is a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony is touching up Liberty Belle's paintwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have time on our hands because we are waiting for Liberty Belle's appointment in Alvechurch's boatyard on 14th June......but that's another story!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Marple to Anderton via Runcorn 12th - 23rd April 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Escape to the Hills</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/04/12/escape-to-the-hills.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Escape to the Hills" /><published>2021-04-12T19:31:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T19:31:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/04/12/escape-to-the-hills</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/04/12/escape-to-the-hills.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Westport Lake to Marple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;12th January - 12th April 2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;(Three whole months!)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n94map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, from 12th April, we are obliged to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until  now we have been allowed to move for essential journeys only. At first this meant popping to the tap and elsan point, maybe staying there for a night or two, then returning to Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210125-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Westport Lake frozen over.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210214-P1040156.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oddly shaped icicles hanging over the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210214-P1040163.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Thoughts of spring came a little early for this coot, surrounded by icicles.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210118_124201_092.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Making kindling from a pallet found in a skip....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210123-P1360535.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Setting off for water.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210213_112201_845.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Knowing the canal was due to freeze over, we stayed near the tap in Etruria, watched over by James Brindley&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210211-P1360547.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;By connecting together our two hoses we were able to connect Liberty Belle to the tap.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210214_103905183_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These two hire boats made their appointment at the boatyard by charging at the ice full speed, breaking it as they went.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210112_105623429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A huge new bridge being built with the aid of a man with a spirit level...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210115-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony dreaming of one day travelling through the Harecastle Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210202_133707534.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We visited some nearby piglets occasionally for something different to do.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the lack of bedding, (and the bulging laundry bag making it difficult to keep the hall cupboard doors shut), made a trip to a washing machine into an essential journey. We do most of our washing by hand but we have nowhere to hang out anything as big as a bed sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outdoor machine we had used in Endon was no longer available to us because of the ongoing maintenance work on the Caldon Canal.... The inside of a warm, steamy launderette did not appeal, even if we could find one that was open. The next nearest outdoor machine was 'beyond the tunnel', which had become an almost mythical place. My goodness, excitement was in the air!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A journey was afoot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We booked our passage through the Harecastle Tunnel. So far so good. Now there was the small matter of Liberty Belle's intermittent horn and unreliable front light....both of which we needed to work on command for our pre-tunnel safety inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These pieces of equipment had been deteriorating for some time and Tony had ordered new ones, delivered successfully to Mary, to be picked up at Christmas....You see what went wrong there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, despite Tony's efforts, the likelihood of them working when required had become a game of chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wondered whether having a wife with a torch at the front of the boat, wired in to the horn mechanism and ready to scream at the appropriate moment, would be sufficient. The torch part of the plan seemed sensible enough for Tony to go out and buy a good quality one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travelled to the tunnel the day before our booking and moored there for the night. It is usually a quiet area with the occasional walker or cyclist passing by. On this occasion a couple of twits decided to wander about with an air-horn! Luckily they moved on before bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topping up our water supply at the tap the next morning, the CRT chap, in charge of letting us into the tunnel, and, crucially, carrying out the safety check, arrived. Tony was testing Liberty Belle's horn. It was in a good mood this morning, having been protected from the rain for a few days in a plastic bag. We had a friendly chat, during which we confessed about the state of our equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was happy to relate that he had already heard the horn working and that the torch would suffice if the light failed, and suggested that we keep the internal boat lights on too. Something that we usually did anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His bad news was that the CRT air-horn had been stolen overnight, an essential piece of safety equipment without which we were going nowhere! Oh heck. I gave him an account of the air-horn incident the evening before and an entirely useless 'description' of the lads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few phone calls and a short wait later, a CRT van arrived and a woman handed over half a dozen air-horns! Dressed in our life jackets and leather hats, we were ready and off we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Tony scraping the top of his hat on an especially low part of the tunnel, and Liberty Belle leaving a little blue paint as a momento on the tunnel wall, we made it through in very good time. We really had arrived in the mythical land of Kidsgrove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned onto the Macclesfield Canal and moored on the aqueduct over the Trent and Mersey Canal. We were close to Kidsgrove railway station, so that Tony could get to Birmingham for his first vaccine! Fabulous! We stayed there until we were in danger of running out of water, then moved the short distance to the next tap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210219-P1360557.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning onto the Macclesfield Canal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210224_091742062_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....viewing the Trent and Mersey below&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210221_142458335.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We were surprised to find that many gravestones in Kidsgrove included the address of the deceased.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210226-P1040198.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In each place that we stopped we had a little exploring to do.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here is Tony at Mow Cop folly.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210226_101347898_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A snack with a view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210228_114427415_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heady heights.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, from facility to facility, we gradually made our way to the most convenient mooring space for the washing machine. We walked the mile or so uphill to the machines in a Londis car park on a traffic island in Congleton. Hurray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote a man we met on the towpath, who, in better times, had journeyed around Europe with his family in a camper van, &quot;Who needs LSD when you can get that excited over access to a washing machine?&quot; I obviously look more worldly wise than I am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210227-P1360619.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A beautiful day with the pretty Congleton Aqueduct ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210227-P1360605.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Macclesfield Canal still has many of the original milestones in place.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the washing was done we had to then decide what our strategy would be for the rest of the lockdown. Going back to Westport Lake wouldn't be an essential journey and seemed a daft thing to do anyway, crowded as it was. We couldn't stay at a mooring near the washing machine as there were no other facilities near there. So, we decided we would continue forwards, one essential journey at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210225_133033724_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony walking over one of this canal's famous snake bridges&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210227-P1360613.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...where the towpath crosses the canal, a horse can cross over without being unhitched from the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then suddenly I had the chance to book my first vaccine in Birmingham! This required an essential journey to Macclesfield, for the railway station. We were pleased to note that there were two taps marked there on our map. Perfect. Except that neither of the taps actually exist&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210307-P1360644.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading towards the hills of the Peak District.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210306-P1360638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What do hills mean?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hills mean locks!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210305_092817593.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hills also mean views.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At Bosley Reservoir, built to feed the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Below you can see the feeder canal heading towards the top lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210307-P1040230.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We followed 'The Silk Road' to Macclesfield railway station and thus to Birmingham for my vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210309-P1360687.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We like to see old mill buildings preserved, with their dignity intact.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210307-P1360657.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There are several dotted along the canals in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Macclesfield until we needed water then headed for the tap in Poynton. Mooring nearby we stayed to explore the area, moving on again when we needed the boaters' facilities in the lovely Marple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marple is a delightful spot, with facilites and shops, (including a bakery where they sell dangerously excellent pastries), as well as beautiful surroundings and interesting walks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to eek out our coal supply but eventually we had to admit that we needed to find a boatyard or marina that would sell us some. So we turned onto the Peak Forest Canal and made our gradual way to the marina, which, it turned out, was only open three days a week. Of course we had arrived on the wrong day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued to Bugsworth Basin and Whaley Bridge, at the end of the Peak Forest Canal, where we stayed until we were sure that the marina was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as a few bags of coal we also took the opportunity to replace an empty gas bottle and fill up on diesel. Topped up with everything, we made our way back to the facilities at Marple to await the hoped for 'great release' on the 12th April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210326_162812_016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Marple mooring, between two snake bridges...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210319-P1360706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and opposite a busy Canal &amp;amp; River Trust yard.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210312_104116890.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Marple lamp post depicting a narrow boat crossing the aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210313_140344519.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The canal features on High Lane's lamp posts too.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210316-P1040243.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Roman Bridge, near Marple, was labelled as such by the Victorians. It's actually an 18th Century construction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210316_134132188.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A tunnel built alongside one of the locks in Marple, for the horses.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210317-WA0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Marple's 'track-a-duct' as viewed through an arch of the aquaduct, where they both pass over the River Goyt&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210317_102756578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The first iron bridge in the Northwest, built over the River Goyt in 1813&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This fancy, modern material was considered for the Marple aqueduct but they opted for stone.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210318_124227023_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Chad standing in Saint Chad's well near Saint Chad's Kirk in Chadkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210318_122742368.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A monk outside Saint Chad's Kirk in Chadkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(wearing enough layers for wintering on a narrow boat)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210320-P1040248.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lyme Park Estate House.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is the back entrance!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210320-P1040245.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In the distance is Lyme's hunting lodge,built in 1737 (replacing one built in 1580).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It became known as The Cage because poachers were jailed there.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040259.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Standing stone sundial in Torrs Riverside Park, alongside the Peak Forest Canal.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(It didn't appear to be working...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210322_103353471.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Trig point on Cobden Edge overlooking canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New Mills' Millennium walkway, above the River Goyt, alongside the railway and opposite the Torrs Mill.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040278.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A mill race for transporting water from the River Goyt, under the road bridge to one of the mills.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040272.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the site of a derelict mill, a Reverse Archimedes Screw, using the old weir to provide New Mills residents with electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1360710.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Alongside the Peak Forest Canal is a sugar coated sweet factory!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210325-P1360735.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the end of the Peak Forest Canal is Bugsworth Basin and lime kilns.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beautiful and full of history.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210325-P1040295.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring Bugsworth Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210324-P1040283.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Toddbrook Reservoir threatened to engulf Whaley Bridge in August 2019. The repairs are not complete but, luckily for me, it has been emptied.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210325-WA0006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;All these pipes pump the water out of the reservoir while the repairs on the dam continue.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
These stones lie on the 2 degrees West longitude. At local midday (13:08 BST, 12:08 GMT), the larger stone supposedly casts its shadow on one of the other standing stones. This, of course, assumes that the sun is out..
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hoped that we would be able to make our way back to Birmingham where we each have a vaccine appointment in May, 12 days apart. Whilst there we planned to collect a hire car and visit Mary, between appointments, (assuming Boris's plan for May 17th goes ahead) then bring her back to the boat for a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual there are now some obstacles in our way. Boats can no longer pass through Macclesfield. A culvert there is leaking and the canal has been drained to enable it to be repaired. The canal is not expected to reopen until the end of June. Circling around through Manchester and along the Bridgewater Canal to reach Birmingham has not been possible for months due to a blockage near the Anderton Boat Lift. We are expecting an email with an update on this situation on 20th April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for now, we must leave Marple because the mooring restrictions have been reinstated, but we will travel along the Peak Forest Canal again. We will decide what to do when we have more information next week...&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Westport Lake to Marple</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Winter’s Tale</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/01/13/a-winters-tale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Winter's Tale" /><published>2021-01-13T10:52:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T10:52:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/01/13/a-winters-tale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/01/13/a-winters-tale.html">&lt;h2&gt;Westport Lake to Westport Lake with excursions on the Caldon Canal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3rd December 2020 - 11th January 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n93map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360335.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Brrrrrr!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were released from Lockdown 2 into tier 3. Once we had established that the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust expected us to move around on the canal, (but without leaving our tier), we set off for the Caldon Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were going to explore the branch to the village of Froghall via the River Churnet, but first we re-travelled the Leek Branch because we had booked ourselves in for the flu jab with a pharmacist there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201206-P1360176.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Santa resting on a canalside bench.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201208-P1040049.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This obstruction in the canal used to be the pivot point of a swing bridge linking a local mill with the main railway line.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winter had begun with a lot of rain, which for boaters means flooded rivers, muddy towpaths, slippery locks, dirty boots and trying to keep carpets clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generally remove our boots before walking through the boat, but occasionally I need to dash through to the front doors when we are travelling. We have a collection of cheap rubber doormats, enough to lay end to end along the carpet. Usually I put them down in advance, but occasionally I feel like Gromit, in 'The Wrong Trousers', laying track as I go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving Leek, we spent a little time exploring the local area because we had left rather too abruptly last time we were there. This involved visiting a few reservoirs...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201207_103255165_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On our way to 'Brown Edge' just outside the Peak District.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201207_114525440_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At Knypersley Reservoir, built to keep the canal topped up, is a dramatic Warder's Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201208-P1040055.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stanley Pool reservoir, built to keep the canal topped up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201210_123612345_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Rudyard Reservoir, you guessed it, built to keep the canal topped up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were satisfied that we had done as much exploring as we could, given the very muddy conditions, we turned around and headed for the branch to Froghall. Part of this section of the canal follows the River Churnet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the river level was too high for us to take Liberty Belle along it, so we walked to Froghall instead, just to see what we were missing. This only reinforced our desire to travel there by boat as soon as we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360204.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazelhurst Junction on the Caldon Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leek or Froghall?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360210.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading down the locks towards Froghall.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360226.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These locks have pretty little split bridges, with modern railings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1040067.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking back at Hazelhurst Junction from the River Churnet.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360252.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazelhurst Aqueduct carrying the branch to Leek over the main Caldon Canal to Froghall.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201218-P1360328.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the old flint mills on the Caldon Canal. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201216-P1040111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cheddleton Station on the preserved Churnet Valley Railway line.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201217-P1360285.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of their diesel locomotives is named 'Eastleigh' in honour of its origins.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201217-P1360310.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The River Churnet as it comes alongside the Caldon Canal....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201217-P1360305.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and they join at this lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201214_140816892cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Knock, knock!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Anyone home?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201214_141857015_HDRcropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At Deep Hayes Country Park, these stepping stones are disappearing fast.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201215-P1040093.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Froghall Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if we could travel this far on the river, Liberty Belle is a bit too tall to go through to the wharf beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201215-P1040085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Victorian Lime Kilns at Froghall Wharf.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Christmas was getting close. We had a hire car booked from Stoke-on-Trent to take us to Mary's for the festivities and we wanted to leave Liberty Belle at Westport Lake, where we thought she would be safe. So, off we went, arriving at our mooring safe and sound, only to hear that Christmas gatherings were no longer allowed to be overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a disappointment. So, that was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we heard that Joe and Kirsty would be keeping Mary company for Christmas dinner and we had got used to the idea of it being just the two of us on the boat, Tony shopped for all the festive food and we settled in and made the most of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, all things considered, we had a very pleasant time. The weather had turned to snow which was great fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201222-P1360333.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We don't need a Christmas Tree because we can sit and look at the one on the boat in front!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360348.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We do need our very own snowman though, of course!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360358.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I let him borrow my hat, just for the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360416cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A walk around Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201225-WA0011cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We decided to use our new table extension over Christmas, to spread out our festive spread!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201225_144003161cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is the disadvantage of the table extension...!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Despite this inconvenience, we liked the extra space and kept it for well over a week!)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201225_135957819.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Free range chickens are rare here, Tony searched the whole of Stoke for this one!)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201228-WA0024cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our cherry brandy.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Made from wild cherries picked during our Sunbury lockdown and saved for Christmas. Very yummy!)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201225-WA0003cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Christmas Day walk around the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201225-WA0004cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Post-walk hot chocolate with a tot of something extra...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Christmas, once our water had run out, we set off for the tap at the start of the Caldon Canal, stopping off at the boatyard where we hoped to buy coal, gas and diesel, only to find that it was closed until 4th January. Oh well, we were not desperate...yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once on the Caldon Canal we decided to continue and try again to get to Froghall. The ground was now frozen so mud was no longer a problem but there was some ice around, so we had to be careful where we put our feet, particularly at the locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201229-P1360455.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;More snow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20210101_120258022_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New Year's day walk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hadn't got far before we were plunged into tier 4. This time we were expected not to move, except for essentials. So, there we were, at the boaters services near Endon, still several miles from Froghall, with a tap, Elsan point, hot showers and a couple of week's worth of coal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were happy to stay there until our coal supply forced us to travel back to the boatyard on the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20210102_101850801_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony looking from the bridge with the River Churnet below.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20210102_102452466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A little picnic at the lock, before turning back.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temperature dropped further and froze us in, just for a day, but it gave us food for thought. If we were to get frozen in for a long spell, fetching coal would not be an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly we were all in full lockdown again, meaning we could only move for essentials. Taking into account the weather forecast and our coal situation, we decided to head back to Westport Lake and hope for a mooring space for us there...  Froghall would have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were planning our journey to this area, we checked the CRT website for any stoppages that might affect us, to make sure we wouldn't get stuck behind a lock or bridge that was being repaired. The website indicates when and where the repairs are due to take place and, because they have to tell us so far in advance, the date range given is a worst case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we did not expect to be here for anywhere near this length of time.....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travelled through the first five locks. As I approached the next lift bridge I saw CRT workers fencing it off. As they let me through to operate it, I asked what was happening... There was a scheduled repair, due to take 8 weeks, which should have been started the day before but they had been delayed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh my goodness! We hadn't checked the stoppages for January! We felt foolish and soooo lucky to be able to pass through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the next lock, workmen again. Oh no. Another stoppage. This one was also booked for several weeks. We moored up and tentatively asked when they hoped to be finished. We were told that they were going to be working until Friday, just a couple of days away. Phew! Our immediate problem was now our water supply, not coal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, for some reason unknown to us, the work wasn't finished on Friday. Desperate for showers, Tony and I walked the 6 mile round trip to the facilities back in Endon on Saturday morning, with Tony carrying several litres of water back with him in his rucksack, to ensure we didn't run out completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we had been moored near the closed lock, we had witnessed CRT boats travelling through on several occasions and the lock gates were not padlocked. We decided that we were desperate enough to travel through and did so on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to explain ourselves on a couple of occasions to boaters who knew about the closure, but so far the CRT have not caught up with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time we had patches of ice to push through and some of the locks were treacherous, but by placing my feet carefully and holding on to railings wherever I could, we made it, first to the water tap and then to the boatyard, where we purchased coal, cooking gas and diesel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fully loaded with what we needed, we arrived at Westport Lake and, luckily, there was a mooring space for us. It is raining again and our snowman has disappeared. We will have to keep an eye on the forecast to make sure we don't run out of water just before we get iced in again, but the temperature for the next few days is in our favour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Message...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;We both send our best wishes to you all. Keep your heads down, fingers crossed and masks on. I know some of you have had your vaccines, so the rest of us need to keep the faith and hold on, it's coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Back in &quot;Lockdown 1.0&quot; I was sitting on a bench outside a church which had recently opened for private prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;An older lady who had visited the church in her mobility scooter and I got chatting. She was obviously concerned about people coming too close so I suggested she get a 2 metre stick and sharpen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;She told me off, saying that it didn't sound very Christian, so I suggested the alternative of a 2 metre stick with something soft at the end instead. She wasn't convinced....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Quite right too. Wielding sticks at each other is probably not the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Keep safe everyone. xx&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">Westport Lake to Westport Lake with excursions on the Caldon Canal 3rd December 2020 - 11th January 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lockdown Lake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/12/13/lockdown-lake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lockdown Lake" /><published>2020-12-13T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/12/13/lockdown-lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/12/13/lockdown-lake.html">&lt;h2&gt;Westport Lake, Stoke-on-Trent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3rd November - 2nd December 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n92map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_102045702_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Westport Lake as seen from the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201204-P1360143.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This useful clock has helped us to keep track of the lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(The 'banana clock' method from the last lockdown began to lose one day each week when we started eating cooked breakfasts on Saturdays...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard, on the grapevine, that Stoke-on-Trent is an area unsafe for boaters, where we are likely to be boarded by unwelcome visitors or have stones thrown at us. Last month we met a boater heading away from this area who bent my ear about her terrible Stoke-on-Trent experience.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, all I can say is that we have been here for weeks and walked along the tow path in both directions many times, visited local towns and parks and at no time has anyone made us feel uncomfortable in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly there are some areas which could do with a tidy up and many of the old buildings have been sadly neglected. However, the canals, towpaths and local parks are noticeably clean, tidy and well kept. We have no regrets concerning our decision to moor here. We have wildlife to watch, walks to choose from, access to supermarkets and we are only a short boat trip away from water taps.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have access to one tap a mile to the north at Harecastle Tunnel and another a few miles to the south in Etruria, at the junction of the Caldon Canal. It makes a nice change to take a trip out to one or the other each week for a top-up.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etruria is named after an Italian district renowned for their artistic products, which Wedgwood presumably hoped would rub off a little.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caldon Canal is named after the local village of Cauldon, but was misspelled on the official documentation authorising the building of the canal...&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201104-P1030945.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A stroll along the canal in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201107_111903140_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A coffee outside Harecastle Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201104-P1030942.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A bottle kiln looking rather dilapidated and surrounded by rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_095801496.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A local boatyard advertising&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;TACLE AND BAIT AIR GUNS ARCHERY BOATS AND ENGINES COUNTRY &amp;amp; WESTERN LINE DANCING&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_100713020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Magnet fishing is popular on canals, the metal found is piled up by the towpath. This piece is covered in mussel shells.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_092841436.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Hanley Cemetery lies in the triangle of land at the junction of the Caldon and Trent &amp;amp; Mersey canals&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201117-P1360082.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The boaters' facilities at Etruria.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201110-P1360067.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching the tap at Harecastle Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westport Lake&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is much loved by the locals and there are always people here appreciating it, whatever the weather. Very young children, dressed in waterproofs from head to toe, are brought here by their parents or grandparents to charge about on balance bikes, feed the geese, run around in the maze and splash in puddles whilst the adults chat or nurse a takeaway coffee. It's a joy to watch.&lt;p&gt; 

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1030979.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An art installation at Westport Lake,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;FOR ALL THOSE WHO HAVEN'T STOPPED&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;spelled out in small white stones.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_102412908.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The B'oatcake, (selling takeaway homemade Staffordshire oatcakes with hot fillings), moored tantalisingly close.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360045.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There is no danger of getting lost in the Westport Lake maze, (the hedges are two feet tall) but the kids love chasing though it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360042.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A fabulous bug hotel in the shape of a railway engine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201118_161607988.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;According to the sign -&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;We do like:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;cut seedless grapes, birdseed, peas, oats and chopped lettuce&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201112_144137766_HDRcropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;We are more sophisticated than people realise. In fact, if you could peel the grapes too, that would be better...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have we been doing all this time?&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we have done a bit of walking and exploring, a few jobs around the boat, a little bit of reading, some bird watching....not much really.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201105_162708330.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony's newly finished table extension!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Marvellous!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Not that we are allowed guests...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201107_103119146.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring the local hills (or mudslides as I prefer to call them....)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201126_110535545.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring a local nature reserve in the fog.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_105307120_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A small park built within the foundations of an old gasometer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201112_104346560.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A takeaway coffee from Hanley Park Pavilion Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201118_093755388.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the site of the old ironworks in Tunstall is &quot;Golden&quot;, a 21 metre tall steel spike, which lights up at night, representing the ironworks' flame.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201115_105321479.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Festival Park's stone circle (modern). Apparently it's &quot;full size&quot;, whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201115_104616695.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Josiah Wedgwood's head. I am not sure he would approve of being left unfinished...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoy looking out for and logging the birds we see around the lake and the canal, getting to know their character traits. Our biggest delight is our resident kingfisher. We see her most days, sometimes more than once.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the photos of our fellow residents that we have managed to take.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201108-P1360057cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kingfisher&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360041cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Robin&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201116_113819671cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canada and Greylag Geese&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360039cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;White farmyard geese&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360040cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moorhen&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201123-P1360100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Coot&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201123-P1360113cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tufted Ducks&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201123-P1360108cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pochard&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201107-P1030963cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Great-Crested Grebe&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201127-P1360131cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Goosander&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201105_091905570cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canada Geese, Black-Headed Gulls and Cormorant.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201106_132107746cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;White duck&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard of Stoke-on-Trent before we arrived and had, in fact, passed through here on Liberty Belle once before, but we knew nothing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it has city status, it is, in fact, a collection of six towns. One of the towns is called Stoke-upon-Trent, (note the difference there), which contains the minster and the main railway station, but the 'City Centre' is in the town of Hanley. The other towns are Tunstall, (where we are moored), Burslem, Fenton and Longton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we have been here, we have made it our business to explore each one of the towns in turn. They must all have been something to behold in times past, each trying to out compete the other with elaborate town halls, public parks, and other fabulous buildings. Sadly, along with the industrial buildings, most of them are in very poor repair, crumbling away. Such a shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_092604956_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liz Lemon's modern sculpture which includes contributions by local school children.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_094148368_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stoke-upon-Trent's minster (St Peter ad Vincula), with re-erected 13th Century arches, and Josiah Wedgwood's grave in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_093250074.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Remains of a pre-Norman stone cross, outside Stoke Minster, showing early examples of the Staffordshire Pretzel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_093407774.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Philip Hardaker's St Peter's community mosaic bench, made with the help of local children.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(We saw his Throne for the Common Person in Stone)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_112343608.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanley Park, showing the Pavilion Cafe, band stand and bridge over the canal. This beautiful Victorian park was restored in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_110250826_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanley cemetery's magnificent Chapel of Rest.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_085435622.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tunstall's Queen Victoria Jubilee Buildings, still a public library but originally also included art and science schools... &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_085519918.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... a fire station (closed in 1926) and public swimming pool (closed 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_090519786_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tunstall's memorial to generations of the Adams Family who owned land, a mine and pottery factories in the area.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_090607219_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tunstall's magnificent Church of the Sacred Heart.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1030985.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burslem's old town hall is now the Sixth Form College.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201113_110810423_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burslem's Wedgwood Institute, built by public subscription as a memorial to Josiah Wedgwood, made arts, science and literature available to all.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Opened in 1869.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_110939766.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fenton's &quot;Onward &amp;amp; Upward&quot; sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_120205604_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Many grand old buildings in Stoke-on-Trent are in a poor state of repair.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It is common to see buddleia plants growing out of them. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_114836475.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;51&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old pottery building in Longton, left for the pigeons to roost in.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_115629345.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;52&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In contrast, these Longton buildings now form the Gladstone Pottery Museum. We hope to visit it one day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1040005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;53&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burslem's memorial to the 57 miners killed in the explosion at Sneyd Colliery in 1942&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1030999.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burselm's cast iron drinking fountain, 1881&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
Westport Lake
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1881 - Port Vale Football Club established a ground at the site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1883 - Brownhills Colliery workings flooded and the lake began&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1884 - Port Vale forced to move their practice ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1890 - Smith Shirley's pleasure boating business established at the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1900 - Pottery waste and canal dredgings were dumped around the lake to raise the banks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1914 - Boating business began to decline at the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1930s - Boating had declined and pottery waste was dumped around the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1940s - Jam Jar Wakes Fairs [Formerly known as Bradwell Wakes] held at Westport Lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1967 - Lease of Westport Lake given to the City of Stoke-on-Trent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1971 - Reclamation schemes saw Edward Heath opening the lake for sailing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;2009 - Westport Lake Visitor Centre built&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;sup id=&quot;fn2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;
The Adams family
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;were landowners in Tunstall from the 13th century and established as potters by 1447. Several of the Adams cousins were called William and owned pottery firms which must have been quite confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially they were among the principal rivals to Josiah Wedgwood but the last family business was sold to the Wedgwood group in 1966.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commemorated on the clock tower in Tunstall are:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams Tunstall landowner 1307&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;Richard Adams Coal Mine owner 1487&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;Thomas Adams 1563&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams Potter 1590&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;John Adams Chief Constable of Tunstall Manor Court 1616&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams Potter 1746 - 1805&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams 1777 - 1805&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams pottery manufacturer 1833 - 1905&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lockdown we were released into tier 3. The Canal &amp;amp; River Trust requested that boats resume cruising but without moving in or out of tier 3. That was a bit of a surprise. We cannot travel northwards, through Harecastle Tunnel, because beyond the tunnel is tier 2. We cannot travel southwards towards Birmingham (tier 3) because some maintenance work is being carried out in Stone. This leaves us with the Caldon Canal, which we are pleased to re-visit because we still have plenty to do there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming the rules don't change again at the last minute, we will be returning to Westport Lake and leaving Liberty Belle there whilst we travel in a hire car to Mary's for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you all manage to have a Merry, if different, Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the immortal words of the showbiz legend and raconteur, Count Arthur Strong,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;&quot;Condiments of the Seasoning&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to you all. xx&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">Westport Lake, Stoke-on-Trent 3rd November - 2nd December 2020 Our route</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Caldon Curtailed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/23/caldon-curtailed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Caldon Curtailed" /><published>2020-11-23T14:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-23T14:33:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/23/caldon-curtailed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/23/caldon-curtailed.html">&lt;h2&gt;From the Black Country Museum to Westport Lake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17th October - 2nd November 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n91map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201103_163538_242.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Westport Lake&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having looked at the up-coming winter closures we decided that our plan should now be to fill in a few gaps on the Four Counties Ring section that we had missed so far, plus the Caldon Canal, followed by the Stourport Ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a return visit to Wolverhampton before turning north on the Staffordshire and Worcestershire Canal at Autherley junction, heading for Great Haywood via Gailey, Penkridge and Stafford; a new section to us. Along the way we saw a kingfisher, several heron, a woodpecker, a few jays, some Little Grebes and plenty of squirrels skipping along the towpath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gailey sounds like a much more interesting place that it turned out to be. We had heard it was a popular place to moor but we couldn't honestly see why....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Penkridge, at the only pub open, we learnt from a local character rather more than we needed about Scottish exports. The people he had been talking to when we arrived seemed to be relieved that he had moved on to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Stafford, we met a couple of friends who were walkers and very interesting to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally arrived in Great Haywood, where Tony had been stung by a bee last time we were here. Thankfully it was too cold for bees this time.  We spent some time exploring the outside of the National Trust's Shugborough House estate. There is a beautiful bridge giving pedestrian access to the estate across the River Trent. It was built in 1550 by the Earl of Essex to enable Queen Elizabeth I to cross the river to go hunting. Originally it had 40 arches, now only 14 remain. (Presumably part of the bridge was demolished when the canal was built.) It is a long bridge but not very wide, so it proved to be inadequate for the Shugborough Hall residents who wished to travel by carriage. Another, wider bridge was built for them which became the preferred route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201017-P1350527cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Little Grebe, spotted amongst all the coots.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201018-P1350555.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Wolverhampton mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201018-P1350567.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Let's go to Great Haywood!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201019-P1350578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A three headed gongoozler.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201019-P1350589cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;OK, enough said.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maybe that explains the three headed cow...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201019-P1030823cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A bit narrow in places...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201019_133234584_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Gailey Lychgate. The church is now privately owned.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201019_134418106_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The other Gailey landmark.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_141612203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sir Martin Noel's Almshouses, Stafford&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_140945750_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. Mary's Church, Stafford. I keep mistakenly calling it the Cathedral...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_140025977.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony at the entrance to Stafford's 18th Century Lockup, an overnight holding cell for local prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_143134840.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Broad Eye Windmill, looking a bit sad and tatty.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;AQUEDUCT OVER RIVER SOW&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350646.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;River Sow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350651cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Left, Haywood Junction 1 mile 3 furlongs&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Right, Deptmore Lock, 4 miles 6 furlongs&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350687.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...even further if you insist on doing a 360 degree spin at Tixall Wide, just because you can!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350705.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;AQUEDUCT OVER RIVER TRENT&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;River Trent.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Haywood Junction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1030850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The cheapskate's view of Shugborough Hall...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1030860.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bridge over the River Trent from the canal to the Shugborough Estate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1030855.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Monument on Shugborough estate to George Anson, who circumnavigated the globe in 1740's aboard HMS Centurian.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A link to Gosport there!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we were back on familiar 'ground', heading for Stoke-on-Trent, with an increasing amount of narrowboat traffic, passing through;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Weston, (past the only remaining inland salt marsh in Britain)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stone, (past a lime kiln dating back to 1790's)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and on to Barlaston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; the way we met a couple and their teenage son aboard a hire boat. The couple hoped to buy their own boat in the near future, and travel in much the same way as we are. At the locks, we shared any information we thought might be useful and generally encouraged them to go ahead with their plans. How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201025-P1350744.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pedestrian's eye view of the upcoming lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201025-P1350753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The first boat we hired in 2003, Elinor Ginger, still afloat!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201025-P1350746.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An ancient Lime Kiln alongside the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201027_114441022_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Staffordshire Pretzel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201027-P1350771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Joule's Ales! Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201027-P1350757.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A celebration of Stone. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a bit concerned about travelling through Stoke-on-Trent, particularly during half term, so we set off early in the morning to tackle the five locks before turning off onto the Caldon Canal, where we hoped to get through another 3 locks and a lift bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were just approaching the second lock of the morning when we heard a shout and saw someone in a hi-vis jacket waving us on. Tony pulled over to let me off and the lock gates magically opened. At first I thought it was a CRT volunteer but it turned out to be the very friendly, chatty, &quot;Rob the Lock&quot;, who sped ahead of us on his bike, setting and opening each lock for us, pausing briefly to help with the gates and paddles before zooming off ahead again. He even turned up the Caldon Canal to help us there too. Rob's day job is as a boat mover but he has very little work at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He used to volunteer with the CRT with whom he still has a good relationship. Rather than get bored sitting at home he has a full English breakfast, fills his panniers with energy drinks and zooms about the towpath on his bike, helping where he can. He says it's good for his physical and mental health. Well, he certainly did us some good, we sped up those locks in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350795.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the many bottle kilns in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350804.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Let's go left!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350813.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The instructions for the staircase lock at the start of the Caldon Canal&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350821.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bottle kilns spruced up and incorporated into the modern housing estate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very beginning of the Caldon Canal was industrial but pleasant enough. Then we came to Hanley Park which was a delightful surprise; a restored Victorian park with formal gardens, Pavilion Cafe, elegant band stand, lake, boathouse, decorative bridge and balustrades. We continued on along the increasingly pretty, winding canal and moored, as Rob had recommended, in Milton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part way along, the Caldon Canal splits in two, with the main branch descending through some locks and heading for Froghall, and the second branch passing over the main canal on an aqueduct and heading for Leek. We went along the Leek Branch first. My goodness the views were fabulous. We decided there and then that we would stay in Leek for a few days to give us a chance to explore the area on foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201102_170023_448.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanley Park&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201102-P1350995.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;James Brindley, canal engineer, in Etruria at the beginning of the Caldon Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1030864.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pretty Caldon Canal&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1350844.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fascinating lockside artwork referencing local industries and landmarks. Note the Staffordshire Pretzel&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1350879.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing the locks down to the lower canal and heading for Leek.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201031-P1350952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Emerging from under a bridge on the Leek Branch to face this wonderful view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1350925.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leek tunnel is a tight squeeze...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201030_142603899_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leek's terraced Cemetary.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1030908croppped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;1676 Elizabeth Ash Almshouses built for local Leek women over the age of 60.
&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1030903cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Settle down on a Leek bench, and rest like a hen on a pretzel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly there were rumours that there would be a second lockdown. The Caldon Canal, although absolutely beautiful, doesn't have much in the way of facilities for boaters, so it isn't ideal for an enforced lengthy stay. We needed to get to a mooring with easy access to an elsan point, a tap and some shops, at the very least. Also, if possible we wanted pretty views and interesting local walks...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the map we decided to head for Westport Lake, near the Harecastle Tunnel, just a couple of days travel away, where there are boaters' facilities, (an elsan point, loo and shower) and taps within easy reach. We were a little sad to leave Leek so soon, but promised to return to the Caldon Canal and give it the time it deserves. We headed back the way we had come, turning right onto the Trent and Mersey Canal at Etruria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stopping off for diesel, coal and water on the way, we arrived at Westport Lake on Monday 2nd November and had the pick of the moorings. We settled on a space in a gap in the trees, where the solar panels had a chance of some sunshine and from where we could see the lake. That same evening we were all informed that the second lockdown would begin on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201121_102252500_HDRcropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our mooring space at Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201102_121955448_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Enough coal to sink a narrowboat! Or at least tip its bow noticeably waterwards...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From the Black Country Museum to Westport Lake 17th October - 2nd November 2020</summary></entry></feed>