<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-06-16T20:28:37+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Liberty Belle Newsletter</title><subtitle>A day-by-day account of our time aboard the Liberty Belle narrowboat.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Normal Service is Resumed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/07/normal-service-is-resumed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Normal Service is Resumed" /><published>2021-06-07T19:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-07T19:44:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/07/normal-service-is-resumed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/06/07/normal-service-is-resumed.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Marple to Anderton via Runcorn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12th - 23rd April 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n95map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210412-P1360763.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving our mooring in Marple&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were expected to move around again we looked at our options and they were few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our route back south towards Birmingham was blocked because an emergency repair for a culvert in Macclesfield required part of the canal to be drained for an indefinite amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other, longer, route to Birmingham via Manchester, along the Bridgewater and the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey canals, had been blocked by a landslide at Anderton for some months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could head off to Yorkshire through the Standedge tunnel but we might not fit through and it would mean all our planning involving our vaccines in Birmingham would have to be altered and become rather complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This left us with the option of re-doing the Peak Forest Canal. Oh well....it is certainly pretty and there are plenty of walks to do, especially if you take the train further into the Peak District.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile we heard from the Canal and River Trust that they were attempting to make provision for boats to pass by the landslide. As there was now hope that we would soon be able to move, it was worth hanging around for further news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210414_165744_754.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Walking back to Liberty Belle along the Peak Forest Canal towpath.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210416-P1040324.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Edale Welcoming Committee representative.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210413_101250150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony considering a new abode.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210413-P1040320.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Enjoying the local walks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210413_121127415.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Picnics are a must.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210416_131430233.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;En route to Kinder Scout, just before the path disappears.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that week we heard from the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust that enough of the landslide in Anderton had been cleared to allow boats to pass along the canal with supervision. There was the possibility that the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey canal would have to re-close if the soil shifted again, so great care was needed. From 21st April a team would be there daily to ensure safe passage. So, things were looking up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a new plan in place, we set off towards Birmingham via Anderton. Although we had been in the lift before, we had only turned around and gone back up again without exploring the river. So we incorporated a trip on the River Weaver into our new plan and booked our passage on the Anderton Boat lift, going down on Tony's birthday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the boat lift had limited opening days so we would be spending a relaxed 6 days on the river, before returning to the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey Canal and dashing to Birmingham with limited time to get to Tony's second vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210417-P1360822.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving Bugsworth Basin, heading back to Marple...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210415-P1360786.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... past New Mills...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210417-P1040332.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... underneath the Disley lift bridge...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210418-P1040336.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...down the Marple lock flight...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210418-P1360872.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...then finally over the Marple aqueduct to freedom!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some beautiful weather, and even had to use suncream on occasions, but with it came the future threat of the lack of water in the canals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The celandine flowers looked cheerful in the sunshine but were soon outshone by glorious kingcups. With the spring flowers came the goslings, ducklings, baby coots and, Tony's favourite, moorhen chicks. We took great delight in seeing them, taking care not to get between them and their mothers; the poor things get so frantic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360909cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Proud mother.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Mallard fathers are not interested in family life.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210418-P1360877.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Expectant mother with her feather lined nest.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Expectant father is nervously pacing nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210421-P1370074cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another expectant mother.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Expectant father is somewhere out of sight, no doubt being aggressive towards someone or something that has no idea why.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way to Anderton we had to tackle Manchester, which always makes me a little tense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading into the city, we encountered an empty pound between two locks. Someone had left a paddle up in one of the locks, leaving the water to drain out overnight. It took time to rectify this before we could get very far, so that was a bad start....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after that, everything went smoothly and we found that the best mooring in central Manchester was there for the taking. It is the only pretty mooring there is, on an aqueduct in a neat residential area. The sun was shining and my coldness towards the city was warming slightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1040339.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canals are often lined with bikes and trolleys but we don't get to see them until the water is drained.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360917.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Locking in the sunshine....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360923.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... taking it in turns....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210419-P1360916.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;.... and sharing our one can of beer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wandered off to explore near our mooring and take a look at the locks we would be tackling the next morning. They are double locks, which were overflowing with water and go underneath the city. It all looked rather daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning the weather was again sunny but we quickly disappeared under the city where the gloom and smell of stale urine dampened our spirits a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210420_082010325.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beneath Manchester....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360939.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... trying not to breath too deeply.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the sturdy look of the locks, they were not too difficult to work and we emerged into daylight and fresher air soon enough. Lots of repair work was going on around us, with scaffolding and floating pontoons alive with fluorescent jackets and cheerful banter. All work had to stop whilst we passed by and some of the available muscle was applied to the lock gates, for which I was grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We emerged from the locks into a low cutting alongside the Gay Quarter of Manchester, lined with trees full of blossom and Gay Pride flags waving in the sunshine, I suddenly felt a love for the city. How fickle I am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening we moored up and Tony noticed that we were surrounded by a film of diesel, glistening in the sun, which was concerning. He was puzzling over this when a man moored opposite us noticed his furrowed brow and assured us that the diesel had been there before we turned up. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360968.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Emerging into daylight. A lovely pair of sculptures hidden in a corner.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pink blossom in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Manchester behind us we were on the privately owned Bridgewater Canal. Dating back to 1761, it was the first British Canal that didn't follow an existing water course and so has plenty of history. However, we didn't hang around because this was our second visit and we wanted to make up enough time to divert to Runcorn before our date with the Anderton Boat Lift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1360982.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A restored milestone at the start of the Bridgewater Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1370030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At regular intervals along the Bridgewater Canal are cranes, poised to slide wooden beams across the canal to isolate a section so that it can be drained and repaired.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A section of the Bridgewater Canal runs parallel to the Manchester Ship Canal then bends away to the South. Here a branch (added to the canal in 1776) turns off to Runcorn. We turned along this pretty stretch, lined with woodland carpeted with bluebells. Here, amongst the usual ducks and geese we saw a shoveller duck, which was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210422-P1370103.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The pretty Bridgewater Canal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210420-P1370009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...eventually runs parallel to the Manchester Ship Canal which can occasionally be glimpsed.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Runcorn the Bridgewater Canal, The Manchester Ship Canal and the River Mersey meet. Sadly the Bridgewater Canal now comes to an abrupt and disappointing end here where there was once a dramatic flight of 10 locks down to The Mersey. These were filled in and built over, so can never be restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210421-P1370095.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Waterloo Bridge at the end of the Bridgewater canal, where it used to travel down the locks to the river.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now it is just a turning space.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210421-P1040361.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Two bridges spanning the River Mersey and the Manchester Ship Canal between Runcorn and Widnes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The 1868 railway bridge and the 1961 road and foot bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210421_151723247.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The River Mersey on the left, with the tide out, alongside the Manchester Ship Canal and Runcorn on the far right.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210421_150113704.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Which came first, the building or the bridge?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having briefly explored Runcorn, we turned back and joined the Trent and Mersey canal, slipping carefully past the landslide and arriving at the Anderton Boat lift ready for our descent onto the River Weaver, a whole day ahead of schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210422-P1370123.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/20210422-P1370129.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The landslide which has blocked the canal since Storm Christoph in January, now partially cleared.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n95/IMG_20210422_155055_083.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Relieved to have passed the landslide and finally be in Anderton.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently we are moored in Cambrian Wharf, central Birmingham, which we love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am trying to catch up on newsletters.....well, this is a start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony is touching up Liberty Belle's paintwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have time on our hands because we are waiting for Liberty Belle's appointment in Alvechurch's boatyard on 14th June......but that's another story!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Marple to Anderton via Runcorn 12th - 23rd April 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Escape to the Hills</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/04/12/escape-to-the-hills.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Escape to the Hills" /><published>2021-04-12T19:31:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-12T19:31:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/04/12/escape-to-the-hills</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/04/12/escape-to-the-hills.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Westport Lake to Marple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;12th January - 12th April 2021&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;(Three whole months!)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n94map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, from 12th April, we are obliged to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until  now we have been allowed to move for essential journeys only. At first this meant popping to the tap and elsan point, maybe staying there for a night or two, then returning to Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210125-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Westport Lake frozen over.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210214-P1040156.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oddly shaped icicles hanging over the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210214-P1040163.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Thoughts of spring came a little early for this coot, surrounded by icicles.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210118_124201_092.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Making kindling from a pallet found in a skip....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210123-P1360535.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Setting off for water.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210213_112201_845.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Knowing the canal was due to freeze over, we stayed near the tap in Etruria, watched over by James Brindley&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210211-P1360547.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;By connecting together our two hoses we were able to connect Liberty Belle to the tap.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210214_103905183_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These two hire boats made their appointment at the boatyard by charging at the ice full speed, breaking it as they went.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210112_105623429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A huge new bridge being built with the aid of a man with a spirit level...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210115-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony dreaming of one day travelling through the Harecastle Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210202_133707534.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We visited some nearby piglets occasionally for something different to do.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the lack of bedding, (and the bulging laundry bag making it difficult to keep the hall cupboard doors shut), made a trip to a washing machine into an essential journey. We do most of our washing by hand but we have nowhere to hang out anything as big as a bed sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outdoor machine we had used in Endon was no longer available to us because of the ongoing maintenance work on the Caldon Canal.... The inside of a warm, steamy launderette did not appeal, even if we could find one that was open. The next nearest outdoor machine was 'beyond the tunnel', which had become an almost mythical place. My goodness, excitement was in the air!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A journey was afoot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We booked our passage through the Harecastle Tunnel. So far so good. Now there was the small matter of Liberty Belle's intermittent horn and unreliable front light....both of which we needed to work on command for our pre-tunnel safety inspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These pieces of equipment had been deteriorating for some time and Tony had ordered new ones, delivered successfully to Mary, to be picked up at Christmas....You see what went wrong there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, despite Tony's efforts, the likelihood of them working when required had become a game of chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wondered whether having a wife with a torch at the front of the boat, wired in to the horn mechanism and ready to scream at the appropriate moment, would be sufficient. The torch part of the plan seemed sensible enough for Tony to go out and buy a good quality one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travelled to the tunnel the day before our booking and moored there for the night. It is usually a quiet area with the occasional walker or cyclist passing by. On this occasion a couple of twits decided to wander about with an air-horn! Luckily they moved on before bedtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topping up our water supply at the tap the next morning, the CRT chap, in charge of letting us into the tunnel, and, crucially, carrying out the safety check, arrived. Tony was testing Liberty Belle's horn. It was in a good mood this morning, having been protected from the rain for a few days in a plastic bag. We had a friendly chat, during which we confessed about the state of our equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was happy to relate that he had already heard the horn working and that the torch would suffice if the light failed, and suggested that we keep the internal boat lights on too. Something that we usually did anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His bad news was that the CRT air-horn had been stolen overnight, an essential piece of safety equipment without which we were going nowhere! Oh heck. I gave him an account of the air-horn incident the evening before and an entirely useless 'description' of the lads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few phone calls and a short wait later, a CRT van arrived and a woman handed over half a dozen air-horns! Dressed in our life jackets and leather hats, we were ready and off we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Tony scraping the top of his hat on an especially low part of the tunnel, and Liberty Belle leaving a little blue paint as a momento on the tunnel wall, we made it through in very good time. We really had arrived in the mythical land of Kidsgrove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned onto the Macclesfield Canal and moored on the aqueduct over the Trent and Mersey Canal. We were close to Kidsgrove railway station, so that Tony could get to Birmingham for his first vaccine! Fabulous! We stayed there until we were in danger of running out of water, then moved the short distance to the next tap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210219-P1360557.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning onto the Macclesfield Canal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210224_091742062_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....viewing the Trent and Mersey below&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210221_142458335.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We were surprised to find that many gravestones in Kidsgrove included the address of the deceased.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210226-P1040198.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In each place that we stopped we had a little exploring to do.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here is Tony at Mow Cop folly.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210226_101347898_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A snack with a view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210228_114427415_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heady heights.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, from facility to facility, we gradually made our way to the most convenient mooring space for the washing machine. We walked the mile or so uphill to the machines in a Londis car park on a traffic island in Congleton. Hurray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote a man we met on the towpath, who, in better times, had journeyed around Europe with his family in a camper van, &quot;Who needs LSD when you can get that excited over access to a washing machine?&quot; I obviously look more worldly wise than I am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210227-P1360619.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A beautiful day with the pretty Congleton Aqueduct ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210227-P1360605.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Macclesfield Canal still has many of the original milestones in place.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the washing was done we had to then decide what our strategy would be for the rest of the lockdown. Going back to Westport Lake wouldn't be an essential journey and seemed a daft thing to do anyway, crowded as it was. We couldn't stay at a mooring near the washing machine as there were no other facilities near there. So, we decided we would continue forwards, one essential journey at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210225_133033724_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony walking over one of this canal's famous snake bridges&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210227-P1360613.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...where the towpath crosses the canal, a horse can cross over without being unhitched from the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then suddenly I had the chance to book my first vaccine in Birmingham! This required an essential journey to Macclesfield, for the railway station. We were pleased to note that there were two taps marked there on our map. Perfect. Except that neither of the taps actually exist&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210307-P1360644.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading towards the hills of the Peak District.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210306-P1360638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What do hills mean?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hills mean locks!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210305_092817593.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hills also mean views.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At Bosley Reservoir, built to feed the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Below you can see the feeder canal heading towards the top lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210307-P1040230.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We followed 'The Silk Road' to Macclesfield railway station and thus to Birmingham for my vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210309-P1360687.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We like to see old mill buildings preserved, with their dignity intact.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210307-P1360657.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There are several dotted along the canals in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Macclesfield until we needed water then headed for the tap in Poynton. Mooring nearby we stayed to explore the area, moving on again when we needed the boaters' facilities in the lovely Marple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marple is a delightful spot, with facilites and shops, (including a bakery where they sell dangerously excellent pastries), as well as beautiful surroundings and interesting walks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to eek out our coal supply but eventually we had to admit that we needed to find a boatyard or marina that would sell us some. So we turned onto the Peak Forest Canal and made our gradual way to the marina, which, it turned out, was only open three days a week. Of course we had arrived on the wrong day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued to Bugsworth Basin and Whaley Bridge, at the end of the Peak Forest Canal, where we stayed until we were sure that the marina was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as a few bags of coal we also took the opportunity to replace an empty gas bottle and fill up on diesel. Topped up with everything, we made our way back to the facilities at Marple to await the hoped for 'great release' on the 12th April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210326_162812_016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Marple mooring, between two snake bridges...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210319-P1360706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and opposite a busy Canal &amp;amp; River Trust yard.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210312_104116890.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Marple lamp post depicting a narrow boat crossing the aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210313_140344519.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The canal features on High Lane's lamp posts too.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210316-P1040243.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Roman Bridge, near Marple, was labelled as such by the Victorians. It's actually an 18th Century construction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210316_134132188.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A tunnel built alongside one of the locks in Marple, for the horses.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210317-WA0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Marple's 'track-a-duct' as viewed through an arch of the aquaduct, where they both pass over the River Goyt&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210317_102756578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The first iron bridge in the Northwest, built over the River Goyt in 1813&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This fancy, modern material was considered for the Marple aqueduct but they opted for stone.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210318_124227023_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Chad standing in Saint Chad's well near Saint Chad's Kirk in Chadkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210318_122742368.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A monk outside Saint Chad's Kirk in Chadkirk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(wearing enough layers for wintering on a narrow boat)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210320-P1040248.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lyme Park Estate House.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is the back entrance!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210320-P1040245.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In the distance is Lyme's hunting lodge,built in 1737 (replacing one built in 1580).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It became known as The Cage because poachers were jailed there.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040259.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Standing stone sundial in Torrs Riverside Park, alongside the Peak Forest Canal.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(It didn't appear to be working...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG_20210322_103353471.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Trig point on Cobden Edge overlooking canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New Mills' Millennium walkway, above the River Goyt, alongside the railway and opposite the Torrs Mill.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040278.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A mill race for transporting water from the River Goyt, under the road bridge to one of the mills.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1040272.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the site of a derelict mill, a Reverse Archimedes Screw, using the old weir to provide New Mills residents with electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210323-P1360710.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Alongside the Peak Forest Canal is a sugar coated sweet factory!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210325-P1360735.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the end of the Peak Forest Canal is Bugsworth Basin and lime kilns.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beautiful and full of history.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210325-P1040295.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring Bugsworth Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/20210324-P1040283.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Toddbrook Reservoir threatened to engulf Whaley Bridge in August 2019. The repairs are not complete but, luckily for me, it has been emptied.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n94/IMG-20210325-WA0006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;All these pipes pump the water out of the reservoir while the repairs on the dam continue.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
These stones lie on the 2 degrees West longitude. At local midday (13:08 BST, 12:08 GMT), the larger stone supposedly casts its shadow on one of the other standing stones. This, of course, assumes that the sun is out..
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hoped that we would be able to make our way back to Birmingham where we each have a vaccine appointment in May, 12 days apart. Whilst there we planned to collect a hire car and visit Mary, between appointments, (assuming Boris's plan for May 17th goes ahead) then bring her back to the boat for a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual there are now some obstacles in our way. Boats can no longer pass through Macclesfield. A culvert there is leaking and the canal has been drained to enable it to be repaired. The canal is not expected to reopen until the end of June. Circling around through Manchester and along the Bridgewater Canal to reach Birmingham has not been possible for months due to a blockage near the Anderton Boat Lift. We are expecting an email with an update on this situation on 20th April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for now, we must leave Marple because the mooring restrictions have been reinstated, but we will travel along the Peak Forest Canal again. We will decide what to do when we have more information next week...&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Westport Lake to Marple</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Winter’s Tale</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/01/13/a-winters-tale.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Winter's Tale" /><published>2021-01-13T10:52:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T10:52:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/01/13/a-winters-tale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2021/01/13/a-winters-tale.html">&lt;h2&gt;Westport Lake to Westport Lake with excursions on the Caldon Canal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3rd December 2020 - 11th January 2021&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n93map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360335.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Brrrrrr!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were released from Lockdown 2 into tier 3. Once we had established that the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust expected us to move around on the canal, (but without leaving our tier), we set off for the Caldon Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were going to explore the branch to the village of Froghall via the River Churnet, but first we re-travelled the Leek Branch because we had booked ourselves in for the flu jab with a pharmacist there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201206-P1360176.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Santa resting on a canalside bench.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201208-P1040049.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This obstruction in the canal used to be the pivot point of a swing bridge linking a local mill with the main railway line.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winter had begun with a lot of rain, which for boaters means flooded rivers, muddy towpaths, slippery locks, dirty boots and trying to keep carpets clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generally remove our boots before walking through the boat, but occasionally I need to dash through to the front doors when we are travelling. We have a collection of cheap rubber doormats, enough to lay end to end along the carpet. Usually I put them down in advance, but occasionally I feel like Gromit, in 'The Wrong Trousers', laying track as I go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before leaving Leek, we spent a little time exploring the local area because we had left rather too abruptly last time we were there. This involved visiting a few reservoirs...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201207_103255165_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On our way to 'Brown Edge' just outside the Peak District.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201207_114525440_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At Knypersley Reservoir, built to keep the canal topped up, is a dramatic Warder's Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201208-P1040055.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stanley Pool reservoir, built to keep the canal topped up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201210_123612345_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Rudyard Reservoir, you guessed it, built to keep the canal topped up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were satisfied that we had done as much exploring as we could, given the very muddy conditions, we turned around and headed for the branch to Froghall. Part of this section of the canal follows the River Churnet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the river level was too high for us to take Liberty Belle along it, so we walked to Froghall instead, just to see what we were missing. This only reinforced our desire to travel there by boat as soon as we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360204.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazelhurst Junction on the Caldon Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leek or Froghall?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360210.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading down the locks towards Froghall.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360226.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These locks have pretty little split bridges, with modern railings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1040067.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking back at Hazelhurst Junction from the River Churnet.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201214-P1360252.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hazelhurst Aqueduct carrying the branch to Leek over the main Caldon Canal to Froghall.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201218-P1360328.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the old flint mills on the Caldon Canal. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201216-P1040111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cheddleton Station on the preserved Churnet Valley Railway line.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201217-P1360285.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of their diesel locomotives is named 'Eastleigh' in honour of its origins.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201217-P1360310.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The River Churnet as it comes alongside the Caldon Canal....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201217-P1360305.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....and they join at this lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201214_140816892cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Knock, knock!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Anyone home?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201214_141857015_HDRcropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At Deep Hayes Country Park, these stepping stones are disappearing fast.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201215-P1040093.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Froghall Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if we could travel this far on the river, Liberty Belle is a bit too tall to go through to the wharf beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201215-P1040085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Victorian Lime Kilns at Froghall Wharf.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Christmas was getting close. We had a hire car booked from Stoke-on-Trent to take us to Mary's for the festivities and we wanted to leave Liberty Belle at Westport Lake, where we thought she would be safe. So, off we went, arriving at our mooring safe and sound, only to hear that Christmas gatherings were no longer allowed to be overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a disappointment. So, that was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we heard that Joe and Kirsty would be keeping Mary company for Christmas dinner and we had got used to the idea of it being just the two of us on the boat, Tony shopped for all the festive food and we settled in and made the most of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, all things considered, we had a very pleasant time. The weather had turned to snow which was great fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201222-P1360333.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We don't need a Christmas Tree because we can sit and look at the one on the boat in front!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360348.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We do need our very own snowman though, of course!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360358.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I let him borrow my hat, just for the photo.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201228-P1360416cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A walk around Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201225-WA0011cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We decided to use our new table extension over Christmas, to spread out our festive spread!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201225_144003161cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is the disadvantage of the table extension...!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Despite this inconvenience, we liked the extra space and kept it for well over a week!)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20201225_135957819.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Free range chickens are rare here, Tony searched the whole of Stoke for this one!)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201228-WA0024cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our cherry brandy.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Made from wild cherries picked during our Sunbury lockdown and saved for Christmas. Very yummy!)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201225-WA0003cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Christmas Day walk around the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG-20201225-WA0004cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Post-walk hot chocolate with a tot of something extra...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Christmas, once our water had run out, we set off for the tap at the start of the Caldon Canal, stopping off at the boatyard where we hoped to buy coal, gas and diesel, only to find that it was closed until 4th January. Oh well, we were not desperate...yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once on the Caldon Canal we decided to continue and try again to get to Froghall. The ground was now frozen so mud was no longer a problem but there was some ice around, so we had to be careful where we put our feet, particularly at the locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/20201229-P1360455.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;More snow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20210101_120258022_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;New Year's day walk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hadn't got far before we were plunged into tier 4. This time we were expected not to move, except for essentials. So, there we were, at the boaters services near Endon, still several miles from Froghall, with a tap, Elsan point, hot showers and a couple of week's worth of coal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were happy to stay there until our coal supply forced us to travel back to the boatyard on the Trent &amp;amp; Mersey Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20210102_101850801_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony looking from the bridge with the River Churnet below.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n93/IMG_20210102_102452466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A little picnic at the lock, before turning back.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temperature dropped further and froze us in, just for a day, but it gave us food for thought. If we were to get frozen in for a long spell, fetching coal would not be an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly we were all in full lockdown again, meaning we could only move for essentials. Taking into account the weather forecast and our coal situation, we decided to head back to Westport Lake and hope for a mooring space for us there...  Froghall would have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were planning our journey to this area, we checked the CRT website for any stoppages that might affect us, to make sure we wouldn't get stuck behind a lock or bridge that was being repaired. The website indicates when and where the repairs are due to take place and, because they have to tell us so far in advance, the date range given is a worst case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we did not expect to be here for anywhere near this length of time.....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travelled through the first five locks. As I approached the next lift bridge I saw CRT workers fencing it off. As they let me through to operate it, I asked what was happening... There was a scheduled repair, due to take 8 weeks, which should have been started the day before but they had been delayed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh my goodness! We hadn't checked the stoppages for January! We felt foolish and soooo lucky to be able to pass through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the next lock, workmen again. Oh no. Another stoppage. This one was also booked for several weeks. We moored up and tentatively asked when they hoped to be finished. We were told that they were going to be working until Friday, just a couple of days away. Phew! Our immediate problem was now our water supply, not coal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, for some reason unknown to us, the work wasn't finished on Friday. Desperate for showers, Tony and I walked the 6 mile round trip to the facilities back in Endon on Saturday morning, with Tony carrying several litres of water back with him in his rucksack, to ensure we didn't run out completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we had been moored near the closed lock, we had witnessed CRT boats travelling through on several occasions and the lock gates were not padlocked. We decided that we were desperate enough to travel through and did so on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to explain ourselves on a couple of occasions to boaters who knew about the closure, but so far the CRT have not caught up with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time we had patches of ice to push through and some of the locks were treacherous, but by placing my feet carefully and holding on to railings wherever I could, we made it, first to the water tap and then to the boatyard, where we purchased coal, cooking gas and diesel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fully loaded with what we needed, we arrived at Westport Lake and, luckily, there was a mooring space for us. It is raining again and our snowman has disappeared. We will have to keep an eye on the forecast to make sure we don't run out of water just before we get iced in again, but the temperature for the next few days is in our favour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Message...&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;We both send our best wishes to you all. Keep your heads down, fingers crossed and masks on. I know some of you have had your vaccines, so the rest of us need to keep the faith and hold on, it's coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Back in &quot;Lockdown 1.0&quot; I was sitting on a bench outside a church which had recently opened for private prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;An older lady who had visited the church in her mobility scooter and I got chatting. She was obviously concerned about people coming too close so I suggested she get a 2 metre stick and sharpen it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;She told me off, saying that it didn't sound very Christian, so I suggested the alternative of a 2 metre stick with something soft at the end instead. She wasn't convinced....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Quite right too. Wielding sticks at each other is probably not the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Keep safe everyone. xx&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">Westport Lake to Westport Lake with excursions on the Caldon Canal 3rd December 2020 - 11th January 2021</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lockdown Lake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/12/13/lockdown-lake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lockdown Lake" /><published>2020-12-13T13:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T13:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/12/13/lockdown-lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/12/13/lockdown-lake.html">&lt;h2&gt;Westport Lake, Stoke-on-Trent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3rd November - 2nd December 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n92map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_102045702_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Westport Lake as seen from the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201204-P1360143.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This useful clock has helped us to keep track of the lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(The 'banana clock' method from the last lockdown began to lose one day each week when we started eating cooked breakfasts on Saturdays...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard, on the grapevine, that Stoke-on-Trent is an area unsafe for boaters, where we are likely to be boarded by unwelcome visitors or have stones thrown at us. Last month we met a boater heading away from this area who bent my ear about her terrible Stoke-on-Trent experience.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, all I can say is that we have been here for weeks and walked along the tow path in both directions many times, visited local towns and parks and at no time has anyone made us feel uncomfortable in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly there are some areas which could do with a tidy up and many of the old buildings have been sadly neglected. However, the canals, towpaths and local parks are noticeably clean, tidy and well kept. We have no regrets concerning our decision to moor here. We have wildlife to watch, walks to choose from, access to supermarkets and we are only a short boat trip away from water taps.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have access to one tap a mile to the north at Harecastle Tunnel and another a few miles to the south in Etruria, at the junction of the Caldon Canal. It makes a nice change to take a trip out to one or the other each week for a top-up.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etruria is named after an Italian district renowned for their artistic products, which Wedgwood presumably hoped would rub off a little.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caldon Canal is named after the local village of Cauldon, but was misspelled on the official documentation authorising the building of the canal...&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201104-P1030945.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A stroll along the canal in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201107_111903140_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A coffee outside Harecastle Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201104-P1030942.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A bottle kiln looking rather dilapidated and surrounded by rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_095801496.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A local boatyard advertising&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;TACLE AND BAIT AIR GUNS ARCHERY BOATS AND ENGINES COUNTRY &amp;amp; WESTERN LINE DANCING&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_100713020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Magnet fishing is popular on canals, the metal found is piled up by the towpath. This piece is covered in mussel shells.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_092841436.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Hanley Cemetery lies in the triangle of land at the junction of the Caldon and Trent &amp;amp; Mersey canals&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201117-P1360082.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The boaters' facilities at Etruria.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201110-P1360067.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching the tap at Harecastle Tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Westport Lake&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is much loved by the locals and there are always people here appreciating it, whatever the weather. Very young children, dressed in waterproofs from head to toe, are brought here by their parents or grandparents to charge about on balance bikes, feed the geese, run around in the maze and splash in puddles whilst the adults chat or nurse a takeaway coffee. It's a joy to watch.&lt;p&gt; 

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1030979.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An art installation at Westport Lake,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;FOR ALL THOSE WHO HAVEN'T STOPPED&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;spelled out in small white stones.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_102412908.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The B'oatcake, (selling takeaway homemade Staffordshire oatcakes with hot fillings), moored tantalisingly close.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360045.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There is no danger of getting lost in the Westport Lake maze, (the hedges are two feet tall) but the kids love chasing though it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360042.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A fabulous bug hotel in the shape of a railway engine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201118_161607988.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;According to the sign -&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;We do like:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;cut seedless grapes, birdseed, peas, oats and chopped lettuce&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201112_144137766_HDRcropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;We are more sophisticated than people realise. In fact, if you could peel the grapes too, that would be better...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have we been doing all this time?&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we have done a bit of walking and exploring, a few jobs around the boat, a little bit of reading, some bird watching....not much really.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201105_162708330.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony's newly finished table extension!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Marvellous!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Not that we are allowed guests...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201107_103119146.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring the local hills (or mudslides as I prefer to call them....)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201126_110535545.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring a local nature reserve in the fog.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_105307120_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A small park built within the foundations of an old gasometer.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201112_104346560.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A takeaway coffee from Hanley Park Pavilion Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201118_093755388.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the site of the old ironworks in Tunstall is &quot;Golden&quot;, a 21 metre tall steel spike, which lights up at night, representing the ironworks' flame.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201115_105321479.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Festival Park's stone circle (modern). Apparently it's &quot;full size&quot;, whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201115_104616695.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Josiah Wedgwood's head. I am not sure he would approve of being left unfinished...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoy looking out for and logging the birds we see around the lake and the canal, getting to know their character traits. Our biggest delight is our resident kingfisher. We see her most days, sometimes more than once.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the photos of our fellow residents that we have managed to take.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201108-P1360057cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kingfisher&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360041cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Robin&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201116_113819671cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canada and Greylag Geese&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360039cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;White farmyard geese&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201106-P1360040cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moorhen&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201123-P1360100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Coot&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201123-P1360113cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tufted Ducks&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201123-P1360108cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pochard&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201107-P1030963cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Great-Crested Grebe&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201127-P1360131cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Goosander&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201105_091905570cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canada Geese, Black-Headed Gulls and Cormorant.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201106_132107746cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;White duck&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard of Stoke-on-Trent before we arrived and had, in fact, passed through here on Liberty Belle once before, but we knew nothing about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it has city status, it is, in fact, a collection of six towns. One of the towns is called Stoke-upon-Trent, (note the difference there), which contains the minster and the main railway station, but the 'City Centre' is in the town of Hanley. The other towns are Tunstall, (where we are moored), Burslem, Fenton and Longton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we have been here, we have made it our business to explore each one of the towns in turn. They must all have been something to behold in times past, each trying to out compete the other with elaborate town halls, public parks, and other fabulous buildings. Sadly, along with the industrial buildings, most of them are in very poor repair, crumbling away. Such a shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_092604956_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liz Lemon's modern sculpture which includes contributions by local school children.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_094148368_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stoke-upon-Trent's minster (St Peter ad Vincula), with re-erected 13th Century arches, and Josiah Wedgwood's grave in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_093250074.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Remains of a pre-Norman stone cross, outside Stoke Minster, showing early examples of the Staffordshire Pretzel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201202_093407774.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Philip Hardaker's St Peter's community mosaic bench, made with the help of local children.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(We saw his Throne for the Common Person in Stone)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_112343608.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanley Park, showing the Pavilion Cafe, band stand and bridge over the canal. This beautiful Victorian park was restored in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201122_110250826_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanley cemetery's magnificent Chapel of Rest.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_085435622.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tunstall's Queen Victoria Jubilee Buildings, still a public library but originally also included art and science schools... &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_085519918.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... a fire station (closed in 1926) and public swimming pool (closed 2011).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_090519786_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tunstall's memorial to generations of the Adams Family who owned land, a mine and pottery factories in the area.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201121_090607219_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tunstall's magnificent Church of the Sacred Heart.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1030985.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burslem's old town hall is now the Sixth Form College.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201113_110810423_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burslem's Wedgwood Institute, built by public subscription as a memorial to Josiah Wedgwood, made arts, science and literature available to all.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Opened in 1869.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_110939766.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fenton's &quot;Onward &amp;amp; Upward&quot; sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_120205604_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Many grand old buildings in Stoke-on-Trent are in a poor state of repair.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It is common to see buddleia plants growing out of them. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_114836475.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;51&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old pottery building in Longton, left for the pigeons to roost in.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/IMG_20201201_115629345.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;52&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In contrast, these Longton buildings now form the Gladstone Pottery Museum. We hope to visit it one day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1040005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;53&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burslem's memorial to the 57 miners killed in the explosion at Sneyd Colliery in 1942&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n92/20201113-P1030999.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burselm's cast iron drinking fountain, 1881&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
Westport Lake
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1881 - Port Vale Football Club established a ground at the site&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1883 - Brownhills Colliery workings flooded and the lake began&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1884 - Port Vale forced to move their practice ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1890 - Smith Shirley's pleasure boating business established at the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1900 - Pottery waste and canal dredgings were dumped around the lake to raise the banks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1914 - Boating business began to decline at the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1930s - Boating had declined and pottery waste was dumped around the lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1940s - Jam Jar Wakes Fairs [Formerly known as Bradwell Wakes] held at Westport Lake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1967 - Lease of Westport Lake given to the City of Stoke-on-Trent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;1971 - Reclamation schemes saw Edward Heath opening the lake for sailing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;2009 - Westport Lake Visitor Centre built&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;sup id=&quot;fn2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;
The Adams family
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;were landowners in Tunstall from the 13th century and established as potters by 1447. Several of the Adams cousins were called William and owned pottery firms which must have been quite confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially they were among the principal rivals to Josiah Wedgwood but the last family business was sold to the Wedgwood group in 1966.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commemorated on the clock tower in Tunstall are:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams Tunstall landowner 1307&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;Richard Adams Coal Mine owner 1487&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;Thomas Adams 1563&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams Potter 1590&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;John Adams Chief Constable of Tunstall Manor Court 1616&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams Potter 1746 - 1805&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams 1777 - 1805&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;addednotes&quot;&gt;William Adams pottery manufacturer 1833 - 1905&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lockdown we were released into tier 3. The Canal &amp;amp; River Trust requested that boats resume cruising but without moving in or out of tier 3. That was a bit of a surprise. We cannot travel northwards, through Harecastle Tunnel, because beyond the tunnel is tier 2. We cannot travel southwards towards Birmingham (tier 3) because some maintenance work is being carried out in Stone. This leaves us with the Caldon Canal, which we are pleased to re-visit because we still have plenty to do there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming the rules don't change again at the last minute, we will be returning to Westport Lake and leaving Liberty Belle there whilst we travel in a hire car to Mary's for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you all manage to have a Merry, if different, Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the immortal words of the showbiz legend and raconteur, Count Arthur Strong,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;&quot;Condiments of the Seasoning&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to you all. xx&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">Westport Lake, Stoke-on-Trent 3rd November - 2nd December 2020 Our route</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Caldon Curtailed</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/23/caldon-curtailed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Caldon Curtailed" /><published>2020-11-23T14:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-23T14:33:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/23/caldon-curtailed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/23/caldon-curtailed.html">&lt;h2&gt;From the Black Country Museum to Westport Lake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17th October - 2nd November 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n91map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201103_163538_242.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Westport Lake&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having looked at the up-coming winter closures we decided that our plan should now be to fill in a few gaps on the Four Counties Ring section that we had missed so far, plus the Caldon Canal, followed by the Stourport Ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a return visit to Wolverhampton before turning north on the Staffordshire and Worcestershire Canal at Autherley junction, heading for Great Haywood via Gailey, Penkridge and Stafford; a new section to us. Along the way we saw a kingfisher, several heron, a woodpecker, a few jays, some Little Grebes and plenty of squirrels skipping along the towpath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gailey sounds like a much more interesting place that it turned out to be. We had heard it was a popular place to moor but we couldn't honestly see why....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Penkridge, at the only pub open, we learnt from a local character rather more than we needed about Scottish exports. The people he had been talking to when we arrived seemed to be relieved that he had moved on to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Stafford, we met a couple of friends who were walkers and very interesting to chat to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally arrived in Great Haywood, where Tony had been stung by a bee last time we were here. Thankfully it was too cold for bees this time.  We spent some time exploring the outside of the National Trust's Shugborough House estate. There is a beautiful bridge giving pedestrian access to the estate across the River Trent. It was built in 1550 by the Earl of Essex to enable Queen Elizabeth I to cross the river to go hunting. Originally it had 40 arches, now only 14 remain. (Presumably part of the bridge was demolished when the canal was built.) It is a long bridge but not very wide, so it proved to be inadequate for the Shugborough Hall residents who wished to travel by carriage. Another, wider bridge was built for them which became the preferred route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201017-P1350527cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Little Grebe, spotted amongst all the coots.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201018-P1350555.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Wolverhampton mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201018-P1350567.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Let's go to Great Haywood!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201019-P1350578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A three headed gongoozler.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201019-P1350589cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;OK, enough said.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maybe that explains the three headed cow...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201019-P1030823cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A bit narrow in places...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201019_133234584_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Gailey Lychgate. The church is now privately owned.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201019_134418106_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The other Gailey landmark.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_141612203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sir Martin Noel's Almshouses, Stafford&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_140945750_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. Mary's Church, Stafford. I keep mistakenly calling it the Cathedral...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_140025977.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony at the entrance to Stafford's 18th Century Lockup, an overnight holding cell for local prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201022_143134840.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Broad Eye Windmill, looking a bit sad and tatty.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;AQUEDUCT OVER RIVER SOW&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350646.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;River Sow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350651cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Left, Haywood Junction 1 mile 3 furlongs&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Right, Deptmore Lock, 4 miles 6 furlongs&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350687.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...even further if you insist on doing a 360 degree spin at Tixall Wide, just because you can!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350705.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;AQUEDUCT OVER RIVER TRENT&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350708.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;River Trent.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1350714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Haywood Junction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1030850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The cheapskate's view of Shugborough Hall...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1030860.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bridge over the River Trent from the canal to the Shugborough Estate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201023-P1030855.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Monument on Shugborough estate to George Anson, who circumnavigated the globe in 1740's aboard HMS Centurian.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A link to Gosport there!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we were back on familiar 'ground', heading for Stoke-on-Trent, with an increasing amount of narrowboat traffic, passing through;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Weston, (past the only remaining inland salt marsh in Britain)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stone, (past a lime kiln dating back to 1790's)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and on to Barlaston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; the way we met a couple and their teenage son aboard a hire boat. The couple hoped to buy their own boat in the near future, and travel in much the same way as we are. At the locks, we shared any information we thought might be useful and generally encouraged them to go ahead with their plans. How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201025-P1350744.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pedestrian's eye view of the upcoming lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201025-P1350753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The first boat we hired in 2003, Elinor Ginger, still afloat!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201025-P1350746.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An ancient Lime Kiln alongside the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201027_114441022_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Staffordshire Pretzel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201027-P1350771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Joule's Ales! Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201027-P1350757.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A celebration of Stone. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a bit concerned about travelling through Stoke-on-Trent, particularly during half term, so we set off early in the morning to tackle the five locks before turning off onto the Caldon Canal, where we hoped to get through another 3 locks and a lift bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were just approaching the second lock of the morning when we heard a shout and saw someone in a hi-vis jacket waving us on. Tony pulled over to let me off and the lock gates magically opened. At first I thought it was a CRT volunteer but it turned out to be the very friendly, chatty, &quot;Rob the Lock&quot;, who sped ahead of us on his bike, setting and opening each lock for us, pausing briefly to help with the gates and paddles before zooming off ahead again. He even turned up the Caldon Canal to help us there too. Rob's day job is as a boat mover but he has very little work at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He used to volunteer with the CRT with whom he still has a good relationship. Rather than get bored sitting at home he has a full English breakfast, fills his panniers with energy drinks and zooms about the towpath on his bike, helping where he can. He says it's good for his physical and mental health. Well, he certainly did us some good, we sped up those locks in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350795.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the many bottle kilns in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350804.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Let's go left!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350813.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The instructions for the staircase lock at the start of the Caldon Canal&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1350821.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bottle kilns spruced up and incorporated into the modern housing estate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very beginning of the Caldon Canal was industrial but pleasant enough. Then we came to Hanley Park which was a delightful surprise; a restored Victorian park with formal gardens, Pavilion Cafe, elegant band stand, lake, boathouse, decorative bridge and balustrades. We continued on along the increasingly pretty, winding canal and moored, as Rob had recommended, in Milton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part way along, the Caldon Canal splits in two, with the main branch descending through some locks and heading for Froghall, and the second branch passing over the main canal on an aqueduct and heading for Leek. We went along the Leek Branch first. My goodness the views were fabulous. We decided there and then that we would stay in Leek for a few days to give us a chance to explore the area on foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201102_170023_448.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanley Park&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201102-P1350995.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;James Brindley, canal engineer, in Etruria at the beginning of the Caldon Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201028-P1030864.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pretty Caldon Canal&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1350844.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fascinating lockside artwork referencing local industries and landmarks. Note the Staffordshire Pretzel&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1350879.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing the locks down to the lower canal and heading for Leek.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201031-P1350952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Emerging from under a bridge on the Leek Branch to face this wonderful view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1350925.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leek tunnel is a tight squeeze...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201030_142603899_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leek's terraced Cemetary.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1030908croppped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;1676 Elizabeth Ash Almshouses built for local Leek women over the age of 60.
&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/20201030-P1030903cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Settle down on a Leek bench, and rest like a hen on a pretzel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly there were rumours that there would be a second lockdown. The Caldon Canal, although absolutely beautiful, doesn't have much in the way of facilities for boaters, so it isn't ideal for an enforced lengthy stay. We needed to get to a mooring with easy access to an elsan point, a tap and some shops, at the very least. Also, if possible we wanted pretty views and interesting local walks...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the map we decided to head for Westport Lake, near the Harecastle Tunnel, just a couple of days travel away, where there are boaters' facilities, (an elsan point, loo and shower) and taps within easy reach. We were a little sad to leave Leek so soon, but promised to return to the Caldon Canal and give it the time it deserves. We headed back the way we had come, turning right onto the Trent and Mersey Canal at Etruria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stopping off for diesel, coal and water on the way, we arrived at Westport Lake on Monday 2nd November and had the pick of the moorings. We settled on a space in a gap in the trees, where the solar panels had a chance of some sunshine and from where we could see the lake. That same evening we were all informed that the second lockdown would begin on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201121_102252500_HDRcropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our mooring space at Westport Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n91/IMG_20201102_121955448_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Enough coal to sink a narrowboat! Or at least tip its bow noticeably waterwards...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From the Black Country Museum to Westport Lake 17th October - 2nd November 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Old and The New</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/11/the-old-and-the-new.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Old and The New" /><published>2020-11-11T18:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T18:27:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/11/the-old-and-the-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/11/the-old-and-the-new.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Stratford-upon-Avon to The Black Country Museum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9th -16th October 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n90map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201009-P1350091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The return to narrow canals!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived back in Stratford-upon-Avon, Tony took back the hire car and, after a bit of lunch, we set off along the Stratford Canal to get a few locks done before the end of the day. Rivers are very exciting but being back on a narrow canal felt good. We had travelled this way two years before but I had forgotten how pretty the Stratford Canal is with its neat little bridges, aqueducts and cottages with barrel shaped roofs. These cottages were built using the same techniques as the bridges, possibly by the same people using the original wooden forms. Cunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one of the locks a group of teenage lads took quite an interest in us, asking all sorts of questions about the canal boating life, then wishing us well as we left. We meet a lot of interested people as we potter around the canals but usually they are people our own age or older, or young children, so this made a refreshing change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the next day cruising all the way to Lowsonford's Fleur de Lys pub, 9 miles and 20 locks away. Tony introduced an added incentive by booking us a table there for Sunday lunch the following day. Having shared the driving and locking duties between us, we arrived in plenty of time for a relaxing beer in the garden before the afternoon was over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201010-P1350111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stratford Canal's bridges. Some a tight squeeze...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201010-P1030770.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...others sweeping across the canal with a flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201010-P1350114.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Aqueducts, some dramatic...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201010-P1350143.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...others quite quaint.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201010-P1350155.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pretty barrel roofed lock cottage.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/IMG_20201010_165149110_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Fleur de Lys garden marquee with Liberty Belle in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having enjoyed our delicious lunch (in very covid-aware surroundings), we set off again for Kingswood junction. As we passed under the oak trees lining the canal we were bombarded with acorns, it was quite violent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201011-P1350165.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony making a new friend.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201011-P1350171.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;More neat little bridges and barrel roofed buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Kingswood we were on the increasingly busy North Stratford Canal and hoped to complete 23 locks on the first day. We were lucky enough to have some help from the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust volunteers, one of whom escorted us up the main Lapworth Flight, forging ahead to set each lock, so the going was easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the day I observed a technique for opening the double lock gates which I couldn't help trying for myself. It didn't only save time and energy but was great fun too, so I was rather pleased with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at our destination in Lapworth by lunch time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201012-P1350189.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;My new trick, kicking open the gates as I cross over the lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201013-P1030776.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lapworth's War Memorial has a sundial on each face of its triangular top stone. Each one quite different from the others.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201013-P1030778.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... some detail.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to get to Birmingham where we had arranged to meet up with Julia in a Jewellery Quarter cafe for lunch, but suddenly the city was put under extra restrictions which caused an emergency re-think! After a short discussion, we moved both the date and the venue back one space to the following day at the Fleur de Lys! Perfect. Not only did we see get to catch up with our Julia, we had another excellent meal and she presented us with a goody bag of homemade cakes, jam and pickle! We felt very spoilt indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still had to travel through Birmingham so onwards and upwards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/IMG_20201014_091804578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We braved the guard goose at Swallow Cruisers to buy coal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350230.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Brandwood tunnel, with the boat ahead of us in silhouette.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350244.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This old guillotine gate is no longer in use but has been restored and kept for historical interest.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350325.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maryvale Road Bridge with a tunnel for the canal and one for the railway.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350284.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cadbury in Bournville. It doesn't look like much fun.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350276.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bournvilles railway station, alongside the canal, is Cadbury coloured.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350209.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We see all sorts of names on narrowboats. This one is called 'Baby Blue'...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and has an illustration of how narrow boats are delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201014-P1350307.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Brum skyline.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/IMG_20201015_084745_014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A sunny Gas Street Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored in Gas Street Basin and briefly risked the market for some fresh veg, before moving swiftly on to moor outside the Black Country Museum, on our way north to explore some sections of canal new to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we travelled along the Birmingham New Main Line instead of the Old Main Line. The straight new canal (1827) was built to speed up the travel from Gas Street Basin to Tipton, avoiding the locks and winding nature of the Old Main Line. The older canal is much prettier than the new one but, having looked down on it from above, I was excited to be travelling along it at last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was particularly looking forward to seeing the beautiful Engine Arm aqueduct from below. It didn't disappoint. Looking up at a decorative or well engineered bridge or aqueduct from below has a similar effect on me as looking up at the architecture inside a Church or Cathedral. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350360.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Birmingham centre, showing the turning for Sherbourne Wharf to the right and Gas Street Basin to the left.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350381.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Welling up as we approach the beautiful Engine Arm aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350387.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... some detail.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350392.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Galton Valley Canal Museum looks bigger from the lower New Main Line Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wide and straight, the New Main Line has it's own beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350421.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;About to pass under the Old Main Line and the motorway at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201015-P1350430.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Old Main Line joins the New Main Line canal at Spon Lane&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1350472.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored outside the Black Country Museum...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1350482.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...Tony has dinner on.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent another day in the museum, despite the weather being a little wet at times, and again managed to find a couple of bits we hadn't seen before. Of course we treated ourselves to fish and chips for lunch, finding a seat underneath a tram-stop shelter, away from the rain. 
Back at the boat we lit our first fire of the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1030789.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A lovingly restored tram at the museum...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1030785.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...the backs of the seats 'up top' can be swung across, so the passenger can face either way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1030787.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;SPITTING PROHIBITED.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Jolly good.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1030794.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This lump of coal would see us through...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1030796.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This cart is being converted into the &quot;Childcatcher's wagon&quot; for Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/20201016-P1030797.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Fish and chips twice please!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christmas shopping...eek!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two of my favourite online shops for unique, handmade gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/IMG-20201111-WA0007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cathy's beautiful handbound, exposed spine notebooks are available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/uk/shop/KookyBook&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n90/HandmadeForChristmas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Rose Hatcher's &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.workhousechapel.co.uk/&quot;&gt;&quot;Handmade for Christmas&quot;&lt;/a&gt; has emerged from her chapel and gone online this year.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Stratford-upon-Avon to The Black Country Museum 9th -16th October 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Docks, Locks &amp;amp; Stocks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/01/docks-locks-and-stocks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Docks, Locks &amp; Stocks" /><published>2020-11-01T17:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-01T17:48:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/01/docks-locks-and-stocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/11/01/docks-locks-and-stocks.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Gloucester to Stratford-on-Avon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;28th September - 3rd October 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n89map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1350017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The 'Ever-present Hill'.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Gloucester Docks, we went back through the lock and onto the Partings, which held no fear for us now! We turned off the RIver Severn onto the River Avon at Tewkesbury. A large sign advised us to sound our horn as we approached the lock, which Tony did as he manoeuvred Liberty Belle towards the awkwardly angled lock landing. Suddenly the lock opened and we were ushered in by the lock keeper. The horn was to alert him to our presence rather than other boaters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lovely welcome; he checked our licence and gave us advice on the locks and mooring, explaining that we should look out for blue markers on the flood safe moorings. We moored immediately beyond the lock and walked into Tewkesbury. What a lovely town. We decided we would visit the Abbey the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200928-P1340939.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bye-bye Gloucester.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200928-P1340949.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Will it be finished by the time the flood waters reach it?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200928-P1340972.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The MASSIVE Upper Lode Lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200928-P1340981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching the first lock on the River Avon.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200928-P1030582.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle as seen from King John's Bridge, Tewkesbury&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200928-P1030605.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tewkesbury Abbey.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the early evening, Tony decided to try and get the heating to come on using the timer. We have never attempted this before but, as the temperature had become rather autumnal and we had a visitor on board, we thought it might be nice to wake up to a bit of warmth. However, despite watching videos on YouTube he couldn't quite get it to work, so he 'zero'ed' the timer, which meant it came on at midnight! Toasty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tewkesbury Abbey was lovely but some of it was out of bounds and there wasn't enough information available about what we did see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1030635.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The splendid painted ceiling inside the Tewkesbury Abbey Church&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1030642cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The carving on this misericord seat is also splendid, but in a different way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/IMG-20200929-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A dragon vet!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well I never...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1030656cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This sculpture struck me as quite sinister...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Abbey, we had hoped to have an afternoon tea, (birthday treat for yours truly), at the local cafe but we had been too quick and it was too early, so we bought birthday buns instead, took them back to the boat and enjoyed them on the move in the sunshine. (We also bought Tewkesbury sausages which turned out to be rivals for Braunston Bangers....!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1030659.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Birthday buns!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1350006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony enjoying the sunshine with Eckington Bridge behind him.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The River Avon is beautiful with views of an ever-present hill which we wound around for ages! Kingfishers escorted us past splendid houses with well kept lawns and private landing stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The autumn is definitely here with colourful trees brightening up the banks of the river and the distant woodlands.  The hedges are full of crab apples and berries, with blackthorn bushes so full of sloes that they create a purple haze in the sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200929-P1350026.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1350072cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle moored at one of the many excellent flood-safe mooring sites on the River Avon.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The River Avon navigation fell into disrepair after it was no longer commercially viable, as did most of the network, and was eventually restored using mostly private money and volunteers. Many of the locks were re-built by local borstal and Gloucester Prison inmates. Each lock is named twice, one name reflecting its locality and the other the main donor of the funds to rebuild it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On joining the River Avon, we had been instructed to tie Liberty Belle front and back before working the locks, (because they are double width and can be quite violent), which was time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although all of them are smart and well kept, many of the locks are a bit odd, with weirs formed by piles of rocks creating wild-looking and rather lovely rapids;  landing stages that are at an odd angle or too short or both, and a couple that are an odd shape. One has a swing bridge across the top which needs to be moved out of the way before using the lock and then replaced afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another has a ground paddle located way off to one side, behind a large sign, and I forgot to put it down as we left. There was a boat right behind us and, as it passed our mooring, Tony managed to call out to them and apologise for my mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1030692.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hold on tight!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1350048.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Such an odd shape...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201002-P1350077cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the River Avon's lockside weir rapids.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1350067cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This lock has an overhead tribute to  Robert Aickman, a local campaigner for the rebuilding of the navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030734.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The flood-proof lock keepers' 'refuge'dedicated to Eric Pritchard who built this and other features along the navigation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;&quot;IF YOU SEEK HIS MONUMENT LOOK AROUND YOU&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1350071.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A tribute to Robert Aickman alongside his lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201002-P1350079.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Colin P Witter Lock, built on unsteady ground, has huge girders for stability.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explored the Georgian town of Pershore, (of plum festival fame), determined to get some local plum jam. There was an Abbey here too. We keep coming across Abbeys on this trip that claim to have been one of the wealthiest of its time....I can't help wondering where all the less wealthy ones were that these were compared to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1030688.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pershore Abbey church was closed to visitors...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1030679.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...but the door was open.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We popped our camera far enough in to take a photo of the inside of the tower.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1030684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tom Harvey's chainsaw carving on a tree stump in the Abbey grounds. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1030675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Flying buttress&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 13th Century the monks from Evesham Abbey had a manual cable ferry to take them across the River Avon to tend their vineyard on the opposite bank in Hampton. There is a still pedestrian ferry in the same location, operated by pulling along a cable strung across the river, which is allowed to drop to the bottom when the ferry is at either bank, to allow passage of boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony remembered that he would need to sound his horn to alert the ferryman but there was no sign of anyone, the ferry was moored and the cable was already lowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We attempted to moor at the first pontoon in Evesham but the flood-safe pillars, standing beyond the pontoon, were bigger than our fenders and rendered them useless, so we moved on to the main town moorings alongside the park, which were lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20200930-P1030690.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle  heading into one of the locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1350061cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Evesham Abbey Gardens has it's own landing stage opposite our moorings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out the lovely Evesham and the remains of its Abbey, the outline of which is carefully picked out in paving slabs in the grounds, which is now a public park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on to Bidford where we also had a quick look around. We had picked up our pace because the forecast was for heavy rain over the next few days. This would inevitably raise the water level in the river and we were concerned that it would become un-navigable and we would be stranded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we had an early start in the rain leaving Bidford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030712.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A representation of the Evesham swineherd seeing a vision of the Virgin Mary, which prompted the building of the Abbey in 701 AD.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030716.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Evesham has many interesting historical buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030719.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Churches used by the population of Evesham not permitted to worship in the Abbey itself.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030732.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Medieval stocks but a modern roof.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Shame - we thought the Evesham people were just very nice to their criminals.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030721.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The remains of the Chapter House archway.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201001-P1030720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The belltower, the only part of Evesham Abbey still complete.
&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On rivers, as you approach a lock, the navigation divides in two, one arm going to the lock and the other towards the weir, or, in the case of the Avon, the rapids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the river divides around an island and either one route is navigable or they both are. Large arrows direct the boats to the navigable route, (some of them large enough to see in time without binoculars, which is helpful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were travelling along in the rain, we found ourselves with a set of rapids straight in front of us, with the water flowing quite strongly. I would have panicked if I hadn't been struck dumb and rigid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;We must have come the wrong way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Had there been a choice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding my voice I queried this with Tony. He couldn't remember there being a choice....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;thoughtbubble&quot;&gt;Would there be enough space to turn in front of the rapids without hitting any rocks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water looked fairly furious.... My chest felt quite tight... Why is this happening with Mum on board? We were still moving forward...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly there was a sharp right turn into a lock. Wow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We soon found ourselves at the Stratford-on-Avon lock, leading onto the canal. By this time, despite being very glad to be alive and afloat, we were a bit fed up of the rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not realising that the lock landing was well before the lock, where the trip boat was moored, we had passed it by and found ourselves in front of the lock with no way for me to get off and open it. Tony managed to turn Liberty Belle, despite the wind, and we went back the way we had come. Tony turned again, pulled over behind the trip boat to let me off and waited mid-stream for me to set the lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I approached I could see it was set against us with the canal-end lock gates wide open. At the river-end of the lock the only way of crossing to the other side was to use the elaborate bridge with curled ramps at both ends. I pulled closed the canal-side gate on my side and set off across the  over-lengthy bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I got to the other gate, the first gate had swung open again. I closed the second gate, walked to the river-end and opened the gate paddle a little, to start letting the water out, assuming that would pull the gate closed. Off again, over the bridge to shut the first gate. By this time, the first gate was open again.. Hurrumph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the river-side gates and opened the other paddle fully, letting the water gush out which held the first gate whilst I went over the bridge, again, and pulled closed the second gate. At last! I fully opened the first paddle and we were finally in business. All this time Tony had seen me pottering back and forth over the bridge with no obvious results...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last, Liberty Belle was through the lock and we were moored in the basin, in dry clothes, watching the rain through the windows. We decided that we would bring the hire car booking forward by a couple of days, rather than sit in Stratford in the rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we moved Liberty Belle to a 14 day mooring outside the basin and drove Mary home. The good weather was over and the temperature was dropping, so Mary had seen the best of the autumn. It would be no fun if she was sheltering from the rain and cold in a boat with steamed up windows! Besides, we had kidnapped her for 4 weeks...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out to have been a good decision to crack on with our journey because the rivers did go into flood and no-one was allowed to travel on them for a few days. Well done Tony!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/20201002-P1350087.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pushing through all the swans towards Stratford.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n89/IMG_20201003_084734855_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stratford-on-Avon basin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir John Betjeman wrote a poem to commemorate the opening of the Avon Navigation in Stratford by Queen Elizabeth the Queen Mother in 1974.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Inland Waterway&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;He who by peaceful inland waterways steers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Bestirs himself when a new lock appears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Slow swing the gate: slow sinks the water down;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;The lower Stratford seems another town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;The meadows which the youthful Shakespeare knew&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Are left behind, and, sliding into view,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Come reaches of the Avon, mile on mile,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Church, farm and mill and lover-leaned-on stile,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Till where the tower of Tewkesbury soars to heaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Our homely Avon joins the haughty Severn,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Sweet is the fluting of the blackbird’s note,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Sweet is the ripple from the narrow boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Your Majesty, our friend of many years,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;Confirms a triumph now the moment nears:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;The lock you have re-opened will set free&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;The heart of England to the sea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we have abandoned the Caldon Canal, (which is absolutely delightful, even in the rain), and are now heading for a mooring suitable for a lockdown.

&lt;p&gt;After some investigation we decided that the mooring outside Westport Lake, between Stoke-on-Trent and the Harecastle tunnel, would suit us just nicely. When we passed by last time we thought it would be a pleasant place to stay. There are mooring rings, boaters' facilities, (including showers), nearby shops, access to countryside walks and birdwatching possiblilites at the lake. Strangely there doesn't seem to be a water tap, but there is one a short boat ride away, outside the tunnel, and a boatyard in the opposite direction, as well as a winding hole in both directions for turning.

&lt;p&gt;Tony walked up there today from our overnight mooring and confirmed that there is a lot of space, so we will hopefully be moored there tomorrow afternoon, in plenty of time for the new lockdown.

&lt;p&gt;Good luck everyone, stay safe. xx
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Gloucester to Stratford-on-Avon 28th September - 3rd October 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Down Memory Lane and onto the Severn</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/21/down-memory-lane-and-onto-the-severn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Down Memory Lane and onto the Severn" /><published>2020-10-21T16:57:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-21T16:57:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/21/down-memory-lane-and-onto-the-severn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/21/down-memory-lane-and-onto-the-severn.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Black Country Museum to Gloucester (via Sharpness)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19th - 27th September 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n88map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Correction:-&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last newsletter there was a photo of Mary posing next to a WAAF poster. I incorrectly stated that Mary was in the WAAF but, of course she was in the WRAF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A silly mistake for me to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WAAF is the Women's Auxilliary Air Force, set up to support the RAF men, whereas the WRAF  was the Women's Royal Air Force, the women's equivalent to the RAF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it goes without saying, that this was during the Cold War, not WWII...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340816.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Gloucester and Sharpness Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving the museum we set off through Netherton Tunnel, past the Merry Hell shopping centre and down the pretty Delph Lock flight to Brierley Hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary used to attend the Grammar School in Brierley Hill. It was right next to the canal, which for her, back then, was just the source of the mist that obscured the playground. Sadly, we passed the grammar without realising it -  now a primary school - and the town itself was disappointingly 'down at heel'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200919-P1340365.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This indicates that an anchor making industry used to be here. One of Mary's Grandfather's was an anchor maker...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200919-P1340364.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....her other Grandfather was a chain maker.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200919-P1340323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle's crew working the locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200919-P1030369.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Dudley No.2 Canal joins Dudley No.1.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200919-P1030379.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sliding into a mooring space between the last two Delph locks at Brierley Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200919-P1340389.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our very pretty mooring at Brierley Hill proved to be the best bit of the town as far as we could see.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued down memory lane past Stourbridge, through Stewponey, (which wasn't as interesting to look at as it sounds), to Kinver, (where Mary grew up), and on to Kidderminster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The canal around here is absolutely beautiful. Tony and I have promised ourselves that we will re-visit over the winter to have a jolly good look around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we arrived in Stourport-on-Severn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1030389.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Golly.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Aggressive mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1340397.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Red House Cone, used in making Stuart Glass, as seen from the top of the Stourbridge Locks&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1030395.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A lovely fish sculpture tops this canalside sign post in Wordsley&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1030405.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading for Stourport.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1030406.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A beautiful circular weir.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1340411.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A tunnel cut through the distinctive red sand stone rock of this area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200920-P1030421.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The delightful front gate of a lock side cottage.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200921-P1340441.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Alongside one of the locks was this cave, dug out of the rock by the navvies that built the canal as a shelter from the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200921-P1030429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What a lovely design for the canal society badge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200921-P1030436.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A post marking the county border.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle is in Staffordshire and I am in Worcestershire.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200921-P1030446.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kidderminster.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200921-P1030457.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Contrasting bridges.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1340495.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The dry dock in Stourport Basin where boaters can paint their boat...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1340496.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and add its name to the lists around the sides.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary had started a pattern of walking alongside the boat on the towpath first thing in the morning, helping with the pushing and pulling of lock gates and then sitting at the front of the boat in the sunshine to admire the views. We now had the River Severn ahead of us, which would be a different kettle of fish, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The land alongside rivers is generally privately owned so there isn't necessarily a tow path; the edges of the river do not necessarily allow the boat to approach close enough for crew to get on or off because of rocks, shallow water or deep vegetation; if a path does exist it often wanders away from the river and may not return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these factors mean that walking alongside the boat for exercise is not an option so Mary was a bit more confined to the boat but we tried to make up for it by having a little walk around the places where we were moored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1340519.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Out on the River Severn.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1340528.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Worcester Cathedral as seen from the river.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1340583.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Working barges; one loaded up and low in the water, the other on its return journey, light and riding high.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another difference between canals and rivers is that you cannot necessarily moor on a river just because it is lunch time. On our first day on the Severn we resigned ourselves to a sandwich on the go on the understanding that we had fish and chips when we arrived in Upton-upon-Severn. It is a very pretty little town which takes great pride in its public places and also sells great fish suppers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1030463.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored in Upton-upon-Severn&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200922-P1030471.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Upton church of St.Peter and St. Paul, made from the insides of Crunchy Bars.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340589.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Upton-upon-Severn, showing the 'Pepperpot', the tower which is all that remains of its old parish church. Now a tourist information and heritage centre.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340610.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A change in the weather...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the River Severn travels South, before joining the Gloucester and Sharpness Canal, there is a section that is tidal, called The Partings. Boaters must contact the lock keeper ahead to check that passage is safe before taking a deep breath and holding it until safely on the canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing we had a lot ahead of us before we reached the safety of moorings in Gloucester, we set off, despite the rain, just like Doctor Foster before us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it was raining, the wildlife were still out and about of course, and I was lucky enough to see a pair of Lesser Spotted Woodpeckers fly across our path and land on the trunk of a tree alongside the river. I was so chuffed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the last lock before The Partings, (Upper Lode Lock), the keeper asked us if it was our first time on this part of the river. Having said it was, he bombarded us with information and lowered a damp leaflet of instructions down to Tony by way of a bucket on a rope. If we weren't worried before, we were now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He suggested we stop at some visitor moorings on a particular pontoon for an hour, to make our timings right. We should contact the next lock from there, to check that it was safe to continue, as there were reports of some debris on the tidal section, which may or may not allow us to pass an oncoming boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having our eyes peeled for visitor moorings, we didn't identify them until we had gone past them...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony phoned ahead and was told that all was well, we should continue to the lock which would be open as there was a boat just leaving, which we would see on the way. There was a large branch in the water but there would be plenty of room. The second lock keepers calm, easy going attitude was reassuring and he was quite right, there was nothing to worry about and we soon found ourselves safely in Gloucester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340635.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sliding past the large branch.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340640.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Nearly there...!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340653.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;&quot;STONG TIDAL CURRENTS&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;MOOR HERE ONLY WHEN&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;WAITING FOR THE LOCK&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;USE STERN ROPE FIRST&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;stern orders!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340658.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Safely in Gloucester Lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of us had ever been to Gloucester and had no particular expectations, so we were delighted to find a fine and interesting historic town. The docks reminded me of a small Liverpool, with the buildings beautifully preserved and well presented with plenty of information boards and a friendly, relaxed atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1340670.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored in Gloucester Docks&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200923-P1030478.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Gloucester's Mariners Church in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to visit the Cathedral the following morning, then Mary treated us to lunch in the Cathedral Cafe. Tony found some online guided walks highlighting places of interest and including information and anecdotes, so we were kept busy in the afternoon exploring the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goodness there have been a lot of monks here, Blackfriars, Whitefriars and Greyfriars to name a few, plus the oddly named Llanthony Secunda Priory, housing Augustinian Canons who came to Gloucester when they were being persecuted in Wales, then refused to return when told it was safe to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffice to say, we didn't do it justice, so will need to return sometime in the future (probably not by boat).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1030481.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Gloucester Cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Originally part of a Benedictine Monastry&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/IMG_20200924_112043744.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Monks' Lavatorium is absolutely stunning.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1030483.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This gargoyle looked particularly impressive in the rain...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/IMG_20200924_111838591.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A modern mason's mark in the repair work on the Cathedral&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1030503.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Blackfriars&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1030500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Whitefriars&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1030498.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Gloucester's old grammar school building.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1030485.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The New Inn, a medieval galleried, courtyard inn, which is far from new.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200924-P1340673.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I think a boat a bit bigger than Liberty Belle was expected...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/IMG-20200924-WA0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A decommissioned lighthouse ship, in Gloucester Docks, soon to become a floating B&amp;amp;B.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200927-P1030574.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Llanthony Secunda Priory&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200925-P1340678.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The lift bridge in Gloucester Docks rising just for us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, off again, along the Gloucester and Sharpness Canal, from Gloucester to.....Sharpness!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gloucester and Sharpness Canal runs alongside the River Severn, with the Cotswold hills on one side and the Monmouthshire hills on the other. We took a couple of days to get to Sharpness, stopping at Frampton-on-Severn on the way. The weather did us proud again and the views were stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200925-P1030524.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;9 Miles from Gloucester&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;7 Miles to Sharpness.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200925-P1030522.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Walking in Frampton-on-Severn, cow herding as we go!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200925-P1340717.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stunning views, left...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340780.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and right.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200925-P1340706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;51&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We didn't need to have this swing bridge moved for little ol' us!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200925-P1340765.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;52&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sneaking past the canons...!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;53&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old Cadbury Wharf.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no locks on this canal but many swing bridges, some electronic and others manual, each operated by a friendly keeper waiting in a little office alongside. Every swing bridge has associated traffic lights which initially show red, then flash when the keeper has spotted you, finally turning green when you are invited to continue your journey. So civilised!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340789.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bridge keeper, hand turning the swing bridge mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340804.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;55&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The old bridge keepers cottages on the canal have a certain style.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340851.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;56&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The remains of the centre of the old railway swing bridge across the canal. The railway bridge extended to coal mines on the opposite side of the river.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340870.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;57&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A model of the railway swing bridge which, for safety reasons, doesn't swing.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh, the disappointment!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned outside the docks and moored in the visitor moorings alongside the tidal River Severn. We had a little look around near our moorings, remembering to wave to Cathy in Bristol as we did so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day we headed back the way we had come, all the way to Gloucester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340862.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;58&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning in front of Sharpness Docks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340885.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;59&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking down river towards Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340892.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Jubilee Sailing Trust's SV Tenacious, docked in Sharpness.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A training vessel with wheelchair access throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1340868.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;61&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from our mooring space across the River Severn.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1030547.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;62&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the Purton Hulks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A collection of old vessels deliberately breached between the River Severn and the Gloucester &amp;amp; Sharpness Canal to prevent erosion.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1030548.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;63&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wooden, steel and concrete vessels, some completely hidden under the silt, others much more obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ingenious solution to a problem and now a unique historic record.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1030561.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;64&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Purton's Church of St John the Evangelist.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200926-P1030564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;65&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We were even allowed inside.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200927-P1340918.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;66&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony's heart sinks. The trickiest people to share the water with are skullers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Luckily these turned out to be the sort that check over their shoulders occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n88/20200927-P1340902.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;67&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing a little extension to the canal, a timber pond, where timber that arrived in the docks was taken and left floating to stop it drying out and cracking before it was moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;The Severn Railway Bridge, which included a swing bridge across the Gloucester and Sharpness Canal, was built to transport coal over the river to Sharpness. Several boats collided with the pillars supporting the bridge, due to the difficulty of steering in the tidal section of the river, but there was one particularly huge disaster in 1960 which finally resulted in the demolition.

&lt;p&gt;Two tankers, (one carrying oil, the other coal), heading for Sharpness Dock, missed the entrance in the thick fog and found themselves fighting the incoming tide, unable to turn back. They both crashed into the railway bridge, damaging themselves, the bridge, and a gas main. The leaking oil ignited, setting the river ablaze; the gas main exploded and the tanker carrying coal caught alight, much extending the life of the fire. Five men died in the tragedy.

&lt;p&gt;Reconstruction of the bridge was attempted but was abandoned due to costs and it was finally demolished in 1967.

&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Black Country Museum to Gloucester (via Sharpness) 19th - 27th September 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Richard III (again) to WWII</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/18/from-richard-III-again-to-WWIIthis-is-the-title.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Richard III (again) to WWII" /><published>2020-10-18T19:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-18T19:50:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/18/from-richard-III-again-to-WWIIthis-is-the-title</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/18/from-richard-III-again-to-WWIIthis-is-the-title.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Coventry to Birmingham&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8th - 18th September 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n87map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200912-P1030243.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pretty Ashby Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There we were in Coventry Basin, all packed up to go, with a hire car booked to take us to fetch Mary. Tony set off on foot to collect the car from the nearest Enterprise office, as arranged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He arrived to find the building closed and no-one about. Curious. He contacted Enterprise and it turned out that they had given him the location of an office that was not in operation. They sent him a taxi which took him to the correct location. Here he was given the car and he drove back to the boat. All this took rather longer than we had expected and was a stressful start to the journey, but all was well in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had hoped to take Mary onto the Ashby canal but it was lacking in water, so we had changed our plans and were going to circle through Birmingham, join the River Severn and then the Avon, returning to Birmingham via Stratford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evening before we set off, with Mary on board, we received an email from the CRT to say that the Ashby Canal was now replenished. Excellent. So we went back to our original plan, (or rather, attached our original plan onto the front of our new plan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off we went, back along the Coventry Canal, past Hawkesbury Junction and on to Marston Junction where we got ready to turn under the bridge and onto the Ashby. Inevitably we had a boat close behind us and we met a boat coming off the Ashby towards us under the bridge. Not just any boat but a very long one which had trouble turning. Eventually after a bit of boat ballet (?) all was sorted out and each of the three boats managed to end up where it had intended to be and facing the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200908-P1340062.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning onto the Ashby-de-la-Zouch Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200908-P1340061cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the junction,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;0 miles completed, 30 to go.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We immediately liked the Ashby; following the contours of the land gives it a winding nature and with no locks at all to keep us busy, it has a sedate air. The weather did us proud and we were able to admire it at its best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent several days travelling on this stretch of canal, stopping off at;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stoke Golding, where King Henry VII was crowned after defeating Richard III at the battle of Bosworth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Market Bosworth, a pretty, small town. Mary, having been before, was able to show us around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snarestone, where Mary made full use of the children's play area...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shackerstone, the end of the line for us as the canal is no longer navigable beyond here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200909-P1030171.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A place obsessed with the crowning of King Henry VII&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200909-P1030160.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;CROWN HILL Near this spot following the Battle of Bosworth KING HENRY VII was crowned and thus began the Tudor Dynasty on 22nd August 1485&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200909-P1030167.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. Margaret of Antioch church, Stoke Golding, where in 1485 the villagers watched the Battle of Bosworth from the battlements.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200909-P1030165.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Before the battle, swords were sharpened on the church window ledge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Vandals.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200909-P1030150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A friendly visitor.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200910-P1030174.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Keep walking, nearly there!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200910_085745422_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beyond the boats is the site of the Battle of Bosworth.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200910_133226737.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Market Bosworth. Pretty market town which takes delight in it's window boxes and hanging baskets...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200910_135044860_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....planting up whatever is to hand.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200911_103435703_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here and in the surrounding area, headstones are made of slate. The engravings remain clear far longer than with other commonly used stone.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200911-P1030217.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We tried to get closer to Shackerstone Motte and Bailey Castle on foot, but this was as good as it got.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200911-P1340081.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Snarestone Wharf. The end of the navigable Ashby Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were a little disappointed at the lack of wildlife on the Ashby, specifically kingfishers and heron. We wondered whether there was a lack of fish or maybe suitable breeding areas but came to no conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on our last day we were in for a special treat. Having turned around at the top end and headed back, we were moored for the night not far from the junction. We arose the next morning and were surprised to see, on the opposite side of the canal, a water vole, collecting and enjoying his breakfast whilst we enjoyed ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a delight it was to see him busying about in plain sight. We were thrilled. For us the Ashby Canal will forever be associated with this little chap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200912-P1030235.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Time to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200913-P1340135cropped2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hello Ratty!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned off the Ashby and back onto the Coventry Canal, this time heading North. We moored at Atherstone over night where we had a little look around and did a bit of shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200914_091713317.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The chimney behind is much older than these 'modern' frontages.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200914_095146182_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A monument to the Atherstone medieval Shrove Tuesday ball game.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The person holding the ball when the whistle blows (after 2 hours), wins.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The game must remain in Long Street and no-one is allowed to kill anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Polesworth onwards, the canal was rather lovely, helped of course by the glorious weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peace was broken by a woman working in her garden alongside her moored boat who yelled at Tony, who was gently chugging along at a suitable slow speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Where's the fire???!!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what she wanted him to do. He could have stopped the engine I suppose but steering isn't going to work then and we would still be there. The alternative would be to reverse but what would that have achieved? Boaters can be a funny lot.....
Tony didn't bother to respond. It seemed pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing along we swung southwards through Fazeley Junction onto the Birmingham and Fazeley. Last time we did this turning, many hands got involved towing and shoving Liberty Belle around the sharp corner. We braced ourselves for the repeat performance but, strangely, it all happened very smoothly.... What a difference a couple of years' experience makes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1340165cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh, North, please.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1340161.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fazeley Junction&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onwards, avoiding Spaghetti Junction with another sharp turn at Salford junction, (Tony has definitely got the hang of this), onto the old Birmingham and Warwick. We moored for the night outside Star City, behind a couple of other boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that evening a hire boat arrived in the dark. Poor devils. It's quite stressful to still be travelling along after night has fallen, hoping to find a mooring before the next lock... The narrow boat in front of us were quick to respond and moored them up alongside, tying the newcomer up to their own boat. So kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1340181.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sharp left.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1340186.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing under the M6 and over a little river.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1030263.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bridge built as part of the Drayton Manor Estate by architect Robert Smirke, pioneer of concrete foundations and responsible for the facade of the British Museum.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1030271cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The estate house has gone, replaced by a theme park that Mary's little sister frequented.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1340176.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I wonder if anyone ever waits for a bus here...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200915-P1030274cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I'm not sure why but I felt obliged to stand here.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we were hoping to set off early and get started on the locks ahead. We were initially a little disappointed that the boat in front of us, having swapped places with the hire boat, set off before us. This meant of course that the locks would definitely be set against us. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hadn't factored in how kind the two couples on board had already proved to be. As they left each lock they closed it up and left a crew member to open one of the paddles to start emptying it for us. Wonderful. This made the whole process so much easier for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 5 locks we parted ways at the junction; they joined the Grand Onion and we headed off for the Digbeth Branch with a little diversion into Typhoo Basin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1030295.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony spotted this delightful bit of artwork on the Digbeth Branch.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1340220.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Keeping out the pesky gongoozlers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1340218.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Anyone for a brew, in Typhoo?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1340224.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Don't mind if I do!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brought us back to rejoin the Birmingham and Fazeley. Only 13 more locks and we would be in the city centre. Mum helped with the steep climb, pushing and pulling lock gates. I went on ahead to set the next lock where I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half way up, I was just operating a paddle to empty a lock for us and a chap on a bike stopped and remarked that it was a shame 'he' was making me do all the hard work. I pointed down to the previous lock, indicating Mary and said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;What about my Mother?&quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Oh my god, that's sooo much worse!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1340259.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Flight of locks up into the city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1340266cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary working the locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1030321.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Outside Itihaas. An excellent restaurant. Julia's favourite.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200916-P1030323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An unstable wall is being held back by what looks like Duplo bricks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Birmingham! Hurrah! Although, in these strange times, there isn't much you can safely do in the cities. We had a little wander around, marvelling at the reduction in the hoardings and watching the new trams in action. Mary and I tried to get into the library so that I could show her all its marvels, including the Shakespeare room, but it wasn't to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approached the door a masked face appeared through a small gap and asked us what we wanted. I explained but apparently you have to have some specific and important library sanctioned task before you can be admitted to limited areas....blah, blah, blah.... so we shrugged off the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200917-P1340270.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The boat roundabout in the centre of Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200917_095233852.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Birmingham's new trams.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200917_102052010_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary at the Bull Ring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200917_102845752_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The monument to those that died in the Birmingham air raids of World War II&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having had a little look around and stocked up our larder, we left for new moorings, turning onto the Birmingham Old Main Line and travelling the few miles to the Black Country Museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200917-P1340272.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Locks up to the Birmingham Old Line canal....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200917-P1030329cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...a stretch of beautiful countryside in the city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We booked ourselves into the museum for the following day. Now, that was more like it! Such a lovely welcome! We had to stop and be chatted to by several staff members (in character) before we finally got to the office where we were able to show our annual tickets and purchase one for Mary. It appears that ours have been extended for an extra 6 months to April. How delightful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet again we spent a whole day at the museum and failed to complete it all. They keep adding new attractions! This time WWII characters were there introducing food rationing and Dig for Victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 'characters' have moved outside and many new signs have been put up to keep people at a suitable distance but we were still able to explore the buildings and, most importantly, we were able to have our fish and chips with a beer. I love this place. (It would have been a very different experience in the rain, but, yet again, we were very lucky with the weather.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200918-P1030348.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Join the WAAF?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Did that.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200918-P1030349.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;FRIED FISH&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&amp;amp; POTATOES&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;NOT Rationed.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Thank goodness!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG-20200918-WA0011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One way system explained the Black Country way!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200918-P1030339.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This lady was explaining the dangers of coal mining and making minor explosions for us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/IMG_20200918_150126410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;Can you imagine living in these cramped conditions?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well, yes, actually!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n87/20200918-P1030352.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fish and Chips!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we were moored outside the Black Country Museum, Tony went to check out the boaters facilities and somehow found himself pulling the red emergency cord in the toilet/shower room, mistaking it for the shower pull. He couldn't see how to switch it off. We all wondered how long it would take for someone to come and see who needed rescuing.....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we will never know, because Tony eventually went back and finally found a reset button. Suffice to say, no-one rushed to anyone's aid. Interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Plans:-&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are just about to start the Four Counties Ring, filling in a few bits that we have missed out so far, including the Caldon Canal. At the moment navigation of the Caldon Canal is restricted due to a sandbank having been dumped in the middle of it by the river as a result of the recent heavy rain. We are hoping that something will have been done about this before we get that far. Fingers crossed...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;
Although it was planned that the canal would go through Ashby-de-la-Zouch to the River Trent, only the first 30 miles were ever completed and only 22 miles have been restored so far.
&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Coventry to Birmingham 8th - 18th September 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Minor Tribulations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/11/minor-tribulations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Minor Tribulations" /><published>2020-10-11T21:29:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-10-11T21:29:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/11/minor-tribulations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/10/11/minor-tribulations.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Peterborough to Coventry Basin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;22nd August - 3rd September 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n86map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330891.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle as seen from Fotheringhay Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off from Peterborough in some very strong winds making it difficult to steer. Travelling up the River Nene, boats enter the locks under the guillotine style gates which are left open, so getting into the locks was relatively simple. However, once Liberty Belle was out of the other end, Tony had to control her in the strong winds, pulling over to the lock landing, waiting to collect me whilst I stayed behind to empty the lock and re-lift the guillotine gate. Then he had to somehow steer her away from the lock landing in order to set off again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one occasion I wasn't strong enough to pull the gates shut behind us so I had to abandon them. On another, there was a boat moored at the lock landing leaving no room for Liberty Belle to pull over to collect me after exiting the lock, so I had to get on before we left the lock with the gates still open. By the time we got to Fotheringhay Castle we were rather tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330875.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The River Nene has some very pretty old bridges...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330852.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and mills to admire as we pass by.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1030036.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An example of the guillotine lock operating panels.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1030029.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hoping that the guillotine gate has been well secured as Liberty Belle is steered beneath.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330892.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Castle Farm in Fotheringhay provides overnight mooring for a small fee.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330894.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;King of the Castle&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Not only Richard III's birth place but also Mary Queen of Scots' death place and Liberty Belle's mooring space.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning the wind had dropped and life should have been easier, except someone left the windlass at one of the locks. We didn't realise this until we arrived at the next one, some time later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony thought the footpath along the river might be accessible from the lock and one of us could walk back to fetch it, however, that turned out not to be so... We couldn't turn around where we were, so, using a spare windlass, we travelled through the lock to turn on the other side where there was more space, immediately re-entering the lock and travelling back the way we had come. Arriving at the previous lock, I picked up the windlass and we turned again. Thank goodness the weather was on our side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, back along the same stretch of river for the third time that morning; back past all the swimmers, kayakers and walkers that had noticed we were rather familiar. We explained ourselves several times...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1330907.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing Fotheringhay's Church.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1330902.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Before our Middle Levels experience, we would have thought this bridge was low.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we arrived outside the pub in Wadenhoe. Tony decided that, although black clouds had gathered, it wasn't going to rain, and off he went to the bar. I was a little behind him and by the time I was ready to join him the rain was coming down in sheets. I took our large umbrella with me but the rain seemed to bypass that and attack me from all sides and from underneath. I was soaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sloshed my way into the bar which was surprisingly busy, so we stood waiting for the rain to subside a bit before going into the garden. We positioned two chairs together under the umbrella, wiped the seats down and settled in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the recommendation of the landlord, we later went to look around the tiny but fascinating village before settling down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG_20200823_153640246.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A pint in the rain.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1030017.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wadenhoe Church&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1020994.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wadenhoe Village...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1020995.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...owned by the Wadenhoe Trust.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1020997.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wadenhoe's fabulous dovecote where pigeons were bred for shooting.&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200823-P1030005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the dovecote there is a swinging ladder that gives access to each of the 650 nesting boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off again. Surely today will be trouble free. Well, not entirely. At one of the locks the electrically operated guillotine gate was out of order and needed to be operated manually. In these situations a large wheel is provided with some mechanism for stopping it from unwinding on its own. In this case it was a chain which is padlocked to a ring welded onto the wheel. The padlock is opened using a key provided for such things. In this particular case we could open the padlock and close it again but could not remove our key afterwards. As the key would be needed many times again over the next few days, this was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to wedge the windlass into the mechanism to hold the wheel temporarily and Tony contacted the River Agency who suggested we do our best. I was worried that we would break the key in the lock. Eventually I managed to remove it but this left the padlock in the locked position, not attached to the wheel. This meant the guillotine couldn't be locked in the raised position, as it should be. After much struggling and some WD40 we finally had a lifted gate, a secured wheel and a separate key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1030031.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The windlass jamming the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Note the broken electric motor flung on the ground beneath)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were all small complications and certainly didn't prevent us from appreciating our surroundings and the wildlife around us. We saw plenty of kingfishers darting around which are always delight. One of the several cormorants we saw was in the river ahead of Liberty Belle, wrestling with a very large fish which it finally subdued and swallowed before it noticed us bearing down on him and flew off. We also spotted some goosanders, which are a rare treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reaching Irthlingborough we found a mooring opposite a nature reserve and were delighted to discover that it was home to several Great Egrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A rare sighting of a Water Unicorn.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200822-P1330855cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of a pair of Goosanders.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1330931cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I tried to photograph the cormorant with his fish.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The fish is inside the cormorant.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1330936cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the egrets.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed moored in Irthlingborough to sit out storm Francis' strong winds, which made it difficult to stand upright, let alone steer a boat. Another narrow boat was moored nearby and the two skippers discussed their plans for the next few days whilst observing the rising water levels. (11 inches and counting...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following our neighbours' example we went to the local nature reserve, 'Stanwick Lakes', for a take away coffee. We arrived just in time before they closed up due to the strong winds. Being careful not to have the cups blown out of our hands and certainly not daring to take the lids off, we sat down at picnic tables near each other and sipped our drinks through the tiny little holes in the lids.....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both boats were heading to Norton, so we hatched a plan to travel together to make life easier at the locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, back at the boat, Tony and I were unaware that our bow rope was slipping free. Our neighbour, Jim, left the safety of his boat and came to rescue us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus began the Liberty Belle and Barney partnership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG_20200824_163830_435.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Painting the edges of the deckboard covers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1030060.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Irthlingborough Church.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1030051.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Crazy spider gargoyle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200824-P1030049.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I'm not sure that this chap was the artist's first choice of model.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG_20200825_153522085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stanwick Lakes has some special residents...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG_20200825_154120376_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and all kinds of sculptures.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the following day, storm Francis having blown himself out, we set off in convoy, sharing the work all the way to Norton.
We moored overnight together at Hardwater Mill and then Becket's Park in Northampton (where we stayed for a day because the weather forecast wasn't good). We continued our partnership the following day but temporarily lost Barney just before we moored up for the night at Weedon Bec (where we snuck out for a curry, which seems to have become a tradition of ours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG-20200828-WA0003cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A warning to people entering Northampton.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200829-P1330959.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A big employer in Northampton, Carlsberg, gives the town a malty flavour.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200829-P1330964.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Northampton's lift-shaft tower, for testing lifts. Now a grade II listed building.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200830-P1030081cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Weedon Bec's village sign. Strangely the 'Brinjol' restaurant isn't featured.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200830-P1030089.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A now isolated arm of the canal at Weedon Bec went to the Royal Ordnance Depot which supplied arms to the Napoleonic Wars and was decommissioned in 1984.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200830-P1030093.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the many fabulous buildings at the depot is now a micro brewery...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;History AND beer!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rejoined forces with Barney in the morning for the last leg into Norton Junction, where we moored up and went with Jim and Margaret to the nearby pub for a pint or two to say our goodbyes. It was sad to break up the 'dream team' but we now had to go our separate ways; Barney to his marina and Liberty Belle to Braunston, where she had an appointment with a man who was going to replace her domestic batteries. (We had been warned when we bought Liberty Belle that her batteries were rather tired but we had soldiered on until now.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200831-P1330985.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Braunston Tunnel&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200901-P1030102.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Braunston's converted windmill.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Invited guests are requested to bring their own ladder. Unwelcome guests may leave without!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A fine example of a &quot;Mother-in-Law's exit&quot; popular in the days when Les Dawson was funy (When was that?).&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst in Braunston we helped the local economy by having second breakfast at the Gongoozlers' Cafe two days in a row, buying several plumbing bits from the chandlers, (see the radiator story from the last newsletter), and filling the fridge full of Braunston Bangers. In between all the eating, Tony re-tiled the fireplace, again. (It has become an annual event).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG-20200831-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Second breakfast at the Gongoozler Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Day 1&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/IMG_20200901_110210006_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Day 2.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200902-P1030110.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle's battery surgery is under way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200902-P1330991.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bye bye Braunston.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our new domestic batteries had been fitted, we set off for Coventry, via Rugby. The weather was rather wet but not unpleasantly so and we arrived to find the ideal mooring in Coventry Basin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200903-P1030124.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Off she goes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200903-P1030132.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What? Why?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200903-P1340016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We've got ourselves a convoy...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200903-P1340025.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The distinctive outline of the Coventry Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200903-P1340048.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Back in Coventry Basin, almost 2 years after our last visit.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n86/20200903-P1030146.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We went to look at the back of the Weavers houses.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Originally built by a Quaker to enable individual weavers to compete with factory workers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan was to collect a hire car, load it up with our washing, and leave Liberty Belle for a few days whilst we popped back to the house and collected Mary for a cruising holiday with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Medieval era Dovecotes were owned by manor houses or monasteries. Over the centuries other more lowly people were allowed to have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pigeons were free to leave through vents in the roof. Nothing was wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feathers were used to stuff bedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The droppings were used not just as fertiliser and saltpetre for gunpowder but also to treat baldness, gout and tumours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each pair of pigeons produced 2 offspring 8-10 times a year for 7 years. The chicks, or squabs, were collected when a few weeks old and roasted on spits, pickled, fried, stewed, braised, used in pies, dumplings, fritters and 'pigeon in a hole'. They were not only versatile and nutritious but also prevented plaque and other diseases (?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, this appeals to Tony and he has threatened to build one in the garden as soon as we return to the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Peterborough to Coventry Basin 22nd August - 3rd September 2020</summary></entry></feed>