<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-03T15:11:26+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Liberty Belle Newsletter</title><subtitle>A day-by-day account of our time aboard the Liberty Belle narrowboat.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ware Next? Yep, then Hertford</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/25/ware-next-yep-then-hertford.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ware Next? Yep, then Hertford" /><published>2020-03-25T19:28:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T19:28:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/25/ware-next-yep-then-hertford</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/25/ware-next-yep-then-hertford.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Paddington to Hertford&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18th - 25th February 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n72map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290713.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bye, bye Merchants Square.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Joe, Kirsty and Carter on board, we left Paddington Basin behind, ready for the next part of our adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When our guests had joined us a few days before they had left their van in Hertford at the end of the Lee Navigation, so we spent the next few days travelling there, with the wind and rain trying hard to put us off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as we had set off, Tony realised there was something missing from the top of the boat. Our gang plank!
Initially we thought it had been stolen but we eventually concluded that Storm Dennis was probably the culprit. Very annoying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290710.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the fuel boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290716.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the restaurant boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290726.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle's equipment rack with a boat hook and a barge pole but no gang plank!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290749.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Things could be worse...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned onto the Regents Canal and were hoping to have a visit from John and Melissa on the way but it rained so heavily that they got soaked and sadly had to abandon the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290719.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the Puppet Theatre boat in Little Venice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290725.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the zoo.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290729.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the Chinese restaurant boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290746.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the bookshop boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290743.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Past the towering cranes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290759.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Through Islington tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290780.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Out of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290795.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A floating garden complete with greenhouse.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG-20200219-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This was very tempting but we didn't have time to stop on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maybe on the way back? &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;ref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of the week, Joe was working from the boat but on the Thursday, he went by train into the office in London. The rest of us moved Liberty Belle from railway station to railway station and let him know where to find us at the end of the day...!
We travelled some of the way with a boat called Lucky No.7, also braving the weather. The boat has a permanent mooring on the river but seems to travel about a lot. The skipper has a friendly dog, who, whenever she got the chance, tried to board our boat.
When we arrived at their home mooring, they turned off and we went through the next lock on our own. As we were waiting in the lock, Lucky No.7's dog suddenly sprang into action, left her boat while the skipper was mooring and hurtled over the bridge, joining a couple taking their dog for a walk. The two dogs were obviously very pleased to see each other. The couple turned back and, returning the dog to her owner, explained to me that the dogs were from the same litter. Apparently, when the sister dog from Lucky No.7 leaves the mooring, the brother dog spends each day staring up the canal in the direction they went. Whenever they return there is a dramatic re-union! How sweet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lee Navigation follows the River Lee (or Lea - the jury is still out), and the mooring opportunities are few and far between. Not having a gang plank reduced our options further. As we got closer to Hertford we began to worry that there wouldn't be a space there for us....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290803.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle's extra crew members walking the towpath which was suddenly diverted. We didn't see them again until the next lock...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/P1290808.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ware riverside gazebos. Where? Ware...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before Hertford, we met a CRT engineer who was just moving one of their boats through a lock. He then helped us through too and reassured us that there were a couple of spaces in Hertford, one where his boat had been moored the day before and another recently vacated one, so we should be fine. Sure enough, we did find a lovely mooring alongside some allotments, a short distance from the town and the supermarket. It wasn't very close to Joe's van but was very near to a car park, and he was able to move there before unloading all his gear from Liberty Belle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They left us on the Saturday morning to get to Bursledon just in time for puppy training classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200222_124539427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hertford's old McMullen Brewery Buildings. McMullen are still brewing in Hertford but now have modern premises.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200223_155940249_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hertford's castle dates back to the year 911. It has been much modified over the years. All that remains are a mound, some walls and this gatehouse.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200223_081850693.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Green Dragon Hotel Vaults.  &lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;ref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200223_161534925.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;15th Century Verger's House, painted a fetching shade of orange.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200223_161445976_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. Andrew's Church, Hertford.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200223_160820307.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Serene carved lady's head with a lace collar and string of pearls.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We explored Hertford and decided that we really like the small town and were happy to leave Liberty Belle moored there whilst we went back to the house for a short visit. This trip home was for a sad occasion. Our dear friend, Trixie, who had been our next-door neighbour for 25 years, had sadly passed away. We went to join her family and friends at her funeral service. So sad. She will be missed by so many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200225_092657834_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hertford East railway station. A very short distance from our mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n72/IMG_20200225_092225643_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Metro. News, Sudoko, crossword and bottom insulation.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Footnotes:-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;Tony’s Noted Pie &amp;amp; Mash (noted by Tony). We weren’t to know at the time that all restaurants would be closed by the time we passed here again.&lt;a href=&quot;#ref1&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fn2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt; Hertford Vaults. The sign, raised lettering on terracotta, reads:-&lt;a href=&quot;#ref2&quot; title=&quot;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text.&quot;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;GREEN DRAGON HOTEL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;CATERING FOR LARGE &amp;amp; SMALL PARTIES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;ACCOMMODATION FOR MOTORISTS &amp;amp; CYCLISTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;GOOD STABLING &amp;amp; MOTOR PIT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;MCMULLEN &amp;amp; SONS LTD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;WINE &amp;amp; SPIRIT MERCHANTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;PROPRIETORS OF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;BONDED VAULTS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;signtranscript&quot;&gt;OFFICES MILL BRIDGE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, when Tony and I discussed our adventures we had, to my relief, decided against taking Liberty Belle onto the tidal section of the Thames, from Limehouse to Teddington. On investigation Tony had discovered that we needed a VHF radio and someone who was trained to use it, so I was relaxed in the knowledge that this wasn't going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before we went back to the house, however, Tony found a VHF training course in Southampton going cheap for last minute bookings. He booked and paid for the course which was scheduled for the day after our arrival. Of course he passed with full marks and managed to borrow a hand-held radio from Helen and Peter. (Thanks guys!) So, that is my fate sealed....&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Paddington to Hertford 18th - 25th February 2020 Our route</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">“Welcome to Merchants Square”</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/15/welcome-to-merchants-square.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;Welcome to Merchants Square&quot;" /><published>2020-03-15T19:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-15T19:27:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/15/welcome-to-merchants-square</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/15/welcome-to-merchants-square.html">&lt;h2&gt;Paddington Basin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11th - 17th February 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n71map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200211_144247794.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hi Paddington!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there we were, fighting Storm Dennis as we approached Paddington Basin. We had booked and paid for our mooring in advance because we had arranged to meet Joe, Kirsty and Carter there in a few days time. We were all looking forward to a bit of sight-seeing there before we explored the River Lee. As it was so windy, it was a relief to know that they were expecting us (or, as our confirmation email had stated, &quot;looking forward to seeing you&quot;), because turning around in the basin and searching for a possibly non-existent mooring space was going to be doubly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we passed the restaurant boat, 'Darcie Green', permanently moored outside Paddington station, the wind, funnelled between the buildings, became very strong and we only just missed knocking the boat as the diners watched...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The next boat to come along behind us did bump into poor Darcie and just stayed there overnight, moored against the restaurant!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on, arriving just in front of our pontoon in the Merchants Square area of Paddington Basin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no space!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what do we do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pulled over to the edge of the canal and I held onto the centre rope, whilst Tony went to investigate the pontoon situation. Storm Dennis wasn't keen on Liberty Belle staying where she was but I stood my ground!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst Tony was confirming the lack of mooring space, a security guard approached me and insisted that I move our boat. Tony returned and we both tried to explain that we had booked and payed for a mooring on the pontoon and we were not going to travel past the pontoon, turn and return the way we had come, partly because it was far too windy but mostly because we had already paid to be here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our explanation did little to stem the flow of his insistence that we move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony tied Liberty Belle to the light fittings to save my arm muscles, (which probably didn't go down too well), then went on board to contact the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust as it was far too windy outside for a phone conversation. After the usual confusion, they requested that Tony take a note of the number of each of the 6 boats on the pontoon. This he did. It didn't help much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the security guard's immediate boss, Duke, arrived and showed us a CRT mooring amongst some little hire boats which we could use. He and the original guard helped with Liberty Belle's ropes and we tied up to the temporary mooring, after promising the CRT that we would move onto the official pontoon as soon as a space became available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. Great. Agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Well, agreed, except we were not going to stay on the boat all day waiting for this to happen, we had paid to be here and we were going to make the most of it..!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all shook hands, (probably the last hand-shakes of 2020) and, with smiles all around, Duke said &quot;Welcome to Merchants Square&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/P1290707.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle giving the boats moored at the pontoon a very hard, Paddington stare.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200211_143003268_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored in amongst the hire boats.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It felt a bit like the naughty step.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So off we went for a walk along the Regents Canal. When we returned the pontoon situation was still the same so we settled down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200211_145611927.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Little Venice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200211_173406628.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Evening in Paddington Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before our 7 a.m. alarm, we were woken by a knocking noise on the boat which gradually travelled from the front of the boat to the back... What could it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the knocking got closer to the back we realised it was accompanied by a voice, asking to speak to the occupant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony stuck his head out of the hatch above our back door and spoke to the two security guards who insisted that we move the boat. Tony insisted he would not and tried to explain the situation, when he could get a word in...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually Duke arrived and sorted things out. Good grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked the pontoon situation, which hadn't changed, so off we went for a day in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our return things were still the same so we settled down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_100100842.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. John's, Hyde Park Crescent. Beautiful tiling.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_123813398.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The amazing Church of the Immaculate Conception in Mayfair.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An absolute must-see.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_124434677.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the side-chapels.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The photos, as usual, do not do it justice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_152140086.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. Paul's Church in Knightsbridge...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_151715096.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...is also worth a peek if you are there.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_131259798.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hyde Park pigeons waiting for the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_145013722.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Nag's Head in Belgravia.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;He's not a tall customer, it's just a very small pub!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200212_153709159_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony trying to get on his high horse in Belgravia.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we got up at our own speed, to find that one of the boats on the pontoon was setting off. Great. We moved Liberty Belle into the space, as promised. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were moored, one of the other boats left too, which was very lucky, because the first boat returned from collecting water to find us in his space....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kept a low profile and went into London again for more sight-seeing. As it was raining, we decided to spend the day in the Victoria and Albert Museum, one of our favourites, and broke the journey back with a visit to The Victoria, a very smart pub near Paddington.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200213_103606021_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This allotment was a surprise!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200213_103157170_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Their hens are introduced to visitors by name.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200213_164051487.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The rather lovely Victoria pub, a very pleasant place to wait for the rain to stop...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After yet another day in the same place, we were running very low on water, so Tony took our large plastic water containers on several trips to a not-so-nearby tap and topped up Liberty Belle's tank using those. Where was I when all this heavy work was taking place? In the launderette. That's important work too, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So by the time Joe, Kirsty and Carter arrived we were moored where we were supposed to be, all clean and topped up with water. They had driven to Hertford, parked the van and taken the train to Paddington, via Liverpool Street station and the underground. Quite an adventure for a puppy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200213_182124414.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our mooring at the pontoon, the official mooring that we had actually booked...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG-20200215-WA0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kirsty and Carter keeping each other entertained on the train.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of days together in London (during which Kirsty introduced me to the shopping heaven that is Whole Food Market. Oh my goodness, I haven't lived!), we set off to spend half term travelling along the Lee Navigation (in the rain) to find Joe's van.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200214_124153344_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from the OXO Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200214_135721160_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Outside the house where Wren lived whilst he supervised the building of St Paul's.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We weren't invited in...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG_20200216_131643232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In the Whole Food Market your trolley travels upstairs on its own! &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n71/IMG-20200221-WA0023.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here I am encouraging mine along.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now in Bishops Stortford waiting for Cathy to join us by train tomorrow. Our future plans are still the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck to all those who are self-isolating and those abroad who have no choice, as well as those who are waiting to see whether they are wanted at work or not. In fact, good luck to us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep each other safe and well. xx&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">Paddington Basin 11th - 17th February 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Slow Boat to London</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/13/slow-boat-to-london.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Slow Boat to London" /><published>2020-03-13T17:47:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-13T17:47:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/13/slow-boat-to-london</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/03/13/slow-boat-to-london.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Uxbridge to Greenford&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;29th January - 11th February 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n70map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290503.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cowley Lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were on our way to London along the Grand Onion. Last time we were here we had scooted past the Slough Arm, so this time we turned at the well hidden junction to explore this short, surprisingly rural, branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290515.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Over one of the Slough Arm Aqueducts.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Under the hectic M25.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290535.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We squeezed through the gap past the boatyard with a boat swinging in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290538.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This pretty, rural setting is very popular mooring, with the boats doubled up along most of the branch.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290549.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A muntjac deer watching us turn out of the Slough Arm back onto the Grand Onion.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the Grand Onion we passed through the Hanwell Locks outside the old Asylum and looked for a mooring in Brentford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290558.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oops. A bit top-heavy?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A kayak polo goal ready for action!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290569.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hanwell Asylum fire door for access to the canal water.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290574.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A slope for an embarrassed horse to escape the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time we were in Brentford, we found a mooring with its own tap, near the shower facilities, and we were hoping to do the same this time, but no luck. We ended up travelling further than we had planned but finally we saw a gap and pulled in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It soon became apparent why the space was available. There seemed to be an obstacle underwater, preventing us from getting parallel with the tow path. I stayed with Liberty Belle and Tony searched for a better mooring but the only space available was for Winter Mooring Permit holders. Oh well, beggars can't be choosers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_093652324_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Carnegie Library, Brentford.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Not as impressive as the one in Loughborough...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200205_144028034_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Brentford Lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200205_152118563.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you say so....&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200205_152832557_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now this sounds sensible.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200205_153630905.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So far though, it's just a building site.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the crow flies, Kew gardens was very close to our mooring, so we decided to visit. Unfortunately we were on the wrong side of the Thames, so, being non-crow, we had to walk quite a long way to find a bridge to cross, then walk back along the river to the gardens, Oh well, it was a lovely day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have both been to Kew Gardens on several occasions but we still managed to discover new treasures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_122642620.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There were no dragons on the Pagoda last time I saw it!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_124532596_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Japanese Gateway.
Despite being here since 1910,
it was new to us!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_114033824.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;When we were children, there wasn't a play area here for us...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_113704631_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...so we made the most of it on this visit.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_134924409.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The flabbergasting Marianne North Gallery.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200131_144237713_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from the tree-top walk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night Liberty Belle somehow managed to find herself on top of the underwater obstacle. Oddly, just as we were leaving the EU, she suddenly lurched and ended up at a frightening angle, dangling off this hidden ledge! We both woke with a start. Tony leapt into action and went outside to shove at the boat, finally succeeding in getting us floating again. (I remained in the bed, supervising things from there...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day Tony went in search of somewhere more suitable to tie up. There was still a space at the Winter Moorings and, strictly speaking, although the permit holders have priority, other boats can moor there if a space is available. Clearly, no one was using this space...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slid in, hoping that no-one with a permit would move us on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were expecting Joe and Carter to arrive the following day and we were now in a more convenient spot, nearer to the railway station. As it turned out, we also had a surprise visit from Robin and Julie on their way home from a trip to London. What a sociable day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG-20200202-WA0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh no!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Is this the end of Maggot...? *&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe's plan was to work while he was staying with us, by either going into the office (near St. Pauls) or working from the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;On the first morning Joe went into London for the day and our only tasks were&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look after the puppy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collect water.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, 1) was simple, tiring, but simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as 2) was concerned, we decided to wait until a break in the rain before setting off for the tap just before the nearby lock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, a boat passed us, heading in that direction. We were concerned that he would pinch our space on his way back from the tap if we vacated it so we waited....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After quite some time Tony went off to see what had happened to the boat and found it moored at the lock. Ok, that meant we were safe to go!
Before we set off, another boat passed us. Oh, for goodness' sake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited for him to return...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did, finally, move to the lock, turn, stop at the tap and fill up with water, then return to 'our' mooring, but it took all day! We hoped Joe's day had been more productive...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had spent a few days in Brentford we moved on, back through Hanwell, then turned onto the Paddington Arm.  In front of us were 2 very slow boats, so we gradually made our way to Greenford in a frustratingly sedate convoy. There we found a very nice 14 day mooring near a pub...&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200206_122454919_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing through Hanwell locks, the old Asylum in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290590cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We think this swan may have had a little help making this nest from a bale of hay...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290637.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Birds are gathering....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We did see a tree full of cormorants. We have never seen that before...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...but we have no photo of that, so here are some crows.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290639cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Trees full of parakeets are very common this close to London.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning onto the Paddington Arm...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290630.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... we've got ourselves a convoy!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we were moored in Greenford, Joe had another day in town and John &amp;amp; Melissa caught up with us. We decided to make use of the dog friendly pub for our meal. Sadly it was too dog friendly, with dogs wandering about and demanding treats from the besotted barmaid. Carter found this far too distracting and therefore so did we!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Joe and Carter had headed for home, we decided to stay in Greenford for a while.
We had another day out in London, a day of sitting tight for storm Ciara and a day hunting the Gruffalo in the woods nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200208_125906131_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Battersea Park Peace Pagoda.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200208_135850987.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The elegant Albert Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200208_120749961.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The grounds of the Royal Hospital, Chelsea.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200208_115653923.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The parking outside the Chelsea Hospital cafe....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/IMG_20200210_102722896_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In the woods at Horsenden Hill,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Gruffalo encounters a man in a rhino hat...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, on a sunny morning, we headed for our 7 day pre-booked mooring in Paddington Basin. We had decided to take the stress out of our visit by reserving (and paying for) a mooring through the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust online booking system....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it worth booking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that's another story...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290682.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Popular city moorings...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290670.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;No room on the boat for a garden?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Drag it behind you in a metal cage!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n70/P1290668.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Londoners whizzing over us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* Maggot is a bit grubby, (see what I did there?), but lives on!


&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently North of London exploring the Lee Navigation and the River Stort. We will need to return the way we came, back to London, where we will brave the tidal section of the Thames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we survive that and Liberty Belle is still afloat, we hope to travel down the Basingstoke Canal, followed by the River Wey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Uxbridge to Greenford 29th January - 11th February 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Curious Characters</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/02/22/curious-characters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Curious Characters" /><published>2020-02-22T18:56:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-02-22T18:56:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/02/22/curious-characters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/02/22/curious-characters.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Kings Langley to Uxbridge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20th-28th January 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n69map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290445.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Boats moored by Cassiobury Park&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first task on the morning of 20th was to get Liberty Belle to a tap. Fortunately we had enough water in the kettle for a morning cuppa.... then off we went!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are signs of spring now. Some leaf buds in the hedges, a little blossom here and there as well as some birds, heron and coots in particular, thinking about pairing up and nesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290409.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now we are inside the London Orbital!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290414.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A prettier bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290421.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An even prettier bridge...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...probably built by a rich landowner.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just managed to squeeze Liberty Belle into a space next to a very popular tap!
Whilst waiting for our turn we met&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;a musician who has lived on boats for years, both here and in Spain. He tried living in a house for a while but couldn't do it and went back to a boat. He was waiting for a gap near the tap for his boat and meanwhile was having a cuppa on another boat in the queue.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;a boater who's car engine had become waterlogged. The RAC van arrived at the tap and we all watched the proceedings.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;the owner of a small plastic boat (the shape of which you could just make out underneath all his 'stuff') who was looking for somewhere to empty his toilet. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After filling our water tank we moved off to the next lock but the small plastic boat had beaten us to it. If it had been a narrowboat we could have shared the lock, but Liberty Belle would probably crush a little boat like that, so we let him go ahead. He started operating the lock with a spanner.....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was too painful to watch so I suggested he get back on board his boat and let me do the work using my windlass. Meanwhile, Tony went to fetch one of our spares and gave it to him. &quot;'ow much do yer want for it?&quot; was his response as he took it. Tony explained that he was welcome to it but has a feeling he has probably sold it since....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen the chap through the lock we passed through it ourselves and moored in a space underneath a railway bridge. As we arrived, the boat in front of us was leaving. I hoped it wasn't us he was escaping from but he explained he was leaving because of &quot;all the pigeon shit&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh. I see. Good point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200121_092245182_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored underneath a favourite pigeon perch.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/20200122-IMGP0043.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A zig-zag alternative to horseshoe falls on the River Colne alongside the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our travels over the next few days we stopped and investigated Watford, Rickmansworth, the village of Harefield and a couple of Nature Reserves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first was Cassiobury Park, originally the grounds of an abbey, then a manor house. Over the years, as parts of the land came up for sale, they were purchased by the council and became a public park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second was Stockers Lake Nature Reserve, the site of old gravel pits, now flooded, with wide paths, visitor facilities and lots of water birds to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200121_131316032_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Indicating the many exciting things to do in Cassiobury Park.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200121_173224885.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cassiobury Farm has some exotic residents.
Here is a night time view of some.
(Wolves?)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290465.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Popular winter moorings where the boats are two abreast.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290467.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The swans gather where the River Colne and Grand Onion meet on the edge of Stockers Lake Nature Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mooring outside a supermarket, picking up supplies.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290486.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Collecting water on our way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One morning, after passing through a lock, I was just closing the gates, (which were very heavy), when Tony called back to tell me there was a boat coming, so I swung one of the gates back open. Walking along the towpath I realised the oncoming boat had pulled in. On speaking to the owner it was immediately obvious that he had had something rather more interesting for breakfast than I had! He seemed to think it was hilarious that I had left the gate open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationlisten&quot;&gt;&quot;I get told off for leaving gates open!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationtalk&quot;&gt;&quot;Sorry I thought you were going into the lock..... Are you going into the lock?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationlisten&quot;&gt;&quot;I am Babe, I am going into the lock, I am.&quot; (Much laughter...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationtalk&quot;&gt;&quot;So, I left it open for you.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationlisten&quot;&gt;&quot;I get told off for leaving gates open!&quot; (Much more laughter...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;conversationtalk&quot;&gt;&quot;Ok, bye! Have a good day!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was to find out, it is a local habit to leave the gates and paddles up when you exit the locks around here. So much so, that the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust have put signs on the locks to remind people. So annoying! Maybe if I start adding a little something to my muesli I would find it funnier...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...or just leave it for Rachel to sort out. Hurrumph!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200125_131841346_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Harefield.
Apparently it's the centre of the world!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200125_132750105_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It certainly has a fair sized village pond...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;oh, and an internationally renowned heart &amp;amp; lung hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent some time looking for the church in Harefield, which turned out to be at the bottom of Church Hill, which we thought was unusual. Attached to the church is a Military Cemetery containing 120 graves of Australian servicemen from the First World War. The Harefield Hospital was originally set up for Australians wounded in Europe and 50,000 of them were cared for there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unique scroll-shaped headstones were designed by people from the hospital before the War Graves Commission introduced the usual, more simple design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200125_140831055.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Smart old alms houses in Harefield.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200125_140305413.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St. Mary's Church, Harefield&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200125_140154517_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Australian Military Cemetery&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290489.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I decided not to add our bin to this lot...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG-20200125-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Great fun for kayaks but poor Liberty Belle struggled past, just missing a moored boat by inches...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/P1290440.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I wasn't planning to swim in the canal anyway...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next planned stop was in Uxbridge. We arrived to find that all the mooring spaces were taken so we had to keep moving. We found a place to tie up outside an industrial estate a little further down the canal. We were still within walking distance of Uxbridge town, so we toured the charity shops to buy some toys for Cocker Spaniel Carter who was due to visit soon. Whilst there we hatched a plan to travel by train into London the following day. At the start of our journey we discovered that we hadn't emptied our rucksack properly after our shopping spree the day before, and had a small stowaway....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG-20200128-WA0004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maggot!
What are you doing in the rucksack?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_122934137_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Seeing the sights!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_111019117_BURST044.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the Faraday Museum.
&quot;Can you keep up with the song?&quot;
Not a hope.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_120502294.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maggot is waiting for a Royal Institution Lecture...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_154558584.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In Somerset house, the only free areas seem to be staircases.
The Stamp Stairs....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_160056106_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and the Nelson Stairs, 
(which reminded me of Hogwarts).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_160712634.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from Somerset House.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_160805186.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Old Father Thames is beginning to show his age....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG-20200128-WA0012.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Somerset House,
where North, East, West and New
are all in the same direction...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_163732593.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maggot at Saint Paul's.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG_20200128_163958655_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Herding sheep to market.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid the rush hour crowds and train prices, we decided to find a pub to while away some time. Unfortunately, it was also rush hour in the pubs! Eventually we found one with a couple of spare stools. The two other people seated at the table welcomed us. They were train drivers and RMT representatives who had been at a meeting earlier in the day and were the two most drunk men we had seen in a very long time! We had a short conversation with them which was repeated many times and successfully entertained us for quite a while... When we left them, both Tony and I were hugged and kissed goodbye by them both. They had already been there for about 5 hours and showed no inclination to leave!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n69/IMG-20200128-WA0020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the way home after a long day...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we are on our way up the River Lee.  After a diversion along the River Stort we will return to London before tackling the Basingstoke Canal and River Wey, all being well....!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Kings Langley to Uxbridge 20th-28th January 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">All the Rage.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/01/29/all-the-rage.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All the Rage." /><published>2020-01-29T19:51:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-29T19:51:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/01/29/all-the-rage</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/01/29/all-the-rage.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Marsworth to Kings Langley&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3rd - 19th January 2020&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n68map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/P1290365.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A pile of hundreds of empty mussel shells crammed into a corner of a lock gate.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Empty mussel shells crammed into a lock gate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Odd...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, with the festive season behind us, (feeling somewhat heavier and less fit, as is traditional), we journeyed back to Marsworth where we had left Liberty Belle. We try not to worry about abandoning our boat but it is always a relief when we find her exactly where we left her, safe and sound, with nothing missing...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to walk a couple of miles or so from Tring railway station so we hadn't packed any food from home, and there was no food on board, so we were obliged to eat in the local pub.... Shame!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we travelled through 7 locks and found a mooring on the outskirts of Berkhamsted. Still having no food, we walked into the town, ate in a pub again (what a bad habit), then walked back via Waitrose where we picked up a few bits. We pulled Liberty Belle over at the 2 hour shopping mooring right outside Waitrose as we passed by the next morning and stocked up properly. So far so good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/P1290362.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cowroast lock. Last time we came the new wood was quite red with black writing on it. This time the timer is a silver grey.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cowroast Lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Last time we were here, these gates were brand new. It is already showing signs of weathering.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/P1290363.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A verty rotten lock gate with a orange painted steel brace.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A little further along the canal, this lock gate must surely be next on the list for replacement!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, out of nowhere, we had our first experience of canal rage! On a wide stretch of canal we saw a boat heading towards us. There was plenty of room but the oncoming boat didn't seem to be taking advantage of the width, heading straight for us. Tony gradually moved more and more to the right, closer and closer to the fishermen lining the towpath. Strangely, the other boat seemed to be hugging the towpath too. Suddenly he started shouting at Tony, demanding that he use his common sense and pass on the other side! One of the fishermen, assuming that boats should stay on the left, as cars do, joined in! Many words were exchanged....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boats just managed to miss each other and no fishing equipment was damaged but it was quite an episode, albeit a slow motion one! We still don't know what it was all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored in Berkhamsted for several days outside The Rising Sun, known to the locals and boaters as &quot;The Riser&quot;, a pub we came across last time we were here and rather like!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200106-IMGP0011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel stood in front of the canalside Rising Sun pub at Berkhamstead&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Outside the pub...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200108-IMGP0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A poster outside the pub reading 'The Rsing Sun. There's nothing for You Here' with characters from the TV series 'League of Gentlemen'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...where a warm welcome awaits....??&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200105_170040278.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A single flocked decoration on the wall reading 'Christmas at the Rising Sun'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The full extent of the Christmas decorations in the Rising Sun...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Berkhamsted is a pleasant town with proper shops, an excellent community cafe, some historical interest and plenty of walks in the hills around, so we weren't short of things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking around the area we came across a monument to the 3rd Duke of Bridgewater who created the first canals to carry coal from his mines in Worsley. (We visited the wharf there during one of  Mary's visits.) It seems the family seat was the Ashridge Estate, near Berkhamsted. The monument was built quite some time after his death and the widow of his successor, who was resident at the time, insisted that the monument was erected far enough away from the house to prevent her from seeing it because she found it so ugly. I have to sympathise with her....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200106_100803632.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A wooden sign with footpath arrows pointing in all directions.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Footpaths every which way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200106-IMGP0020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel stood in a zig zag warren of worn earth trenches.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some of the 7.5 miles of WWI troops training trenches dug out above Berkhamsted&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200106-IMGP0030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone castle-like building surrounded by walls.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A college we came across which looks like a walled city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200106_110523790_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony at the entrance to an old ice house.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old ice-house in the grounds.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200106-IMGP0031.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A set of hoal posts with its net furled.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of Tony's definitions of posh - a goal with a net attached.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200106-IMGP0033.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone fluted column with a copper orb at the top.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The ugly Bridgewater Monument.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200106-IMGP0039.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The village pond and stocks with a half timbered house.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stocks conveniently close to ducking pond.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200107-IMGP0004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony at the top of the steps to the castle motte.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Berkhamsted Motte &amp;amp; Bailey Castle&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200108-IMGP0006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The decorative 'Potten End' villag sign.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A walk to Potten End to find an interesting tea room where we planned to have lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200108_114429472.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A sign explaining that the tea room is closed for an extended Christmas break.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We found it but it was, of course, closed...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having explored Berkhamstead we moved to Hemel Hempstead where we stayed for a few days whilst storm Brendan blew itself (himself?) out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/P1290371.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel working a very difficult lock mechanism.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Put yer back into it!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/P1290370.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel working a very difficult lock mechanism in a slightly different position!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Get yer weight behind it!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200110-IMGP0022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Greg's baker with Liberty Belle moored alongside.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A canalside Greggs.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Really?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Yep.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/20200112-IMGP0026.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle moored between two other boats on a wide, peaceful bit of canal near a lock.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our mooring in Hemel Heampstead.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hemel Hempstead has much to admire. It has a wide pedestrianised town centre with a variety of shops and long strip down the middle dedicated to children's play areas and various types of seating, some of which are under cover. On this main street is the entrance to a covered shopping centre which has a soft play area, comfortable seating and toilet facilities with large cubicles for family use, changing facilities with a hoist, large enough for use by an adult, curtained babyfeeding cubicles with comfy armchairs and a small kitchen with microwave. Beat that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What's more, there is a long strip of garden following the river, which separates the main shopping street from the car parks, which are well hidden from sight as you stroll along the winding path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't suggest it is somewhere to go out of your way for, but if you are in the area, Hemel Hempstead is worth a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200112_151638929_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The river passing through Hemel Hempstead with ornamental plants and trees.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The river-side walk between the shopping street and the car park.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200114_084450913_BURST000_COVER_TOP_cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A goose which has characteristics of both species.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A hybrid goose.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Part Canada and part Greylag.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well, well, well!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our wanderings we also found the historic town of Old Hemel Hempstead which still has its own high street with some interesting old buildings as well as a delightful public park and play area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200118_143744276_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony stood by the oron railing in Old Hemel Hempstaed with a haf timbered house in the background.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hemel Hempstead Old Town High Street.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200118_144704953_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An isolated stone and brick tower with a opening through to a garden with a church spire behind.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;16th Century Charter Tower and walled garden is all that is left of a mansion in the Old Town.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near our mooring space was the SunnySide Farm Shop and Cafe where a charity employs adults with learning difficulties to grow and sell produce, look after the hens, and run the cafe. We felt we should support them so we bought a loaf of bread, some expensive, tiny eggs and some extremely expensive washing-up liquid refill. I just hope it's super-concentrated!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, in search of a launderette, we walked along the canal to visit Kings Langley. On the way back we stopped at a cafe boat where we had tea and cake whilst listening to the owner's unfavourable opinion of the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust. It seems that they have made it difficult for him to run his business. Shame on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the weather was more favourable we moved Liberty Belle to Kings Langley.
Joe was hoping to meet up with us so we walked from KIngs Langley to Watford looking out for a suitable mooring space on the way. We needed a parking space near by as well as easy access to a railway station so that Joe could spend the day working in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our walk we came across a boat that was straddling the canal, its back mooring pins having worked their way out of the sodden ground, and the front pins were only just holding too. It was effectively blocking passage for any other boats as well as being in danger of drifting off. Tony contacted the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust to explain the situation and they contacted the owners. That was our good deed for the day done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned from Watford on the train, having concluded that Liberty Belle was already in the best position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200115_132106642_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A narrowboat straddles the canal while Tony talks on the phone.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The loose narrow boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG-20200117-WA0010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An Art Deco building with 'Ovaltine' written across and a picture aof a healthy wench holding a sheaf of barley.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kings Langley, home of the Ovaltinies!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day we had a nose around Kings Langley where we found a church cafe selling excellent cakes and a fish and chip shop! Not a bad day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe and his puppy, Carter, joined us that evening and stayed for a couple of nights. During the day Joe went into work by train and we got to play with Carter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG-20200117-WA0014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel with Carter the cocker spaniel sniffing at the full extent of his lead.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What's this over here?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What's that over there?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This way. No, that way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Backwards, forwards,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;upwards, downwards,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;here, there,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Walking a puppy.....!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Joe and Carter had gone back to their normal lives, we decided to follow in Joe's footsteps and take a train into London for the day. We saw the Wallace Collection, which is well worth a visit, caught up with Robin, walked along the river and took in the views from level 10 in the Tate Modern. It was a pleasant, sunny, satisfying day but tiring. When we got back on the boat we just managed to have a shower each before we completely ran out of water! Oh well, we will have to move tomorrow to find the next tap...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200119_112104157_cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A bioxwood carving of a peasant leaning on a wooden 'pole'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Wallace Collection had a carving of a man with a Calder &amp;amp; Hebble handspike!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What are the chances?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200119_113902243.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An piece of iron armour to cover a horses head with a short 'unicorn' spike and an eagle's beak.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Armour for a horse's head.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fearsome!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG_20200119_131743106_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony stood at a stone pulpit attached to a church wall.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony addressing the crowd&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(well, just me)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;from an outside pulpit.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n68/IMG-20200119-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The skyscrapers of central London illuminated by the golden setting sun with electric lights on within the scene.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The view from Tate Modern of London lighting up,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;courtesy of Robin.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are gradually making our way into London, as slowly as our water supply will allow, hoping that we will find suitable moorings as we go. In the spring we tentatively plan to travel North up the rivers Lee and Stort then, (via the Thames), tackle the River Wey and Basingstoke canal, followed by the Thames to Lechlade.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Marsworth to Kings Langley 3rd - 19th January 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">‘Driving Home for Christmas’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/01/08/driving-home-for-christmas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="'Driving Home for Christmas'" /><published>2020-01-08T17:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-08T17:27:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/01/08/driving-home-for-christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2020/01/08/driving-home-for-christmas.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Brinklow to Marsworth Junction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3rd - 17th December 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n67map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/20191212-IMGP0009.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The words 'This door makes depth' carved into a lock arm.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lines of poetry carved into the lock gates...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/20191212-IMGP0008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The words 'Captive for a while' carved into a lock arm.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...at Hillmorton by Peter Coates in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had been banished to the house for an uncertain amount of time whilst waiting to hear from the boatyard. Liberty Belle's dry dock in Brinklow was actually an old widebeam hull with a lift-up section at the front which can be raised to let water in and allow a narrowboat to be driven inside. Being a boat itself, the dry dock can be floated into position behind the boat that is going to enter it. The front section is then lowered back into place and the water pumped out, allowing access to the narrowboat's hull. Genius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are baffled by my description of the dry dock and want to know what it is really like, this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TiOyp4xkLfs&quot;&gt;YouTube video of Brinklow's Floating Dry Dock&lt;/a&gt; might help &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, Liberty Belle didn't have her propeller repaired but instead, had her original propeller, (replaced some time in the past and housed in the engine bay), re-fitted. Her bottom was blacked (in two stages because of unfavourable weather conditions) and a few other little jobs completed that had been recommended when we had her survey done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, on Wednesday 11th December, she was ready to be collected. We drove back in the hire car to a convenient parking space where the road meets the canal, near Brinklow, and walked the muddy route to the boatyard where she was waiting for us. Once on board, we eased our way between all the moored boats to the end of the arm, turned and headed off to the parking space where we loaded the contents of the car into the boat. Tony then drove the hire car into Brinklow, parked and walked back to the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/20200108-IMGP0010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our brass propeller showing a bent blade.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This is the bent propeller that was removed. The blade on the left shouldn't have a hump in it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off we went to Rugby. Initially we weren't very impressed by the propeller, as we seemed to be struggling, but it turned out that we had picked up a large sheet of plastic that was causing the problem. Once that was removed we were off like a shot! With her original propeller in place, Liberty Belle seemed much faster. Apparently, the one that was in place when we bought her was designed to be equally efficient for travelling forwards or in reverse.... As we spend most of our time cruising forwards, hopefully we gain more than we lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored overnight in Rugby and the following morning Tony caught a bus to Brinklow, collected the hire car and returned it to Enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We then set off for Hillmorton locks, where one of the pounds was short of water, which slowed us down a bit whilst we topped it up. 
The following morning we arrived outside the chandlers in Braunston just as they were opening and bought ourselves 12 bags of coal. (They store their coal indoors here, so it stays dry. Last year we had a lot of wet coal which doesn't create much heat....you live and learn.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we made our way through Braunston we were greeted by a very friendly lady who had heard about us from our newsletter friends, Lin and Charles. It was exciting to be recognised, we felt like celebrities! We didn't have time to stop though, because we had promised ourselves a curry in Weedon Bec if we got there early enough....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, through Braunston Locks and Tunnel, to Norton Junction. Through 7 locks there, (including the one we nearly sank in, right back at the beginning), which were heavy and difficult, partly due to an excess of water.  Then, finally, we arrived! Not only were we in time for a meal out, but we were able to go for a leisurely drink beforehand too. It was our third visit to this particular Indian Restaurant - we are practically regulars!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bags of coal piled up in the bow and covered with a nylon waterproof cover.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Doesn't everyone keep their coal under a bike cover?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290274.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view back from the stern of Liberty Belle from inside a lock.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It feels good to be travelling again.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/20191212-IMGP0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony steering well wrapped up in a waterproof jackest and German army issue arctic mittens.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wrapped up well.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel driving Liberty Bellein a brimmed hat and muffler looking like Zorro!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Zorro!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290309.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two stand up paddleboarders making their way along the canal under a bridge.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Polite and patient SUP'ers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290330.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle ploughing its way through part of a 100 strong flock of Canada Geese.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wall to wall *&amp;amp;%$£@ geese! The photo doesn't do justice to the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day was very windy but we soldiered on regardless, which was a mistake. At one of the locks Tony brought Liberty Belle into the side and held onto her centre rope as it was too windy to just drift about waiting for me to open the gate. There was a sudden gust of wind which took him by surprise and he fell backwards, giving himself a large bump on the back of his head. I was rather worried, thinking he might suddenly collapse later in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out, we were joined by another boat, so he was kept chatting by the helmsman (or rather, woman), so at least she would notice if something was wrong. Her partner, working the locks with me, was also quite chatty, so we were both entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young couple had met doing the Argentine Tango, which takes them all over the world (I guess they don't tango all the way there and back...). They decided to give up their rented flat in London and buy a boat to live on instead. They work from home and only need to be in London occasionally so it suits them well. They were very up-beat, happy and pleasant people. Their boat is called 'So Long'; see what they did there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished the day by eating leftover curry. It was just as yummy as it had been the day before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony didn't suffer any ill effects from his accident and the egg-sized lump gradually went away over the next couple of days. Another lesson learnt (possibly) - tie your boat securely when waiting for a lock...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290343.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone bridge decorated with ogee half–cupolas and by ogee headed niches.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Grade II listed ornamental stone bridge in Cosgrove. Presumably funded by a well-to-do local landowner.*&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290346.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view down onto the River Ouse from the iron canal aqueduct.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Grand Onion passing over the River Ouse in an iron trunk.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather slowly cheered up over the next two days and we had several sightings of deer and kingfishers. We passed through Milton Keynes without stopping, as we wanted to get a little nearer to Berkhamsted where the canal was due to close for repairs on 7th January. We didn't want to be under too much pressure immediately after Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Marsworth we found an ideal mooring; amongst other boats, outside a private house with plenty of people passing backwards and forwards. We decided that Liberty Belle would be safe there for the two weeks over Christmas. It did mean we had over 2 miles to walk along the muddy towpath to get to the railway station the following morning, but we travelled light and got there in plenty of time to catch our train to Eastleigh. (Chandlers Ford station was closed because of rail strikes...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290350.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The steel barge horse sculpture by the side of the canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Back through sunny Milton Keynes...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/P1290354.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Il wildlife decorate this modern panted steel sulpture by the side of the canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...with its canal-side art.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n67/CosgroveBridgePlaque.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An extract from a local newsletter.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;*Apparently there is some doubt about the name of the Cosgrove bridge.
In Feb 1996 the Parish Clerk tries to cover his arse in a local newsletter....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The image reads...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;ORNAMENTAL BRIDGE - BRIDGE ROAD: As neither British Waterways, Village historians nor Older residents can agree, i.e., Solomons or Samsons Bridge. (British Waterways, know it as Solomons Bridge but can't confirm the origin of that name). The clerk to avoid embarassment and, in an attempt to remain neutral as a non resident, intends to refer to it by the above title from now on. As you read this, it is hoped that work has already commenced on the bridge and its approaches as previously reported.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently moored in Berkhamsted and have been exploring the local area. As yet we haven't done any planning at all! We will let you know when we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Brinklow to Marsworth Junction 3rd - 17th December 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Weaving around The Black Country</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/12/28/weaving-around-the-black-country.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Weaving around The Black Country" /><published>2019-12-28T18:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-12-28T18:03:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/12/28/weaving-around-the-black-country</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/12/28/weaving-around-the-black-country.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Birmingham to Brinklow&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13th November - 2nd December 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/BCN-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Birmingham Canal Navigations&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Map of the Birmingham Navigations. We did most of the red and yellow parts in the centre and top of this map.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n66map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;&quot;Birmingham has more canals than Venice, but I know where I'd rather be...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quote from a friend. (You know who you are!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We, in contrast, were very enthusiastic about the adventure ahead of us as we set off from Cambrian Wharf, looking forward to the twists and turns, loops and junctions of the Birmingham Navigations. We had read that, although not known for their beauty, these canals were interesting from an industrial point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started well, round the Port Loop, the Soho Loop, up the pretty Smethwick Locks and across the beautiful Aqueduct onto the Engine arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280553.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Such pretty iron footbridges.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Smart new housing on the Port Loop.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280500cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A little canine gongoozler.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first tiny hiccup was having to be towed around the turning space at the end by a kind gentleman whose boat is moored there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we stood on the stern watching him haul us around, we chatted about the large old warehouse opposite his boat. Apparently it is a listed building which has been strengthened inside to preserve it. The outside remains untouched, including a protruding wooden structure. The man said it would inevitably fall at some point and he just hoped it missed his boat when it did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanking our helper, we moved back across the aqueduct and then through the delightful Galton Valley, which makes you feel, (briefly), like you are in the middle of the countryside. This illusion is almost immediately shattered by the main roads criss-crossing overhead... Down below, The Old Main Line passes over the New Main Line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next diversion was along the Titford Arm, up the Oldbury Locks to The Pumphouse. We planned to turn at the next winding hole but we didn't quite get that far. The canal proved to be too shallow for us, so we had to reverse the half mile back to the Pumphouse.  Well done, Tony, that was not an easy task!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A resident boater at the Pumphouse stood, with mug of tea in hand, and watched us backing up. He offered us a mooring for the night, for which we thanked him, but we insisted on returning down the lock flight, so he recommended some safe moorings. What a nice man.
We moored up at a pontoon that he mentioned. It is safe because you can't reach it on foot. It was sooo slippery that we couldn't have walked off if we tried!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of days later we met a boater who had injured his knee in this very place. Ouch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280569.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Engine Arm Aqueduct crosses the New Main Line&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280591.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The old warehouse building at the end of the Engine Arm with its precarious looking wooden structure overhanging the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280609.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Galton Valley Pumping Station, now a museum&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280637.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Old Main Line passes over the New Main Line&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This company must be doing very well...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280615.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...because it's products are holding up the whole of the Birmingham area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280620.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you are travelling on the motorway in the West Midlands, rest assured there is plenty of scaffolding keeping you aloft.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280624.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well, you never know around here...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280653.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The water is so shallow you can see all the workings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280656.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Grade II listed Titford Pumphouse looking all smug as if it had actually pumped enough water up the locks!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280676.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Travelling backwards....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then continued to twist our way around the network, moving from the Old Main Line, (the wiggly one), along the connecting Gower Branch onto the New Main Line, (the straight one), until we found our way onto the Walsall Canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we travelled down the Ryders Green Locks which were easy to operate, once we got through the pallets. At the seventh lock we met a friendly group of people gathered around a shopping basket fire with their supply of booze and kindling. They warned us about the hidden obstacles in the canal ahead, advising us to stay strictly in the middle. Thanks to them we made it through to the visitor moorings in Walsall without incident, but it was slow going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280695.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So many junctions!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280699.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ryders Green Locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Just shove yer way forwards!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fire extinguishers.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We stopped counting them after a dozen.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280725.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Something with 4 wheels...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walsall was bigger than I was expecting and looked interesting, so we decided to spend a day exploring. Some of our time was lost searching for the Museum. We tried following the tourist signs, some of which had been moved (people seem to enjoy this game). Finally we arrived at the library and asked an assistant. The museum we were seeking closed 5 years ago but the signs have been left up. Okaaayyyy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out that this wasn't the oddest thing about the town. On our travels we discovered St Paul's, which is part church and part shopping centre. It was converted in the 1990's and surely has to be unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also came across the 'Retail Multiples' which is an indoor market and Post Office, which is strange but seems to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the outskirts of the town there is the Walsall Arboretum, which is a public garden made on the site of a flooded limestone quarry. Oddly, it isn't an arboretum. At the time, it was fashionable for a town to have an arboretum, so that's what they called their park. This explanation is given, as if it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way to the visitor's centre where there was a craft sale, (well, that's what they called it), and a display of quilted wall-hangings, representing local villages. They were beautifully made and very slightly bonkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a bit of sanity we visited the Art Gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191116_151429745_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St Paul's still looks like a church from the outside&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191116_151446981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;From the inside it looks like a shopping mall.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191116_152218545.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It turns out that it is both.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191116_152053193.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This chapel is still a place of public worship.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191116_114400473_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The entrance to the non-arboretum, with its display of poppies.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191116_122411566.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This face pops up a lot around here.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In this case he has been stitched onto a wall-hanging.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after the un-reality check that is Walsall, we left our moorings and turned a corner straight into the Walsall flight of 8 locks. There was so little water that I had to go to the top lock to send enough down to keep Liberty Belle floating. It was a long job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the 7th lock, Liberty Belle got stuck half way in. Tony couldn't persuade her to go forwards or backwards. I tried flushing water at her but it didn't help. Meanwhile, the Wolverhampton Community Payback Team came to see what was going on. They were full of advice and tried to pull us out using the stern rope. This didn't work, so Tony rang the CRT for help and, whilst we were waiting for someone to ring him back, it was noticed that the boat had shifted slightly. Tony tried to reverse and she moved! A huge log bobbed up at the bow. It must have been wedged underneath between the entrance to the lock and Liberty Belle's bow. One of the team persuaded us to let him use our barge pole to try and move the log. He was successful and we were able to continue. Well done lads!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony phoned the CRT to cancel our rescue. Finally we got through the last lock, arriving to the sound of loud singing and the sight of a parade with people of all ages waving flags and led by white horses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turned out it wasn't for us, but a celebration of the Prophet Mohammed's birthday. I waved madly and a couple of people encouraged me to join in and come for the feast, but I thought of Tony waiting on the boat, and decided to decline!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried onto the Wyrley and Essington Canal. Nicknamed the Curley Wyrley it has some very tight corners under its bridges and is annoyingly shallow, but it has some pretty sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280738.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Phew. Made it to the top of the Walsall Locks.
What a morning!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280748.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A fridge...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;27&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A stretch of the Wyrley &amp;amp; Essington with pretty views and no rubbish.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280754.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;28&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We tied up to these convenient posts. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bypassed the Cannock Extension on this occasion and, turning at Catshill Junction, we went down the Daw End Canal. This leads into the Rushall Canal which was closed due to lock repairs, so we went as far as we could and turned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a night spent at a marina's visitor moorings we returned to the Catshill Junction which was frozen! This was a surprise and made turning the corner onto the Anglesey Branch very difficult, especially as a wheelie bin was frozen into the centre of the canal. We aborted our first attempt and Tony pulled Liberty Belle out of the ice by her stern rope. We started again, breaking up the ice with the boathook as we went so that Liberty Belle could swing round. It was slow and I was all for giving up but we managed and, as it turned out, the canal was very pretty and well worth a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the Anglesey Branch was the Chasewater Park, where we had a lunch stop before heading back to Catshill Junction to re-join the Curley Wyrley. The wheelie bin was still there but the ice had melted, thankfully!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280776.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;29&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The bird life seems to be thriving!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280790.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;30&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Geese having a nice wash after making a complete mess of the tow path.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280811.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;31&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Proof! The sun did come out!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280818.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;32&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A limestone quarry waste heap. Many old quarries in this area are now nature reserves.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280825.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;33&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle and a bin, both stuck in the ice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280831.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;34&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Right then, Liberty Belle, back we go and try again...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280844.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;35&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A name that crops up a lot on the canals around here.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280852.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;36&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The end of the Anglesey Branch with the Chasewater Reservoir in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280860.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;37&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;King of the castle at the Chasewater Park&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280865.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;38&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old steel coal chute, used to guide coal from rail truck to boat up until the 60's&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280874.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;39&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We were so busy admiring this bridge that we went the wrong way, and had to reverse.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280881.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;40&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Back again, the bin is still there but the ice has gone.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280886.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;41&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canalside art depicting everything connected with Catshill Junction, except wheelie bins.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we went up the Cannock Extension which is as straight as an arrow, heading purposefully nowhere.  It was, however, very pretty in its autumn colours. We didn't go right to the end, but turned at some private moorings in an old colliery arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back on the Curley Wyrley, we got as far as Sneyd Junction where we were welcomed onto a mooring outside the facilities by a kind boater on long-term moorings there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280892.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;42&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Canal and River Trust.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Busy, busy busy!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280917.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;43&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The children will soon learn not to fall in the canal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280924.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;44&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Just throw the old bed in the canal. It'll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280925.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;45&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;There's a gap in the fence, very convenient for disposing of stuff you no longer want...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next little branch on our list was the Bradley Arm, (aka Wednesbury Oak Loop), which can be navigated all the way to the end during office hours. Otherwise, there is a winding hole part way along. This seemed so odd that we decided to play it safe and just went as far as the turning point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that it should be easy going because the CRT's workshop is at the end, so they are bound to keep the canal clear. Famous last words!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The canal was very hard work. By the time we had given it the benefit of the doubt, it seemed a very long way to reverse back to the junction, so we soldiered on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met a boat coming the other way, which was a complete shock as we hadn't seen a moving boat for ages! The helmsman warned us that it had taken him ages to turn at the winding hole. Great. With a boathook and lots of chugging backwards and forwards, we finally managed it.
Just as we were finally facing the right way, a gentleman on the towpath said there was an easier winding hole a few yards further along the canal. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we arrived back on the Old Main Line canal, where we could travel at a reasonable speed - possibly even 3 miles an hour!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way to the Black Country Museum visitor moorings and, because of the bad weather, we stayed for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191121_110839591_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;46&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The route from the canal to Wednesfield church and town centre is through this pretty park.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191121_110521520_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;47&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The canal side entrance to Wednesfield's Wetherspoons.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191121_112326260_HDR_cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;48&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Swans making a huge fuss over taking off, then landing just a few yards further down the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191121_112759768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;49&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle being reflected in a shiny arc above the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1280975.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Arriving at the Coseley tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191123_084313015.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;51&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Black Country Museum Visitor moorings.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst moored outside the museum, we went on a boat trip through the tunnels (a bit of a busman's holiday), where we tried 'legging' the boat. This is how boats used to travel through the tunnel. The horses were taken over the top and two or more men lay head to head along wooden boards placed across the boat, with their feet on the tunnel walls. They then walked along the tunnel walls to propel the boat forwards. Once we got going it was surprisingly easy. Of course we didn't have to do it for long...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our second day we went into the Black Country Museum which is fascinating. We spent quite a lot of time chatting to the various 'historical characters' positioned around the museum in shops and houses. They were very chatty and full of interesting information. Mary is from this neck of the woods, with chain and anchor making being part of her history, so I found it all the more interesting for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191122_104024251.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;52&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Black Country Flag, here represented as a shield, was registered in 2012. The black represents smoke; the red, furnaces; white, a glass flask and the links represent the chain making industry&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191122_104721597_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;53&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A typical Black Country Chain maker, depicted in an artwork in Dudley.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(I imagine the bare chest is just as likely as the square links...)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191122_143654844_BURST002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;54&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here we are in our safety helmets, enjoying the tunnel ride.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191122_151009125.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;55&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here we are in period costume, legging it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Ok, not exactly us.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191123_102159000_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;56&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Going in the back door, directly from the canal. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191123_142832104.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;57&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Not sure why this is here, but I am appreciating it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191123_110623890.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;58&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Vintage trolley bus ride.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ding, ding!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191123_113616036_BURST000_COVER_TOP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;59&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fish and chips, cooked in lard, the old fashioned way.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Is 11:30 too early?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our couple of days off we were anxious to make up a bit of time. So, via Tipton Green and Pudding Green junctions, we turned onto the Wednesbury Old Canal and back down the Ryders Green locks. Here we met a man who was walking his dog along the towpath. I told him that we had found all the people around here, in the Birmingham area, very friendly. That was a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;&quot;You're not in Birmingham now, Bab. This is the Black Country. Never call the Black Country Birmingham, we don't allow that.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think he forgave me though, because he opened a couple of lock gates for us. At lock 7 we were recognised by the group of drinkers gathered around their shopping basket fire, who welcomed us like old friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we reached the Tame Valley Canal which is remarkably straight, with several aqueducts, but was disappointingly shallow. We slowly made our way to Perry Barr locks, hoping to get through at least some of them before mooring for the night. However, on inspection, it was obvious that the pounds were very low on water and a lot of time would be needed to fill them up. Liberty Belle was already positioned in a nice visitor mooring at the top, outside some boaters facilities, so we decided to tie up, stay put and tackle the locks early the following morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after breakfast I got into my wet weather gear and set off to start sending water down the locks. I was met by the wonderful sight of a Canal &amp;amp; River Trust employee already on the case! This very nice man not only helped us to work the locks but dashed backwards and forwards to the locks behind and in front of us, re-setting the paddles to allow water to pass down and filling each lock ready for us. He did all this in a cheerful way, chatting to us as he went. This was the first of several flights of locks he had to check that day. Apparently he had never been called a hero before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our chats, we discussed the rubbish we had seen in the local canals. He told us that 5 years ago the contract for cleaning the canals went to a company who do not possess a single boat. (As far as we know, Chris Grayling had nothing to do with the contract, on this occasion). As a consequence, they have only been able to remove rubbish from the edges. So now, there is 5 years worth of dumped rubbish waiting to be collected.... Good grief. You couldn't make it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Spaghetti Junction, which is far more amazing from underneath. The splash from the lorries going through deep puddles is more impressive too when it slops over the side of the road and comes down into the canal in a waterfall... All the fun of a very slow log flume ride!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We joined the Birmingham and Fazeley Canal at Salford junction and moored at the top of the Minworth Lock Flight.. We were cold, wet and hungry, and grateful for some dry clothes, a coal fire and a hot lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290043.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;60&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Canal &amp;amp; River Trust hero!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;61&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Works as hard as a cat?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What? &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290070.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;62&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Look out for lorry-spray!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290090.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;63&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Star City. The site of recent violence.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of days later we turned right onto the Coventry Canal at Fazeley Junction, which proved to be a lot easier than coming the other way. Now on the pretty section of the Coventry Canal we suddenly realised that the locks didn't need anti-vandal keys to operate them, the safety equipment was still in place and we had flower beds rather than rubbish bags to look at. On reflection, we were glad to be free of the Birmingham Navigations. We shan't need to go back there again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also began to see other boats moving around. One very small boat with an outboard motor seemed anxious to overtake us. Apparently they were in a rush to get to London. We happily moved over so that they could pass. Their motor was thrashing away, creating an impressive wake but not really going much faster than we were, so we stared at their rear-end until we stopped in the delightful Polesworth for a late lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day we came across several locks which had been abandoned by the previous occupants with gates open and paddles up, which is very annoying. It seems the little boat in a hurry to get to London had saved themselves time and effort by leaving half their work for me to do! Charming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We braved frozen ropes, slippery surfaces and mooring pins frozen into the ground to get to the useful little town of Nuneaton. It’s main claim to fame seems to be George Eliot, who gets a mention at every turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290109.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;64&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turret Bridge. Robert Peel wanted the canal footbridge on his land to be fancier than the others!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290121.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;65&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fazeley Junction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290095.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;66&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Winter pansies brighten up this lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290096.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;67&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;It was this big!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290158.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;68&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A thin line between the canal and flooded fields.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;69&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wearing &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; my layers...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290179.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;70&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A working barge leaving a lock to allow us to use it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290183.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;71&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A temporary halt to the dredging of the lock's side pond.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/IMG_20191129_142130662_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;72&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;George Eliot, in drag...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we joined the Oxford Canal at Hawkesbury junction and on to Brinklow where we moored just around the corner from the boatyard where Liberty Belle had an appointment with a dry dock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning, as we were trying to turn through the iced-over canal, we had a phone call from the engineer to check that we were on our way, reassuring us that, once we had passed under the railway bridge, he would see us and sort us out. Did he heck. He was having his tea break whilst we wondered where to go, what to do and where everyone was! Eventually Liberty Belle was settled into the dry dock and we were on the bus to Rugby, where we picked up our hire car and set off for the house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290207.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;73&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Allotment sheds slowly sliding into the canal....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290214.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;74&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sorry Ashby Canal, we will explore you another time.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290219.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;75&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ok, let's go!!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290247.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;76&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Room for one more in the boatyard??&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290250.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;77&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Where is everyone?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Are we in the right boatyard?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Is there a bloke called Steve waiting for us to arrive somewhere else?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290251.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;78&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Just standing here, holding the rope, hoping someone will finally acknowledge us!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290260.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;79&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One boat out....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n66/P1290264.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;80&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...another boat in.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Our travels so far.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/SixteenMonthsMap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route so far.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you are all having a delightful festive season! We are at the house at the moment, enjoying the company of family and friends. We will be heading back to Liberty Belle in the New Year to move her on past some locks in Berkhamstead which will close from 7th January until the end of March. We will potter about in the area until the Spring, when we can set off again to explore the parts of the network that we missed out this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Birmingham to Brinklow 13th November - 2nd December 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Brummagem Again!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/21/brummagem-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brummagem Again!" /><published>2019-11-21T18:41:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-21T18:41:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/21/brummagem-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/21/brummagem-again.html">&lt;h2&gt;Birmingham&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4th - 13th November 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191020-WA0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle moored alongside other residential boats at a wide wharf&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle moored in Cambrian Wharf.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(Straight ahead is the Birmingham Arena)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191108-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Inside the back door of Liberty Belle are two matching shelves holding a pair of windlasses and a pair of mooring spikes.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony made us new windlass &amp;amp; mooring pin holders.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Posh.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting a few jobs done at the house, we returned to Birmingham, dropping off the faulty inverter on the way. Having already been moored for our 14 day allocation, we were ready to move Liberty Belle straight away and make room for another boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived we noticed that the other 14 day moorings were empty, so there certainly wasn't a queue! Tony contacted the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust to see whether they would allow us to stay until we had our inverter back from the repairers. They were agreeable, which meant Tony could easily travel by train to collect it. Fab!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, whilst we waited, we had a good look around the building site which is Birmingham City Centre. We do love Birmingham but it is surrounded by hoardings, scaffolding and apologies! I overheard someone saying that to get anywhere in Birmingham you have to go the long way round. That is so true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside exploring churches and museums, the Central Library and Botanic Gardens we were there to witness the switching on of the Christmas lights and the start of the German Christmas market, as well as the Remembrance Sunday Parade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year we attended a  Remembrance Sunday service around a village memorial, which was a small and very personal affair. This year, in the middle of a city, it was on a much larger scale and very formal. Very different and yet the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also included the occasional trip to the Briar Rose (our nearest Wetherspoons), The Wellington Specialist Real Ale Pub (of course) and the Damascena Coffee House, (my personal favourite).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191107-WA0006x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The German Christmas Market with decorated and illuminated wooden huts selling goodies.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It's beginning to look a lot like Christmas...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191107-WA0014.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tall illuminated Christmas Tree constructed from smaller trees mounted on a frame.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Christmas tree is actually a pile of small trees.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cunning.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191106_124801121.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The whole entrance to the ICC has been removed.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The ICC is having a facelift.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;They seem to be going back to the bone!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191106_125613374.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lots of building materials stashed behind hordings beside the museum.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Outside the Museum and Art Gallery, the work goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191022_144149201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The centrallobby of the library is circular with staircases newtween the levels. Each level is a ircular balcony.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The centre of the ultra-modern Birmingham Central Library.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191022_150016896.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Glass fronted oak bookcases in a period room.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the very top, a sudden change of style.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A collection of everything to do with the Bard, including bad reviews....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191022_152042829.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel descending one of the escalators in the central lobby.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Reversing down the travelator.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A very odd sensation that I don't necessarily recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191106_130128871_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A colourful garden has been built on the terrace of the library.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The delightful 7th floor garden.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Here you can relax and listen to the heavy-duty machinery on building sites from all around the city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191106_161229143.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cast iron arches with a mezzanine floor and a glass roof make up this room in the museum.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the Museum.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I found this room in the building more interesting than the exhibits.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191105_080058469_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view don the locks with a brick wall with arched recesses and Liberty Belle behind.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking down Farmers Bridge Locks with Cambrian Wharf (and Liberty Belle) on the right.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191108_141644283.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tall rectangular, cast iron, roofless, open topped booth. It has decorated panels.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Temple of Relief.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A Victorian cast iron urinal in the Jewellery Quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sadly it is closed, so no relief for Tony!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191108-WA0007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony outside the Middle Eastern coffee shop.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Ooooo.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A second Damascena!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now there is one by the cathedral and one in the Jewellery Quarter. Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191110_133626292.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cast iron aviary consisting of four domed parts connected together/&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The very pretty aviary at the Birmingham Botanical Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191110_140706461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A small brick and tiled shelter in the gardens.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mr. Cadbury used to sit in here to eat his lunch. Transferred brick by tile into the Botanical Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191020-WA0010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The 17 beer hamd pumps in 'The Wellington'.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Wellington.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Look at all that choice!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG-20191111-WA0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel enjoying a pint and mixed smoked nuts.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;My choice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191112_121136872.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The font is a modern bronze, three part fountain.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The font at St Martin's in the Bullring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n65/IMG_20191112_121214578.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The modern door has decorative foliate stainless steel hinges.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the decorative hinges on the church's front door.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we were here, Tony also took the opportunity to try and book Liberty Belle into a boatyard to have her propeller fixed. He chose a convenient boatyard and contacted the number. After some confusing phone calls where he was sent around from one phone number to another until he came full circle, he tried another boatyard. Here he had more success. Now that we had a date we could plan our next few weeks of travel. We decided we had enough time to explore the Birmingham Canals before heading for the Coventry area for Liberty Belle's dry-dock booking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having had the call to say our inverter was ready for collection, Tony went by train to fetch it. It had been the switch that was broken. The nice engineer said there was no charge, so Tony handed him some beer money and both were happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it was back in position and working, we were off. There is a very complicated network of canals around Birmingham and Tony had planned a route that would enable us to travel along most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt good to be on the move again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still chugging around Birmingham and will be heading to the boatyard in time for Liberty Belle's dry-dock 'appointment'.
We had hoped to have time to explore the Ashby Canal on the way but that will now have to wait until next year....&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">Birmingham 4th - 13th November 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good Ol’ Brummagem</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/14/good-ol-brummagem.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good Ol' Brummagem" /><published>2019-11-14T16:21:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-14T16:21:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/14/good-ol-brummagem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/14/good-ol-brummagem.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Nantwich to Birmingham&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14th - 23rd October 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n64map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270884.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A partially obscured sign reading 'Hack Green Secret Nuclear Bunker'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Shhh...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Luckily the weeds have grown over this sign, otherwise everyone would know!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Nantwich on a misty autumn morning with lots of locks ahead of us. The canal was busy and so there was a lot of waiting around for Liberty Belle but it is always nice to chat at the locks and help each other through. It had been a long and tiring day and the sky began to look threatening before we arrived at our planned mooring. We tied up for the night before the last two locks on the Audlem flight, just in time for the rain to start!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the locks I had heard rumours of cake so, whilst Tony put the kettle on, I dashed up to the top of the flight to investigate. Sure enough I found a covered stall on a garden wall with various cakes, bagged up in pairs, a price list and an honesty box. What a wonderful idea. I chose lemon drizzle...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back I helped a single-handed boater through the last lock and passed on the information about cake. He was suitably excited about the news!  Then I took my treasure indoors before I got too wet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the evening in the Shroppie Fly pub, just a few locks down from our mooring and treated ourselves to a delicious meal. Apart from some lads playing pool in the other bar, we were the only customers. Considering the quality of the food, this seemed a real shame, but I suppose it was a school night...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270925.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Shroppie Fly pub in converted canalside warehouses.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Shroppie Fly pub, part way up the Audlem Flight&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191014_171743844.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The bar is made from a large canal boat. The name Shroppie Fly is on the bow.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The bar is made from an old boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A barrel-roofed brick building.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An unusual building at one of the Audlem locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off the next day to Market Drayton, with plenty of locks to do again. We eagerly checked the cake stall as we passed by but were disappointed to find it empty. As we reached a bend in the canal we looked over our shoulders just in time to see an elderly gentleman carrying cake boxes to the stall. Noooooo, too late!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The canal was busy but the boats were well choreographed, one up, one down, one up, one down... Ideal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Market Drayton in no time and looked for somewhere to tie up. We pulled over at some mooring rings and read the notice. Mooring was allowed on this stretch of the canal on market day and the day before, Wednesdays and Tuesdays....  We discussed this for an embarrassingly long time but came to the conclusion that it was Tuesday and so we tied up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270938.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony moving a large raft of floating plant material from the entrance to the lock.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony using the boat hook to move a massive clump of floating weed so that the lock gate can be opened...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270951.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A colourful 'Welcome to Market Drayton' sign with pictures of buildings from the town, a kingfisher and a perch fish.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A really delightful sign welcoming us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270952.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Canal and River Trust sign reading 'Welcome to Market Drayton. Overnight mooring only Except for Tuesday &amp;amp; Wednesday (pre-market and market days), when daytime mooring is allowed.'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So, what day is it?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270955.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle mooring in daylight on a Tuesday!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our Tuesday mooring...!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to our early arrival at Market Drayton and the good weather that afternoon, we managed to service Liberty Belle's engine. Not only that, but the engine still seemed to work afterwards! We were pleased with ourselves until we discovered that the battery inverter, which provides 240V electricity for the TV and my hairdryer, no longer worked.  What on earth could we have done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much discussion and checking Tony managed to convince me that it must be a coincidence...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony with a beard and me without a hairdryer, personal grooming is at an all-time low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191015_172652638_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A modern brewery beside an older pub.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On the way to find a supermarket in Market Drayton we discovered this...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191015_172750382.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Red Lion pub with a large painted JOULE'S BREWERY in the eaves.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and felt we should investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It was a good decision.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG-20191015-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A beermat describing the history of Joule's Ales&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Joules brewing family included the scientist after whom the unit of energy was named!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG-20191015-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel with our pints of Joule's Ale&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So really, it was an educational visit.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we set off in the autumn sunshine. We were travelling through a tunnel of trees, with insects busy in the shafts of sunlight and leaves falling all around us, catching the light as they tumbled. Beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the hard work began, with some difficult locks. The advice for operating the Tyrley Flight is to keep the boat in the previous lock whilst setting the next, because of the strong sidewash across the front of each one. This way the boat can be driven at top speed towards the source of the sidewash which will then turn the bow towards the open lock gates....(If the boat is left to drift in the pound it will be too difficult to approach the next lock at the right angle.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The crew member thus needs to walk ahead, set the lock, open the gates, walk back to the previous lock, shut the gate, back to the current lock, shut the gate.....etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The locks were far enough apart to make this a slow, laborious process.
We also had a boat just in front of us, which meant we needed to empty each lock again before we could use it. The chap in front took pity on us and, when he could, after leaving the lock, he would wind up a paddle to start to drain it for us. This made life a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270966.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A canalside tree stumo decorated with a hat, eyes and nose with a fish dangling from a string.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canal-side art?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maybe...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270974.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A lock in a deep red sandstoen cutting.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the Tyrley Locks&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1270988.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wharf-side buildings decorated with flowers.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tyrley Wharf's pretty lock-side cottages.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cadbury's used to collect local milk here and transport it to the factory by barge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Canal and River Trust sign warning of falling rocks. &quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Crikey!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Now we need to look out for rockfalls...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280021.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A very tall bridge over the canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Being in a deep cut means high bridges&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280066.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A similarly tall bridge with a circular hole containing a telegraph pole.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...one with a short telegraph pole standing in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280032.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two low red brick stable buildings beside the canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another smart set of canal-side stables.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280033.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of the distant Wrekin Hill&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Shropshire's Wrekin Hill in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280043.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A wooden lock gate whichcan be swung out to block off the canal at a bridge.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Shropshire Canal has gates that can be used to cut off sections for repair.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280052.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tall rectangular brick building with a sloping roofed extension towards the canal providing shelter for loading and unloading boats.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A small wharf previously belonging to Cadbury.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280095.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tunnel through the red sandstone. SOme stone has collapsed at the sides.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The local rock obviously doesn't cut easily giving this tunnel entrance an interesting shape.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the day the battery warning light came on so we had to pull over and have a look. It seems, in our attempt to inspect and tighten the alternator belt we had, in fact, managed to loosen it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning,Tony replaced the alternator belt with one of his spares and all was well. (We have plenty of spares of everything for the engine because it is so difficult to buy them at a reasonable price when travelling around).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then had a short journey into Wheaton Aston where we knew that one of the locks was being repaired and wasn't due to open until that afternoon. When we investigated, the workmen were obviously still busy and told us that it may take longer than forecast, possibly until the following afternoon, so we prepared to stay there for a day or maybe more...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hire boat, that we had seen several times over the past couple of days, moored up behind us and were surprised to learn that the lock was closed for repair. We were shocked that the hire firm hadn't warned them, as it had been planned for some time. They were quite upbeat about it though and one of the women was actually pleased as it would give her a chance to have her hair done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we waited we visited the village but there was very little to see. We checked the vegetable options in both shops and found we had a choice of cauliflower or.... cauliflower. We also looked for a hairdresser for our new friend but there wasn't one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to the canal we met our boating neighbours and informed them that the village had just a Co-op and a Spar. The woman's eyes lit up! A Spa! Wonderful! Her dreams had come true.... We were a bit baffled then realised the mistake. No, no. A 'So-near-so-Spar', not a health spa. What a disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turned out the lock opened that evening but we stayed overnight and left first thing the following morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191017_124902973_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A drained lock with a ladder propped againt the far gate and workmen.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Wheaton Aston Lock still under repair.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191018_105141100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view towards the altar of the church with a barrel roof.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A brief stop in Brewood took us to St. Chad's.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191018_105700786.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunflowers arranged in a hollowed out pumpkin on a window cill.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the many Harvest Festival displays in the church.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG_20191018_110425302.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony, with hands and face showing over the top of St Chad's notice board, reminiscent of the old Chad peerinbg over a wall cartoons.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wot. No church cafe?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were both looking forward to being back in Brumm but first we had to get through the 21 locks at Wolverhampton. We thought these might be rather industrial and run down but were pleasantly surprised. They we all very neat, well kept and easy to operate. About half way up the set of locks we came across a busy work party hoeing, weeding, sweeping and rubbish picking. Wow! This was Wolverhampton's secret - a well supported community payback scheme!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most canals approaching cities are rather grim but around Birmingham there are many beautiful sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280103.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A beautiful stone and cast iron aqueduct in need of painting.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A pretty but neglected aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280135cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Five herons, including one coming in to land, in a farmers field.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Five herons in a field. Five!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We have only ever seen one at a time until now.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280174.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel behind and ornate black and white cast iron footbridge.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A pretty footbridge over one of the Wolverhampton locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280183.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A sign at Wolverhampton Top Lock with painted flowers.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lock pride, that's what we like to see.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG-20191019-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle moored just over the fence from the museum.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our overnight mooring outside the Black Country Museum.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280358.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone parapet on the wall leading to a lock with deep abraded grooves.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Years of ropes cutting into the stone as the horses pulled their boats out of the lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eventually arrived in Birmingham and found a 14 day mooring next to some residential boats and near the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust offices. We always feel safe in good ol' Brummagem, but this mooring felt especially so. We decided that we no longer needed to get to Leamington Spa before going back to the house as we were already in the ideal place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting a few jobs done and meeting up with Julia for a delightful lunch, we were fortunate enough to get a lift all the way back to the house where the garden was awaiting our attention...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG-20191020-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A floating pontoon on the canal on the opposite side to the towpath&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A pontoon mooring that has no pedestrian access.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;'Zomboat!' fans will understand the advantages.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/P1280441.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tall buildings herald our arrival in Birmingham.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Heading for the city.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n64/IMG-20191106-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Library of Birmingham has terrace gardens overlooking the city and our moorings.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle in her mooring as seen from Birmingham Central Library.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony has booked Liberty Belle into a boatyard near Coventry for the first week in December to have her propeller repaired. We will be heading back to the house whilst she is in the dry dock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime we are exploring the canals around Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Nantwich to Birmingham 14th - 23rd October 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Liberty Belle Visits Her Home Town</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/07/liberty-belle-visits-her-home-town.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liberty Belle Visits Her Home Town" /><published>2019-11-07T16:58:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T16:58:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/07/liberty-belle-visits-her-home-town</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/libertybelle/2019/11/07/liberty-belle-visits-her-home-town.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Chester to Nantwich&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;30th September - 13th October 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n63map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270371.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TRachel operating a lock with a friendly, interested black dog.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An applicant for the post of &quot;Ship's Dog&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270352.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A canalside modern bungalow conversion with a wooden spire.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving Chester on a sunny day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270596.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony driving Liberty Belle through wooden countryside.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pretty Shropshire.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As September came to an end we began to see hips and haws in the hedgerows with crab apples and damsons in the trees above.
The leaves began to fall, the temperature began to drop and most days came with rain showers. We kept ourselves going with mugs of coffee and cocoa on the move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony decided to grow his beard to help keep him warm over winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still occasionally spotted sprigs of meadow sweet or a butterfly to remind us of the summer just gone.
(We were surprised to see some very young ducklings in the first week of October; I don't hold out much hope of them maturing in time for winter.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dodging the rain as much as possible we left Chester and headed for Wales. (Probably not the best place to go if you are trying to avoid the wet weather.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning onto the Llangollen Canal we immediately entered the first of the Hurleston Locks which is rather narrow and needs careful handling, so it is manned by lock keepers. Liberty Belle was a tight fit, but we made it through without incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a reservoir here at the bottom of the Hurleston Locks which is filled from the Llangollen canal. The water rushes past the locks through the overflows on its way to the reservoir, creating quite a strong current in front of the bottom gates. This makes the approach to the locks difficult. These locks were also hard to operate, so we both had a tiring day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had moored up we realised our phone signals were poor so we decided to go to the local pub to use their WiFi and get a bit more newsletter done. When we tried to access the WiFi we were informed that the local BT box had been involved in a traffic accident and so there was no WiFi to be had. We were advised to have a conversation...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270373.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle approaching the entrance to a bridge over the Llangollen Canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning onto the Llangollen Canal...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270382.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle in a very tight lock, the narrowest on the network and somewhat distorted through collapse.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;..and into the tight lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270393.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle appraching the electric lifyt bridge beside Wrenbury Mill, now housing a shop and hire boat company.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Wrenbury Mill&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270409.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle in a staircase lock with volunteer assistants.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another flight of locks! Grindley Brook&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the day we approached Ellesmere there were no locks to do but plenty of swing bridges which was just as well as I needed something to do to keep me warm. The canal was pretty enough but not very interesting except for the kingfishers and herons. We occasionally had a gap in the hedge through which we would see either a field of corn or cows. Ellesmere itself is a pleasant little place with cafes, useful shops and canal-side art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270427.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel winding a lift bridge open as Liberty Belle approaches and an oncomimg boat waits by the towpath.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One at a time please! &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270416.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel winding another, green painted, lift bridge open.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Instead of the usual black &amp;amp; white, this lift bridge was camouflaged.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Maybe the local smugglers hope we will crash into it in the fog so they can lay claim to our cargo!?!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270740.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Corn growing in a field beside the canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The corn is as high as an elephant's eye...&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270501.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A dead tree with lopped branches tilts towards the canal from the bank.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A dead tree 'bough-ing' to Liberty Belle&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/DSCN3301.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone bench sculpture with a blue mosaic represneting the canal and the words 'Narrow boats loaded with tons of limestone coal, milk and cheese. Duchess COuntess Jupiter move slowy on the way to Whitchurch'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A sculpture...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/DSCN3303.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone sculpture with a spiral twist reading 'Shropshire Cheshire Wales. Vale of...'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;... or two..&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/DSCN3299.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony sitting in a stone, boat shaped shelter.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...some more useful than others.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270465.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cast iron signpost pointing to Ellesmere, Hurleston and Llangollen.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving the little Ellesmere arm and heading for Llangollen.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Ellesmere the views became much more interesting and, in response, so did the canal. The complicated landscape required tunnels, embankments, locks, aqueducts and  viaducts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we negotiated the Chirk tunnels. Neither of these is very long, as tunnels go, but they took us ages! We were going against the flow of water (to the reservoir) and, because Liberty Belle was a fairly tight fit, she had difficulty displacing the water. It seemed to take forever!. Thankfully there wasn't a queue of boats waiting to come through...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270515.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle crossing Chirk Aqueduct with the stone arches of the railway viaduct behind.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A via-duck as seen from the back of an aqua-duck.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270479.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cow wading through a flooded field.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An aqua-cow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270535.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A sign by the canal reading 'Welcome to Wales. Croeso I Cymru.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Cymru!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270548.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Thirteen arches of a railway viaduct in the valley below.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A railway via-duck in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually we reached the famous Pontcysyllte Aqueduct. Tony went onto the tow path to take some photographs and I drove. Although I have been across it several times (in hire boats), I suddenly felt scared. I am not sure why but I seemed to talk myself into it somehow. I could feel my heart being squeezed. I knew logically that I was safe, but it was quite a weird sensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after the aqueduct is a very tight turn under a bridge, so I handed over the tiller to the expert and corrected my breathing!
Before reaching Llangollen there are a couple of stretches of the canal which are not wide enough for boats to pass each other, so I went ahead on foot to make sure these sections were free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270566.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle crossing the Pontcysyllte Aqueduct&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A lofty Liberty Belle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;.
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270572.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of the stone pillars and cast iron arches of the Pontcysyllte Aqueduct.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A side view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &amp;lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/IMG_20191005_101510.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The 126 feet unprotected drop over the side of the  Pontcysyllte Aqueduct to the River Dee be&quot;low. &amp;gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;My view!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Gulp...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270605.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel standing in frony of one of the stone bridges on the way to Lllangollen.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Terra firma.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to the moorings without incident and tied up in the best position; in the sunshine, as near to the town as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the background we could hear dogs barking and thought we must be moored near a boarding kennels...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off we went to pay for 2 nights' mooring and discovered that the electric hook-up was included in the price! Perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly dogs started to appear on the wooded slope on the opposite side of the canal. One jumped into the water, then another. They both tried to scrabble back onto the bank but the concrete side was too steep. I and another boater dashed over trying to encourage the dogs to the towpath side. One responded and I tried to grab it but it had no collar so I couldn't get a hold. The two dogs were now frantic, barking and scrabbling against the concrete sides. Other dogs jumped in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A man appeared on the wooded bank, and we assumed the dogs must be his. Tony moved Liberty Belle across the canal to pick him up and transport him to the tow path.  Once he was on the same side as us, all the rest of the dogs (there must have been a dozen all together) jumped into the canal trying to swim to him. Flippin' 'eck. More people tried to help but none of the dogs had collars... The only thing left to do was to get into the canal and help each dog out in turn. The owner agreed that it would probably come to that.... None of us volunteers felt prepared to get in water so we left him to get his own tweed suit wet. I assume he did just that. I don't suppose he looked quite so dapper in his country gentleman's outfit by the time he got home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it turned out that we were not opposite boarding kennels after all and were in a very quiet, as well as pretty and convenient mooring. After a walk to the end of the canal at Horseshoe Falls, out came the vacuum cleaner, the electric heater and our new electric kettle and we attempted to get our money's worth!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270625.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A horse pulling the trip boat.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Horsedrawn narrowboats are the only ones allowed between the Llangollen Basin and Horseshoe falls.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/IMG_20191005_121208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dakota, the horse, waiting in his stable for his turn to pull the boat.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Your turn next!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/IMG-20191005-WA0021.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel on the grassy slope above the River Dee.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Uphill above Horseshoe Falls.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270614.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cow standing in the River Dee with two other cows behind.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another aqua-cow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270629.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A steam engine chugs by beside the canal towpath.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A passing steam train.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making good use of our two day mooring and the beautiful weather, we went for a walk to the castle ruins overlooking the town. Castell Dinas Bran, or Crow Castle, is a Medieval castle built on the site of an Iron Age hillfort. The walk was delightful and views were spectacular.
We decided to walk back via the Pontcysyllte Aqueduct and along the canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we got to the canal, the weather had changed. It was too wet and windy to enjoy a walk over the aqueduct so we sheltered as well as we could and had a little picnic outside the visitors' centre. We were just in time to see a very small day-hire boat trying to negotiate the tight turn under the bridge heading for the aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The little boat had two men at the back and several passengers, most of them children. The helmsman was going at full speed and didn't seem to know how to steer. He smacked into the side of the canal, reversed without looking behind him, then went full speed forwards again, with the inevitable smack into the side. The children on the boat were screaming as they were thrown about. One of them was wearing another's hot chocolate drink all over the back of her coat. The men at the helm showed no concern whatsoever as they bashed and crashed their way about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nutters!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left before we had to witness the crossing of the aqueduct...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped off at a pub on the way back, grateful for some respite from the rain.
On our return we were pleased to see that the Nutters' hire boat wasn't embedded in the side of Liberty Belle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were moored in the last space before the hire company's moorings with a narrow bridge between. There was no sign of any damage, but I was glad I hadn't been there to witness them passing by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The extensive ruins of Castell Dinas Bran on the hiltop above Llangollen.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Castell Dinas Bran&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270656.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two sheep, beside a steel bench, facing the wooded view from the hilltop.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Locals appreciating the views.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270633.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel attempting to entice a cast iron crow from its perch on a gatepost.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Trying to train the castle's crow.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;He's not having any of it.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270653.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel standing with the castle on a hill in the background.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On our way to the aqueduct with Crow Castle in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending our couple of days exploring the area around Llangollen, we took Liberty Belle back the way we came. Back over the aqueduct (Tony at the helm), through Chirk tunnels (this time we were travelling with the flow, which made it easy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tony driving Liberty Belle back across Chirck Aqueduct.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Back the way we came....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270685.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A blue sign reading 'Welcome to England'.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...back into England&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we had booked passage through the locks onto the Montgomery Arm and planned to explore the Prees Branch too on our way back to the Shropshire Union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Montgomery Arm is being restored and is only navigable for the first 7 miles. The number of visitor boats allowed on the arm at any one time is limited to 12 and passage through the locks at the top of the arm has to be booked in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored at the top of the Montgomery Canal ready to go down the set of locks as soon as they opened at midday. As it happened, they were ready early and waved us in at 11:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270762.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cast iron signpost pointing to Llangollen, Hurleston and Mongomery.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning into the Montgomery Canal&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cast iron signpost reading 'Newtown 35 Miles, Welsh Frankton 0 Miles, Montgomery Canal'.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Are we back in Wales?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270707cropped2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Canal and River Trust chalkboard reading 'Welcome to Frankton! Boats booked for passgae today. Down, Liberty Belle ....'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;They are expecting us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel standing behind a stone wall at the edge of the canal. The wall has a small gap spanned by a cast iron arch.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An iron rail over a gap in the wall, to stop the horse's rope getting caught.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once through the locks the canal was uneventful. It was shallow, which made us slow, and had high hedges on both sides so there was not much to see. As we got nearer to the end of the navigable section of the canal, we came across a winding hole and decided to take the opportunity to turn, just in case the canal got any more difficult to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard work, with me on the tiller revving and reversing and Tony with the barge pole shoving and heaving. With much churning of mud and weed we finally managed to turn and moored at the first opportunity. We then walked the final stretch of canal into town only to find it was the best bit! Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking back to Liberty Belle we noticed that a boat was straddling the canal. It was attached to the bank opposite the tow path with it's bow rope. It's stern rope had frayed right through allowing the boat to float freely across the canal. That was going to be tricky for the next boat to come along. Now we were glad that we hadn't brought Liberty Belle up this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we headed back to the start of the canal arm to arrive at the locks just as they opened at 12 and then turned back onto the main branch to Ellesmere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day we took a diversion down the short Prees Arm, (which never did reach as far as Prees) to see the skew lift bridge highlighted in our guides. It was indeed skew although it wasn't clear why, as it didn't really line up with the track on either side. We bought a bottle of gas in the marina at the end of the arm, reversed out, turned and followed the arm back onto the main canal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought the Prees Branch was prettier than the Montgomery but at first we weren't sure why. We decided that, although both canals were lined with hedges, the ones on the Prees branch were set a little bit further back from the canal itself and were interspersed with various trees, so the heights, textures and colours made it more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside the canal here is a nature reserve, consisting of peat bogs and lakes. Originally it was a battle to keep the canal sides from collapsing and joining the lake but in more recent years, steel piling has been used to create a firm edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270791.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cast iron signpost pointing to Prees Branch, Hurleston and Llangollen.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Turning into the Prees Branch&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270786.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle approching the junction to the Prees line. A red brick toll cottage with a pyramidal slate roof stands at the end of the junction.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Approaching the Prees junction&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270778.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of the lake, surrounded by trees, from the canal.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The beautiful Blake Mere near the town of Ellesmere&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270810.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle about to pass under the skew lift bridge on the Prees Line. The constuction is slightly different from other lift bridges having hinged side rails.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The skew lift bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued on to Whitchurch, finally arriving in the dark. It was quite busy on the main canal so there was plenty of help at the locks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270827.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle in a lock with several streams of water eminating from holes in the brick lock wall.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Water gushing through the side of a lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Luckily it can't get in through the window...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/IMG_20191012_140711083_HDR.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rachel behind the Lychgate of the church with the church in the background.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A lunchtime stop in Marbury.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The pretty church (locked) is right on the edge of a mere&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270836.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Passing back through the narrowest lock under the watchfull eyes of the Canal and iver Trust staff.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The vigilant lock keepers at Hurleston Locks&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After squeezing back through the Hurleston locks under the watchful gaze of the lock keepers, we turned back onto the Shropshire Union Canal, heading this time for Nantwich. We arrived and found a mooring by the Nantwich Aqueduct, Liberty Belle's home 'ground'.
(We were a little bit concerned that the original owners would see her and demand to know what on earth we had done to their boat. Luckily we got away with it!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270855.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A life-sized draft horse, leaning to take the strain, constructed from large old timbers, probably lock gates.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Horses are often the subject of canal-side art.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Isn't he something?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A narrow boat called 'Liberty'&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty sans Belle&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/IMG_20191013_145452527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timber framed buildings in Nantwich town centre.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Damp, but pretty, Nantwich.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/IMG_20191013_120618.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle's sign written side with revealing 'Nantwich' as her original home moorings.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle's origins.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270857.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Narrow boats line the canal at Nantwich with a stone arched bridge in the distance.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The canal through Nantwich...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n63/P1270859.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The grass covered embankment carrying the canal over the neighbouring land.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...is above the town on an embankment.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This newsletter has been a long time coming, I know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently in Birmingham waiting for our battery inverter to be fixed. We will then spend some time exploring the network of canals around the city before heading towards Milton Keynes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully we will be able to buy some coal on the way - it's getting a bit nippy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plans are not very detailed yet as we need to book Liberty Belle in at a boatyard (somewhere) to have her propeller fixed and her bottom painted...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><category term="LibertyBelle" /><summary type="html">From Chester to Nantwich 30th September - 13th October 2019</summary></entry></feed>