<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-18T09:08:58+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Liberty Belle Newsletter</title><subtitle>A day-by-day account of our time aboard the Liberty Belle narrowboat.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">From Bath to Bristol &amp;amp; Back Again (via the Everglades)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/05/17/from-bath-to-bristol-and-back-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Bath to Bristol &amp; Back Again (via the Everglades)" /><published>2019-05-17T21:40:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-17T21:40:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/05/17/from-bath-to-bristol-and-back-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/05/17/from-bath-to-bristol-and-back-again.html">&lt;h2&gt;Bath to Bristol and Back Again (via the Everglades)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;24th April - 1st May 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n44map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4291276.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Another beautiful day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 24th April is Tony’s birthday! After opening his card (not from me, you understand) and hanging it up, we moved Liberty Belle nearer to Bath Spa station and went food shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 11:30 we were waiting at the station for Mary to arrive. We had 2 exits covered but she came out at the third! She nearly went to Leamington Spa, (we are still not sure whether it was her mistake or that of the ticket office) so it could have been worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin, Robyn, caught up with us in the afternoon so we had a long chat, a cuppa and a stroll to take in the views. We all agreed that she lives in a lovely city!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4241146.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing Sydney Gardens in Bath with Cleveland House (originally built as the Kennet &amp;amp; Avon Canal's Management Headquarters) straddling the canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4241154.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On both visits to Bath, Liberty Belle spent some time moored next to this sundial. If the sun was shining, we could see what time it was...Oh well, we'll call it lunch time, just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning, Rose joined us for second breakfast. After opening his second birthday card and hanging it up, we all set off for Keynsham. Rose volunteered to help me fight with some of the locks which sped up the proceedings, particularly for the deep lock in Bath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way we attempted to tie up outside one of the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust facilities moorings, which was tricky due to certain boats being permanently moored there....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the canals, the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust provide certain facilities for boaters. These consist of one or more of the following:- a water tap; elsan disposal; toilet tank pump out; toilets; rubbish bins; recycling facilities (rare); showers (very rare). Boats should only moor at these facilities for the short time it takes to use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In areas where people are likely to want to stay, near shops and pubs, visitor moorings are provided which are restricted to a specified number of days. As there are very few of them on the Kennet &amp;amp; Avon, these moorings are usually restricted to 1 or 2 days. It is very difficult to moor alongside the towpath on this canal because the boats become grounded before they are close enough to the edge for the crew to alight. As a consequence of this, many of the visitor moorings (and even facilities moorings) have been adopted as permanent moorings, disregarding the restrictions. This is very frustrating....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we travelled along Rose was able to point out beauty and colours where I only saw rusty bridges and dilapidated walls... This journey is wasted on me. Maybe someone should write a Rose App that enables you to film things as you go along and points out how beautiful it all is. Or maybe I should just learn to observe...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kept our eyes peeled for a lunch time mooring but found nothing until Keynsham, at about 3pm, where we took the last remaining visitor mooring. Rose had to leave us there and catch a train home, a little later than she had planned. Thank you, Rose, for a lovely day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4251165.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bath Deep Lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Just look at the height of those gates! They are so heavy that they are opened &amp;amp; closed using a winding mechanism, not pushed like the others. This seems to take forever....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bath Deep Lock is the second deepest lock in the country at 19ft 5ins (we didn't measure it ourselves...). It has the combined depth of the two locks that it replaced during the restoration of the canal in 1976. A road was built over the original site of one of those locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bristol Harbour is tidal, so, before entering the harbour, it is necessary to contact the Harbour Master or the keeper of the tidal lock to get permission to continue. Tony attempted several times to book our passage through the lock into the harbour. When he finally managed to get through, he informed them that one of their numbers didn't seem to work at all. The lock keeper was surprised that the number was still being given out as it belonged to a phone that had fallen into the lock a year ago... Well, no wonder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lock itself had been left open but we needed to stop and buy our Bristol Harbour licence. We tied up, making sure we avoided a pole sticking out horizontally from the pontoon looking all the world like an eye-poker-outer. It turned out that the pole had been put there at the same height as the lowest bridge in the harbour to indicate whether we would fit under it or not. It was going to be a tight squeeze, but it wouldn't need to be lifted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our 3 day licence, some indication of where we could moor and the advice to 'navigate the bridges as best you know', off we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got closer the rain poured down in torrents. We contacted Cathy and she confirmed that there was mooring space outside the 'Vegetable Diva', where she works. Hurray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we tried to moor the wind picked up and kept Liberty Belle pinned against the end of one of the pontoon 'fingers' that we were trying to swing past. The lady operating the ferry took pity on us, stood on the end of the 'finger' and heaved Liberty Belle past it and into our mooring. Well done and many thanks to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cathy, who was just finishing her break, saw us arrive and rushed out to greet us but had to immediately return to work.  As it was getting late we stopped to have lunch on the boat before visiting Cathy at her place of work for a coffee. We immediately realised that we should have saved ourselves for something from the cafe because the savoury treats looked absolutely wonderful. I was determined that we would buy some of them the following day. After finishing work Cathy joined us on Liberty Belle for the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4261210.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing under the low bridge in the pouring rain.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4261205.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hello Bristol!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind only got worse overnight. As the waves thrashed against the side of the boat, it sounded like an ogre was tramping up and down on the roof, moaning and groaning… Mary got up a couple of times in the night to check that we weren’t untied and floating off out to sea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/IMG-20190427-WA0007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Waves slapping about at our mooring.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all the noise, we got through the night unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning Cathy and Will escorted us as we were blown around Bristol for the day, dodging in and out of museums, shops and cafes. Joe managed to track us down and joined us for lunch, making 6 of us, quite a family gathering! This could have been tricky in Mokoko, but we managed to commandeer the only table large enough for us in the cafe - Cathy and I can look quite threatening when necessary! Later we all returned to Liberty Belle for the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning the weather was comparatively calm. There were several rowing teams out on the water. Joe joined us for the morning for a coffee in Pinkmans and a look around the excellent Bristol Museum and Art Gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will joined us for lunch at the Christmas Steps pub, after which Joe set off for home and we, (Tony, Mary and myself) set off for the SS Great Britain. We found plenty to interest us en route and by the time we arrived it was almost time for Cathy to finish work. We got straight onto the ferry back to Liberty Belle and I rushed to buy a few yummy things for tea time from her in the ‘Vegetable Diva’. Soon afterwards Cathy arrived with more nice things to eat, shortly followed by Will with even more goodies, so we shared a delicious feast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4281218.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony, Mary, myself &amp;amp; Joe reflected in the mirror sphere that is the Bristol Planetarium.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4281228.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mary &amp;amp; Tony outside the SS Great Britain, with Liberty Belle and the 'Vegetable Diva' in the background, just a ferry ride away.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Monday morning Cathy returned to Liberty Belle and became our helmsman for a couple of days. We had planned to moor at Keynsham the first night but there was no space for us so we had to carry on all the way to Bath where we moored on the river. Well done Cathy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4291246.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Setting off from Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4291271.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Kennet and Avon is partly river and partly canal bypassing unnavigable parts of the river. A weir accompanies each lock on the canal stretches allowing surplus water to flow into the nearby river.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P1240591.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;No, we haven't taken a wrong turn and ended up in the Everglades but we have found a turtle! (Cathy gets the prize for spotting him)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wandered around Bath, taking in the sights, including the Abbey and covered market. We ate excellent pies in The Raven at lunch time, then, in the afternoon, Cathy took Liberty Belle through the 3 locks to the mooring space we had used the the week before. During the evening Cathy had to leave us and caught the train back to Bristol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P4301289.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The horseshoe weir at Pulteney Bridge in Bath which allows a greater flow of water than a straight weir built as part of flood defences in 1972.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary, Tony and I joined a free walking tour of Bath, available every day and worth every penny! We had a very pleasant and knowledgeable guide who kept us interested for over 2 hours. In the afternoon, Tony and I left Mary on Liberty Belle, reading her book, whilst we went for a walk uphill to get some views of Bath. We do like this city and are already planning to return (probably by train to avoid cruising back through Reading...).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P5011317.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Riverside view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P5011297.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hilltop view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n44/P5011309.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Surrounded by flowering wild garlic.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the success of Wednesday's tour we decided to stay for another day and join a different tour, which was also interesting. Feeling that we had now seen some of Bath and maybe learnt a little bit about it, we set off in the afternoon. Before long the weather turned and we got soaked to the skin! We moored up as soon as we found a space, because we couldn’t take any more. We found ourselves in Bathampton for the night, just 2 miles and 3 locks away from our Bath mooring. Oh well!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Bath to Bristol and Back Again (via the Everglades) 24th April - 1st May 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bath Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/05/10/bath-time.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bath Time" /><published>2019-05-10T09:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-05-10T09:04:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/05/10/bath-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/05/10/bath-time.html">&lt;h2&gt;Woolhampton to Bath&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16th - 23rd April 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n43map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4180998.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Burbage Wharf near Pewsey&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Woolhampton full of trepidation, wondering what the Kennet and Avon would throw at us next. It turned out to be a confused electronically operated swing bridge. Having waited for the pedestrians on the towpath to cross over the bridge, I pressed the appropriate buttons to lower the barriers and start the swinging process. Before it had opened enough to let Liberty Belle go through, it stopped. According to a passer-by, it had been fixed the day before... By now, more pedestrians were gathering on the towpath, waiting to cross and Tony was wondering what was taking so long. I pressed the button required to swing the bridge back across the canal and there was some movement, which was encouraging. Tony tied Liberty Belle up and came to investigate. I allowed the bridge to shut again and re-started the process. This time the bridge behaved exactly as it should, opening wide to allow Tony to guide Liberty Belle through. It also closed perfectly and we were off again. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed through Newbury, where we should have been moored back in February for my Mum's birthday - just a bit late. There, we teamed up with another boat, a hire boat with a crew of 10, covering 3 generations of a family, and worked the locks together. We had a short delay, (OK, a long delay), when one of their crew threw the rope from the boat in the direction of a waiting crew member on the tow path, and the rope fell in the water. There was a terrible sound as the rope wrapped itself many, many times around the propeller.  Liberty Belle was waiting in the lock for the other boat to join her. After a while, two more boats arrived and tied up patiently. Just as we were about to give the lock to these newcomers there was a cheer and the offending rope was held aloft. We were off!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Kintbury we managed to squeeze into the last available mooring. It could have been argued that we were partially blocking the bridge so we planned an early start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4160951.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The tranquil scene just before we scattered the swans and ducks...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4160960.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The swing bridge that only wanted to open half way...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/IMG_20190417_084646_597.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our mooring for the night. Liberty Belle just squeezed in before the bridge. Note the ambitious gradient of the railway track on the side of the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to set off before anyone had time to complain about our mooring. Entering a lock we noticed a boat following behind us so we waited for them to catch up. A young man, jogging along the towpath, stopped to help at the lock by opening the second gate. I thanked him. I was a little surprised that he should stop his jog for us. He explained that he was holidaying on the approaching boat and was a little put out that they had set off whilst he was on his run....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There appeared to be two other young people on the boat but as we all waited for the lock to fill, several more young people gradually emerged, buttoning up their clothes, or eating cereal, or cleaning their teeth…. Obviously two of the crew were much too impatient to wait for the others to be ready. We shared the locks with them until they turned around just before Hungerford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch and a quick look around the town we teamed up with another boat, 'First Light', owned by Colin and Julie who are on the same adventure as us! This is the first couple we have met that are continuous cruisers planning to complete the whole network. Obviously we had a lot to chat about. Our first encounter together was a collapsed swing bridge, crawling with Canal &amp;amp; River Trust people rapidly repairing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, out of nowhere, Beckie and Buddy appeared! It was an amazing surprise. They were able to join us on board for a little while until we arrived at the bridge where Beckie had left her car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Great Bedwyn, First Light moored up and we said goodbye to Colin &amp;amp; Julie. We continued on to our mooring for the night, alongside a field of delightful pigs who ignored us completely. I briefly thought we had a very different neighbour in another field - a large kind of deer or elk. I was very excited! However, when it lifted it’s head, its antlers remained on the floor, now looking like a fallen branch. The strange creature was a donkey. I do like donkeys but it was still a bit of a disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4170988.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Surprise visitors!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After checking on the pigs, (fast asleep in a bundled heap in their cosy house), we set off through 10 locks and a tunnel. The tunnel was short and we were able to see a heron framed in the circle made by the far end of the tunnel and it’s reflection. It was a beautiful sight, gradually becoming closer and closer. Just as we were about to emerge from the tunnel I tried to take a photo of the heron but, of course, it flew away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Honeystreet and were able to moor up directly outside the Barge Inn. The perfect mooring! I have always wanted to moor there. Unfortunately the pub was closed for refurbishment. No wonder the mooring was available. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robin joined us there and, to make up for our disappointment at finding the pub closed, he drove us to another pub and bought us dinner. What made it even more delightful was the pub parrot. He didn’t speak to us at all on the way in, but as we left he clearly said&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Goodbye. Thankyou.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fabulous!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4181007.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Good luck Mrs Swan.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4181004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A very cute boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following morning we waited in Honeystreet for the Devizes to Westminster canoe race to pass by. We had no desire to get muddled up in that. Whilst we waited we all got some jobs done. Once it was clear, Robin drove off to park his car in Devizes and we set off in Liberty Belle. Robin cycled back along the towpath and met us at a swing bridge where he and his bike boarded Liberty Belle and we arrived in Devizes together where we met up with the Bradshaws and Julie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4191020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In the Vale of the White Horse, as you can see.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Julie &amp;amp; Robin as extra crew members we flew down the Caen Hill locks, fuelled by ice cream, tea &amp;amp; biscuits and lager, in that order. After a well deserved lunch, Robin and Julie each went on their way. We sat in the shade on the towpath and enjoyed a relaxing cuppa. Later Joe joined us on his way home from a road trip to Scotland and the Lakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4201041.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The boat shuffle.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4201061.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Still going after all those locks!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning Joe crewed with us for a while before returning to his van and heading home. We continued on to Bradford-on-Avon, where we shared the last lock with a hire boat. The boat was a long one and the stern of the boat was subjected to a lot of water spray whilst in the lock. Tony felt sorry for the woman at the helm and let her out of the lock first, despite the concern that she might take the best mooring space! Fortunately, her boat was too long to fit into the space we wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a stroll around Bradford-on-Avon we bumped into a woman from the boat we shared the Caen Hill locks with the day before, which was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4211068.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Hello Joe!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4211074.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Stepping over what used to be the Wilts &amp;amp; Berks canal.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4221077.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The very impressive 14th Century Tithe Barn (which may not have been used for tithes...) in Bradford-on-Avon.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4221083.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St Laurence's Church has a ribbon carved around two of its pillars.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short stay in the delightful Bradford-on-Avon we set off for Bath. The countryside was beautiful. There were lots of boats to see on the way, in varying states of repair (or dis-repair). We moored on the outskirts of Bath, just before Sydney gardens then went for a stroll to see if there were any other moorings available nearer the railway station. We were due to meet Mary off her train the next day. Having found what we wanted, we had a quick look around Bath and decided we like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4231103.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This part of the canal has escape steps for wildlife at regular intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4231088.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This boat is more solar panel than viable boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4231105.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The beautiful Dundas Aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4231123.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well done Mrs Duck, keep them safe.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n43/P4231118.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Gongoozler &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Woolhampton to Bath 16th - 23rd April 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Kennet &amp;amp; Avon Canal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/04/23/welcome-to-the-kennet-and-avon-canal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Kennet &amp; Avon Canal" /><published>2019-04-23T22:05:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T22:05:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/04/23/welcome-to-the-kennet-and-avon-canal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/04/23/welcome-to-the-kennet-and-avon-canal.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Banbury to Woolhampton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8th-15th April 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n42map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4100843.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Passing through Somerton Deep Lock again, this time with blooming Forsythia&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we returned to Liberty Belle, waiting for us in Banbury, we had plans....Reading by Friday, (to meet Robin and Julie), then Bath by Easter! Hahaha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we had to give Liberty Belle a service with the help of Bill the Engineer. This took flippin’ hours but a proper job was done. So, later than expected, at 14:30, we left Banbury and tried to get to Aynho Wharf for fuel before they closed.... It was slow going, especially when we tried to fill Aynho Weir Lock. The previous users had left one of the paddles up slightly, allowing the lock to leak and preventing it from filling completely.... Grrr...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were nearly there, hoping that they would still be open at 18:00 when we were likely to arrive, when we met a chap that informed us that they closed at 15:30 at this time of year. Oh flip! We now had to moor there overnight so that we could refuel when they opened at 9 am. This meant that we hadn’t done as many miles as we had hoped and we wouldn’t get the early start we needed the next day. Already things were not going to plan....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this set back, the revised plan is to get to Oxford by Friday, which is far more achievable.
Once we had a tank full of fuel we set off from Aynho. As we were coming into Somerton Tony noticed someone walking along the towpath towards us who looked like Neil and walked like Neil. It turned out to BE Neil! It seems he wasn't in Spain, as we had thought! Once we had managed to get him on board and found a mooring space we stopped for a cuppa and a slice of cake, kindly provided by our surprise guest. It was only a short visit as he was on his way North. He left us with the remains of the cake and walked the few yards back to his car. (We had finished the cake before he drove off....)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the day we had a slightly traumatic experience when coming alongside the towpath to let me off for a lock. We almost trapped a duck and her ducklings! Mother duck knew to race along to the rear of the boat but the ducklings swam in confused circles with Liberty Belle giving them less and less room! Mother duck was quacking and encouraging them to follow her and they where chirping and darting about in all directions! At the last minute Mother duck managed to get her message across and all were safe... Phew.
We collected water from Thrupp and moored there for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4100848.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Don't forget me!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On leaving Thrupp  it was an easy trip into Oxford where we found a mooring quite near the Isis lock, the last one before the Thames. We went for a look around Oxford then cooked a curry ready for the weekend visitors. In the evening we went for a short walk in the hope of seeing some otters but were not in luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4110849.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;If you have too much stuff in your boat, add another boat!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4110857.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Donkey field squeezed between the canal &amp;amp; railway line, underneath the motorway. How relaxing for them...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4110859.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A raft used to monitor otter population. How exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the boat ready for our guests we went into Oxford for a snack in the Handlebar Cafe, which was delightful, then a look around the fascinating and utterly wonderful Pitt Rivers museum. Neil popped by to see us again on his way back South and we all went to collect Julie &amp;amp; Robin from the station before heading to Wetherspoons (Four Candles) for a meal. Robin had misunderstood the situation, thinking we would be travelling from Oxford to Reading in one day and had only paid for his car to stay in the Reading car park for 24 hours, so we spent some time downloading an App that would enable him to pay remotely for an extra day’s parking. Julie was trapped for a day longer than she had planned...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neil headed back to his car and the rest of us started our weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began Saturday with a big breakfast and then set off onto the Thames. The river was not as wide there as we had anticipated, nor as busy. There were, however, a lot of rowing boats, which we somehow managed to avoid. All the locks were operated by push-button controls and most of them were manned by lock-keepers, so the going was easy. We completed about half of the trip between Oxford and Reading before mooring for the night alongside a slightly rough river's edge with trees and nettles at Shillingford bridge. We avoided the moorings next to the bridge as they were very smart and bound to be pricey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4130001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leaving Oxford.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4130006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Plenty of room for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4130860.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Most of Robin is indoors, out of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/IMG_20190413_192503_928.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our beautiful mooring space that we initially assumed was free...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early on Sunday morning, we began to suspect that our mooring place wasn’t free, as we had assumed, so we left hastily before someone charged us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we turned the corner, leaving the River Thames at Reading, I seem to remember seeing a friendly sign saying &quot;Welcome to the Kennet and Avon Canal&quot;.... Hmmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The water was shallow and we struggled to manoeuvre. When we found somewhere to stop, to allow Robin &amp;amp; Julie to disembark, there was a sign with rather small writing. Having tied Liberty Belle up, we approached the sign and managed to read that, by stopping there, we now owed the 'up to 4 hours' fee of £4. If we stayed overnight we would owe £9:50. We were also informed that we had now been caught on CCTV and a failure to pay would result in a fine of £100. These moorings are owned by the council, offer no facilities except mooring rings and are not even secure. Robin and Julie disembarked and headed for Robin’s car whilst we moved Liberty Belle on with Tony muttering &quot;Just let them try...&quot; and immediately getting grounded on the corner. A bit of to-and-fro, back-and-forth and we were free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We travelled through the centre of Reading (no moorings here at all) before coming to a narrow stretch where traffic lights were in use to prevent boats from meeting head on. Boaters are expected to press a button, pedestrian crossing style, on the right hand side of the canal and wait up to 12 minutes for a green light. There is nowhere to tie up, nowhere to allow a crew member to step off the boat, so Tony had to try and swing Liberty Belle within reach of the button with me leaning over to press it. The light went green straight away so we avoided having to decide how to stay put for up to 12 minutes....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought this was tricky but it was nothing compared to the next 2 locks. Liberty Belle had to choose between obeying Tony and being swept away by the river rushing past the lock. Luckily, Tony won. If there had been any rain recently, the ending may have been different. We helped ourselves to a map of the Kennet and Avon, chuckling at the obvious error on the map. There was a symbol in the map’s key for mooring and it hadn’t been used on the map until Bath. Not so funny really, as it turned out… In reality, there are mooring spaces, but they are generally few and far between. If you want to stop alongside the towpath, which we have done many times on other canals, you risk coming aground before you are close enough to jump off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the second lock, where the river gives way to the man made canal, the mooring posts were well ahead of the lock due to the river rushing around and in front of the lock gates. The strong wind pushed us against the mooring which was handy for me to get off but tricky for Tony to get away and pick up enough speed to get through the river flow and into the lock. Once in, the flow of the water when the lock was filling was so crazy that I could only open the paddle a tiny amount before it got too tricky to control the boat. Unfortunately the water was leaking out of the bottom gates almost as quickly as it was flowing in through the paddle. Slowly Liberty Belle began to rise but became out of control so I dropped the paddle  to allow Tony to get control again. The filling of this lock took ages and it was all very stressful. &quot;Welcome to the Kennet and Avon&quot;. Yeah, right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of the lock was a different world of calm. Finally we were able to leave the lock and moor behind the other boats in the tranquil canal. We were exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4140893.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The crew&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4140883.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle looking tiny in one corner of a Thames lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4140908.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Going through Reading centre. &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4140898.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Just lean out and press the button, I will try to get as close as I can....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4140911.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Pull in alongside the short landing stage to let off your crew member then pull out again against the flow of the water....Thank goodness the water level is low!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4140916.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;When the lock gates are open just make a mad dash at the lock, trying not to let the water push you away...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the following day every lock had a nasty surprise and they were interspersed with lift bridges. Most of the bridges were electric, the traffic controlled by lights and barriers which are operated by buttons on a console. In order for the controls to work, a British Waterways Key needs to be turned in the keyhole and is only released when the bridge has been replaced. As we approached one particular bridge it became apparent that someone had already lifted it. The boat passing under the bridge had a single crew member so his key had been left in the control panel. Following him in quick succession were two other boats, each with a one-man crew. With a few shouted messages it became apparent that the helmsman of the third one was charged with retrieving the keys. He waited just beyond the bridge for us to pass under and for me to lower the bridge before he collected the key. It all went very smoothly. However, the van driver waiting for the bridge to be returned did not respond to my wave of thanks for being patient. Presumably because he wasn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about 4 o’clock we decided to give up finding a sensible place to moor for lunch and tie Liberty Belle to a couple of trees. I managed to jump from the bow onto a firm piece of land and wrap the rope around a tree as Tony nudged it with Liberty Belle's nose. Tony then brought the back end in and jumped, trusting that he would land with his feet on firm ground... He was just trying to secure the stern rope to the second tree when a passer by stopped and told us about some proper moorings just a few minutes away, beyond the next lock. I released the front and Tony returned the stern rope. Being a gentleman he allowed me to step aboard before him and got left behind on the towpath as Liberty Belle was swept to the other side of the river. I grabbed the tiller and managed to steer her back over without getting grounded... Golly.
By the time we had operated another lift bridge (with another impatient van driver) and charged Liberty Belle through the flow of the river across the front of the lock and through the lock gates, waited for the volunteers (bless their cotton socks) to refill the lock and release us, another hour had gone by. One of the lock keepers said he suspected that one of the moored boats at the top of the lock was about to leave and thus give us a space to moor. He went ahead of us and confirmed that this was the case. Thank you kind man! Phew. Lunch time at last!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: as we had lunch so late, we didn't have an evening meal. Tony has pointed out, on a regular basis ever since, that he has missed an entire meal.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4150921.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Monkey Marsh Lock, one of only two turf-sided locks in the country. It is listed as an ancient monument.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/P4150923.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A scalloped edge lock, the modern update to an old turf-sided lock.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n42/IMG-20190415-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The result of a particularly big bump entering a lock. The bookshelves are emptied onto the floor - I even found a CD inserted between the pages of a book...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">From Banbury to Woolhampton 8th-15th April 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Annnd They’re off!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/04/22/annnd-theyre-off.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Annnd They're off!!" /><published>2019-04-22T22:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T22:15:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/04/22/annnd-theyre-off</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/04/22/annnd-theyre-off.html">&lt;h2&gt;From Loughborough to Banbury&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18th March - 7th April 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear All, sorry we haven't been in touch lately, we have had long cruising days. At last we have had a break for a day, so I have found some time to catch up on newsletters...here's one for a month ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n41map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3200620.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It's another long day&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday 18th March, after walking around a lake in Loughborough, doing a spot of bird-watching, (coot, mallard, wigeon, tufted duck, gadwell and swans) we received an email from the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust informing us that the River Soar was now open. We could go! It was too late to set off straight away so we got ourselves ready to set off first thing in the morning. Meanwhile, Joe contacted us and we arranged to meet at the weekend at Napton junction, so there was no time to waste!
As soon as we set off our spirits lifted. We didn't even stop for tea breaks or lunch, making pots of tea and sandwiches as we 'sped' along!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3190579.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Canons directed at boats on the River Soar...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3210663.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A pair of heron.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a lock on the outskirts of Leicester we met two young lads magnet fishing who seemed delighted to see us, immediately abandoning their pastime for the new one of bombarding Tony and myself with questions!  Actually, there weren't many questions but each one was repeated many times. In their attempt to help us with the lock they managed to get in the way in every possible manner, giving me reason to be anxious by walking across the lock gates without holding on. I found myself trying to find several different ways to explain why one set of gates could open whilst those at the opposite end wouldn't, whilst Tony tried to explain how he managed without being on any kind of benefit, what a licence is and the concept of a pension. Finally, we managed to move out of the lock. As a parting gesture one of the young gentlemen asked if he could have a pound for helping, so I explained to him that he owed us far more than that for entertaining them, after which they quickly returned to their magnet fishing...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking 9 hours to travel 15 miles and complete 11 locks we arrived at the secure moorings to find no space there for us, so we chained &amp;amp; padlocked Liberty Belle to the towpath and settled ourselves down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3200604.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Sharing the water in Leicester with rowers and swans.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised along in this way for the next couple days, admiring the blackthorn blossom, the fresh hawthorn leaves, the cheerful celandine and violet flowers. Spring is definitely on its way, we even saw a pair of kingfishers and a pair of heron! There were also a few more boats around now that the season was changing.
We arrived back at the bottom of the Foxton flight of locks where Tony went to arrange our passage up whilst I gave some Australians a tour of Liberty Belle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When our turn came, I took the helm and Tony did the locking. He didn't have much help from the volunteer lock keepers as they were busy trying to fish an American boater's mobile phone out from one of the top locks...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3210637.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Steering Liberty Belle into the bottom lock at Foxton,&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3210645.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Making our way to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3220670.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Do you remember me mentioning the elm trees planted alongside the canal as 'Living Milestones' in a previous newsletter? Well, I remembered to take a photo of a marker put in the place of one of the trees. Not a thing of beauty in itself....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we arrived at the Watford flight of Locks where we were also allowed to make our way down without supervision. We obviously look the part now. Oh Heck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3220726.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Half way down the Watford Locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3220724.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside one of the locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Norton junction on Friday afternoon, ready to meet up with Joe with his new purchase, ‘Suzanne the Nissan van’. We spent the weekend helping him with the conversion of Suzanne into a camper - insulation, leisure battery, pull-out bed….all sorts! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/IMG_20190324_164751.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony making use of the lock arm when cutting bed slats.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/IMG_20190324_153735.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A well earned tea break.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe left us on Sunday evening, after a very busy weekend, but we arranged to meet him back at the house on the following Thursday, to carry on the good work with Suzanne. First we had to get Liberty Belle to a 14 day mooring in Banbury (again), so we spent the next few days getting there as fast as we could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first evening we decided to moor up in Napton near The Folly, so that we could go into this excellent pub for an evening pint. We were disappointed to find it closed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n41/P3220706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A boat and its butty moored alongside each other. The butty doesn't have its own engine and is towed along, but it is steered separately with its own rudder.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to get into Banbury on the Wednesday, so we moored up and went back to the house a whole day early!
With Suzanne parked in our driveway we continued to work on her for a week or so, in preparation for Joe and Kirsty to take her to Scotland. Oh, and we did some very urgent gardening…!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">From Loughborough to Banbury 18th March - 7th April 2019</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning to Love Loughborough</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/17/learning-to-love-loughborough.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning to Love Loughborough" /><published>2019-03-17T16:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-17T16:40:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/17/learning-to-love-loughborough</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/17/learning-to-love-loughborough.html">&lt;h2&gt;Hanging Around Again!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;6th - 16th March 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n40map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG_20190307_091124882.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle being dwarfed by a working boat.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle being dwarfed by a working boat.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It soon became apparent that the weather wasn't going to improve any time soon. As the days went by the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust closed the River Trent in front of us and the River Soar behind, because of high water. Oh... We were stuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3100562.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The River Soar is in Flood!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The River Soar is in Flood!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next couple of days we explored Loughborough, the birthplace of Ladybird Books (oh yes indeedy). We shared our time between Wetherspoons, the excellent (and free) museum, the well stocked aviary, the shops and the launderette.  We began to be concerned about our water running out so we decided to move around the corner into the wharf. We carefully picked our time to avoid the worst of the wind and rain. The rain fell in stair rods and the wind prevented us from mooring alongside the tap. We gave up and moored against the pontoon (with some difficulty) and hung all our wet clothes around the boat with towels beneath to catch the worst of the drips! The next day we were more successful, managing to collect water and re-moor without any trouble. Whilst waiting for the water tank to fill Tony used his fishing net to collect all the rubbish floating around in the wharf and binned it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG-20190312-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Moored in Loughborough Wharf&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Moored in Loughborough Wharf&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were now in a mooring spot restricted to 24 hours but:-

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;most of the facilities supposedly on offer were in fact out of order (toilets, elsan &amp;amp; showers)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;we couldn't travel due to rising water levels&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;No-one else was moored here or likely to arrive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3050517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Loughborough's beautiful Carnegie library. There is a modern extension for the main library and the old part is for the children.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG_20190307_131539.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the children's library. This photo gives you a little glimpse of an absolutely beautiful room.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3050514.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I am so fond of this statue. I have never been fond of a statue before. He is delightful. He is wearing and admiring a single sock. (In case you are worried, he also has a strategically placed fig leaf.) Bless him!.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG_20190312_174420.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Two of the three carved stone balls at the wharf. I like these too. The one in the foreground has a single sock carved into it. They really love their socks here, it's such a shame they don't seem to have a matching pair&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3060522.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Guess what this huge mould was used for!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3050520.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well done Loughborough, this is what you call a war memorial! It is 46 metres tall and has a collection of 47 bells. It is open to the public but not until Easter. I wonder if we will still be here.....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we thought the Canal &amp;amp; River Trust would probably leave us in peace.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile we are running out of coal and, as we can't travel to any marinas, have no chance of getting any more. Access to elsan points is also impossible (too much information?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we have been preserving our coal for the evenings and using public WC's (by that I mean in supermarkets, pubs and cafe's). This situation, of course, makes Wetherspoons and their bottomless top-ups (if that makes sense…)  invaluable! We are becoming very good at making the drinking of a single pint of beer fill the time available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Tony began to feel trapped. He was cheered only by sightings of the pet ferret being taken out on his daily walk and his regular trips (in the gaps in the weather) to the nearest lock to keep an eye on water levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3100560.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;On one of Tony's pilgrimages to the lock the water is at amber level - risky.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3140566.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The following day it is deeper, at red level - dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On one of the better days weather-wise we decided to go for a walk along the towpath to see where the canal joins the River Trent and Erewash Canal at Trent Lock. We planned to treat ourselves to a pub lunch there and then catch the train back to Loughborough. On the way we saw a whole field full of lapwings rising just above the ground, doing a few acrobatics then landing again. The towpath gradually and mysteriously morphed into a public footpath on the flood plain alongside the river. We boldly continued on our way until we reached the junction. Trent Lock was on the opposite side of the river to us and there was no bridge. We were stranded on the flood plain. How could this happen? What did the horses used to do when towing a boat? Swim across?
We were dismayed. We could either walk back the way we had come with no hope of lunch, or carry on following the footpath across the floodplain towards civilisation. So we carried on, moving further away from the river, across farmland, to a small country road which we followed under the railway and into the village of Sawley, situated not far from a railway station. We found three pubs, one of which belonged to an unappealing chain, one served very sad looking food, the third was selling excellent ale from its own brewery but no food other than crisps and nuts. What to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were so busy enjoying our beer (and very hot chilli bar snacks that actually made Tony cry) that we missed our first train. It had been a very close thing but 'a miss is as good as a mile'. Never mind, it wasn't a long wait for the next train and we were merry enough not to be too upset! We got back to the boat and had a slap-up curry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG-20190308-WA0000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These cooling towers watched over us for most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG-20190308-WA0006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lunch, of sorts...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now we were well into March. We had originally travelled up here to kill time whilst we waited for the lock in Reading to open on 15th. So we decided to abandon our plan of going to Nottingham and head back to Oxford as soon as the canals were open again. We would, of course, take Liberty Belle to Nottingham some other time but for now, to keep ourselves entertained, we decided to go there by train. Our journey was uneventful (except that we saw those blessed cooling towers again). We collected a tourist map from the information centre and started to follow it. It was so windy that our map was soon swept away so we went back for 2 more! It soon became apparent that Nottingham likes its tourists to pay for its attractions. Now, don't get me wrong, that is absolutely fair enough .... but we restricted ourselves to the free stuff.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/IMG-20190309-WA0001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony's world is turned upside-down by Nottingham's 'Sky Mirror' sculpture.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3090540.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Robin Hood firing above my head.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3090544.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony sitting at the base of Nottingham Castle&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3090552.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the fabulous porch of Nottingham's oldest church, St Mary the Virgin. Up close, the stone carved lion at the apex looks rather like a lap dog...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3090528.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The beautifully painted chapel in Nottingham's Catholic Cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n40/P3090536.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inside the same Cathedral showing what looks like the most richly decorated basket from a hot-air balloon dangling from the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the magical date of 15th March has come and gone. We are still here, in Loughborough, and Tony is still pacing up and down the towpath. Wetherspoons is an oasis for us. Not always an oasis of calm, due to the rugby, but we are not about to complain. The washing has been kept up to date, thanks to the launderette, some tinkering with DIY has been done and I have caught up with the Newsletters...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Hanging Around Again!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To Leicester and Beyond!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/16/to-leicester-and-beyond.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To Leicester and Beyond!" /><published>2019-03-16T11:11:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T11:11:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/16/to-leicester-and-beyond</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/16/to-leicester-and-beyond.html">&lt;h2&gt;Leicester to Loughborough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;1st - 6th March 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n39map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3010371.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bridges and swans on the approach to Leicester.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approached Leicester we had our first abuse from a fisherman! He was a young chap with a young woman hovering in the background. He had been pointing out the water coming from the lock as we descended and had settled himself on the bank with his fishing rod. Liberty Belle was eased out of the lock. I stepped onto the deck after closing the gates, looked over at the fisherman and smiled. In response he stood up and shouted at us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Don't you know you are supposed to slow down when you pass fishermen?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite us knowing that this isn't the case I simply pointed out that we couldn't go any slower without losing steering and he wouldn't want that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;I could report you!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony suggested that he should go ahead and do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Other people have been done you know!&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We shrugged at him and carried on.  I hope the young woman was impressed by his knowledge and bravado otherwise the whole event was a waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3020396.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leicester Cathedral by night.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3020388.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It is a small, neat, cheerful cathedral.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stayed in Leicester for the weekend at our secure mooring at the Castle Garden. There was a lot of interesting architecture both old and new. You can't move around the city without regularly coming across information boards about its history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visited the Cathedral where a very friendly curate, after inviting everyone to pause and join her in the Lords Prayer, smiled at me as we sat down then came and chatted to us about the cathedral, the different visitors they get there; the local rugby team colours; how she became a curate; her duties as curate; the funerals she had conducted... She made us feel very welcome and we liked her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ancient Guildhall, dating back to 1390, is beautiful and well worth a visit. It was due to be demolished in the 1920's because it had become dilapidated and was considered an eyesore but local historians thankfully stepped in and saved it, opening it as a museum in 1926.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local market was excellent, with lots of vibrant stalls. It is undercover and the wooden stalls are permanent. In the evenings a group of Sikhs hand out food to the homeless from one of the stalls, to the sound of loud and jolly music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the main street there are billboards which have free integrated phones (modern ones with no handsets), WiFi, phone charging ports and access to local information. (BT Inlink). What a wonderful resource. We saw a couple of homeless people using them but they were first brought to our attention when we encountered a very drunk man shouting abuse relating to his mother at a billboard one late afternoon.  Of course it turned out that he was actually talking to his mother on the phone. I'm not sure which is worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having looked them up on the Infi-net it seems they have been installed in lots of places around the country...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday evening we attended an event celebrating the life of local suffragette, Alice Hawkins, in the square that contains her statue. It was entertaining, educational and very moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found some disappointments in Leicester. The Jewry Wall Museum (part of the Roman town) was closed for refurbishment and the Richard III museum was exhausting. We felt that it was no different from reading a book about him except you had to stand throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3020392.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I cannot think of this chap without the accompanying Cockney rhyming slang. When I saw a local restaurant bearing his name, I couldn't help thinking that it was a bad move.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3020383.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Despite being named after me I wasn't invited to help myself from the stall. Rude.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3030428.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Jewry museum glimpsed through the Jewry wall, a Roman construction amazingly still standing tall.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3030422.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The inside of the Guildhall which was fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3030437.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An eye catching and rather beautiful modern building belonging to Leicester University.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/IMG-20190302-WA0002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leicester's own Statue of Liberty (no relation to Liberty Belle). A poor copy of the New York one, placed on top of Liberty shoe factory. When the factory closed, she was saved and put on a roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/IMG-20190302-WA0002-crop2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We can't help thinking that she must have looked better from a greater distance. If they had to save her, perhaps a taller pedestal would have been a good move...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Monday we set off despite strong winds. It was slow going as we encountered some very heavy lock gates and one lock full of rubbish that we needed to push clear with the boat hook before we could open it. We got Liberty Belle in there, shut the gates behind her and started to empty out the water through the bottom gates. We soon realised that the top gates weren't shut properly so the water was just passing through both sets of gates. We had to stop, let the lock refill completely, ease apart the top gates and clear the rubbish caught between them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This involved Tony being precariously balanced on the partly opened gates which were desperately trying to shut together whilst he wielded the boat hook to push the rubbish out of the way. That done, we started again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we left Leicester the river was lined with parkland, old factories, new housing and a wildlife park. We saw cormorants, a kingfisher, a little grebe, herons, an egret and a pair of Gadwell ducks (identified by Tony The Birdman).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the last lock of the day Tony couldn't bring Liberty Belle to the side due to the wind, so after closing the gates I was left stranded! There were no opportunities for me to be picked up for half a mile. Despite trying to travel slowly, Liberty Belle was being swept along in the flow of the river so I had trouble walking fast enough to keep up, particularly as I had styles to climb and a muddy track to contend with! She must have been going at a crazy 4 miles an hour! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we met at our nighttime mooring in Mountsorrel, just before the next lock. It was a fascinating little village with an ancient castle site and several sculptures done by a chap called Mike Grevatte.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3040456.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Old factory buildings&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3040464.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The rubbish waiting to be trapped between the lock gates&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3040461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An old chimney preserved within a modern housing estate.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3040467.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A modern building that looks like a giant chrysalis - it turned out to be the National Space Centre!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050477.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony mounted on the mount overlooking the village of Mountsorrel.
(Please note - he is not lounging on the monument which is specifically banned.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050476.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An elegant bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050485.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mountsorrel's buttermarket, built in 1793 to replace the medieval market cross.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050483.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony attempting to disarm Mike Grevatte's Earl of Pembroke.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050487.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;(In case of some mis-understanding, Black Bess was his horse.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050488.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony attempting to take Dick Turpin's place...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050489.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mike Grevatte's stone carving of a swan.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050493.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mike Grevatte's replica of Mountsorrel's medieval stone cross.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050482.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tony on the site of the Mountsorrel Castle, razed to the ground in the 13th century. I found this out on the infi-net - there was no information at all at the site. What a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n39/P3050486.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I have no idea why a ladder and a pair of crutches are being used as a trellis, but there they are.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day we travelled to Loughborough. On the way we saw loads of Canada Geese and some Greylags, a swan sitting bolt upright on a nest and our first ducklings (yay!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored up just outside Loughborough Wharf in a residential area. We decided to stay there to shelter from the high winds expected on the following day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Leicester to Loughborough</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back at the Start</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/13/back-at-the-start.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back at the Start" /><published>2019-03-13T16:36:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-13T16:36:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/13/back-at-the-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/13/back-at-the-start.html">&lt;h2&gt;Watford Locks to Leicester&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;25th February - 1st March 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n38map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route - we went for miles!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2240136.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The flight of locks at Watford where I found mussel shells cast aside at the edge of the reservoir.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The flight of locks at Watford where I found mussel shells cast aside at the edge of the reservoir.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main plan is now to get to Bath for Easter. This involves getting through Reading and onto the Kennet and Avon canal.  One of the locks in Reading is closed until the 15th March so we had time to kill and planned to spend it going to Nottingham along the Leicester Arm of the Grand Onion and then back via Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I am writing this newsletter, the plan has been forced to change - but more of that another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way we passed through Crick tunnel, the first bit of canal we had done when we picked up Liberty Belle and began our adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250164.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The inside of the tunnel is covered in mineral deposits from the water that has been running down the walls for 200 years.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250142.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I don't think the childcare is being fairly shared...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250149.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Suddenly sheep were pouring over the hill and galloping towards the canal, bleating loudly. Does their breakfast usually arrive by barge?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then passed the Crick Marina where Tony had first seen Liberty Belle.
We planned to cover the whole canal network in 2 years. We are now 1/4 of the way through that time, back at our starting point and we have barely covered any of it...
At least now we were covering new ground (or water...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelling along the gently winding canal, lined with blackthorn blossom, we passed through fields of sheep with their young lambs (quite noisy), then through cow country (quite smelly), followed by ploughed fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped off at Yelvertoft village on our way to have a look around. We checked out the church and found the village shop which had a miserable shopkeeper and a miserable selection of goods. Further along the road we discovered the village butchers and went in. What a contrast to the general store! Well stocked with all kinds of interesting store-cupboard items, cakes &amp;amp; biscuits, fresh fruit &amp;amp; veg, cheeses, oh, and meat products. The owner, despite currently teaching a sausage-making course, and the shop being officially closed, was welcoming and chatty. As well as him being entertaining, his sausages turned out to be excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250201.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These signs usually show all that is available in the village. We have contibuted the boat at the bottom, so not that hopeful!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;6&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Well, that was not on the sign!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;But that was!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250198.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;8&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fancy!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250194.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;9&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;These built in seats (sedilia), have very worn stone posts, presumably the people usually seated there had rough sleeves and were extremely fidgety.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250197.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Welcome notice in the church which suggests visitors help themselves to tea, coffee or squash! We didn't but it was very nice to have the option.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250205.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;11&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Squisito, a most excellent butcher's shop.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2250204.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;12&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Squisito's butcher teaching chefs to make sausages.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having studied our route in detail we decided there would be enough time to divert down the Welford Arm, an offshoot of the Leicester Arm, which terminates at Welford. It was sunny and the canal was pretty. We arrived that evening at a pleasant wharf. We explored the interesting little village the next morning before returning to the main canal. Whilst we were there we learnt that, in this area, the canal used to have elm trees spaced out along the edge as milestones. This explained the cast metal signs we had seen along the canal which claimed to be 'living milestones'. They had been placed there by a volunteer group to mark the site of each of these trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2260254.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;13&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We came from Norton Junction, skipped up the Welford Arm and now head for Foxton! In a nutshell!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had another tunnel to negotiate on our way to Foxton, at Husband's Bosworth. I really should have bet Tony that he would hit the side, because I would have done rather well out of it! Part way through the tunnel we met a boat coming towards us. Along his side of the tunnel was a strip of wood put there to protect the tunnel from boats and boats from the side of the tunnel. On our side there was just bare tunnel wall. We didn't realise this until the other boat didn't give us enough room and we were forced against the side. There was a horrible graunching noise and Liberty Belle left some of her paint on the tunnel and the tunnel left some damp, chewed debris on her stern. The other boater shouted a cheery 'sorry' over his shoulder as we passed. Hmmmm...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last we were at the famous Foxton Locks where there are two sets of 5 interconnecting locks that take the boats down a very steep hill. Arriving there in February we were extremely lucky to have a warm sunny day with excellent views across the miles of countryside in front of us. As the weather was so lovely there were lots of people around admiring the views, the locks and the boats, each one, it seemed, enjoying an ice cream. By the time we got to the bottom of the hill we felt we deserved an ice cream ourselves, so Tony managed to manoeuvre Liberty Belle into a position to drop me off outside the shop and then negotiate the sharp corner whilst eating a Magnum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2260264.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;14&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Lock winder's view at Foxton locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2260269.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;15&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Helmsman's view.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sharp corner took us along another diversion to Market Harborough. This part of the journey brought us kingfishers and a very difficult swing bridge. The bloomin' thing nearly beat me, it was so heavy! Luckily another woman happened to come along and joined me in the final push to re-engage it. (It crossed my mind that I might let Tony have a turn on the way back...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2260283.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;16&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The very awkward and heavy swingbridge.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked Market Harborough, especially its free museum (in an old corset factory) and its ice cream shop, Gallone's, selling proper ice cream in a cone with lots of tempting flavours to choose from...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2270294.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;17&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Market Harborough's St. Dionysis Church&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2270288.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;18&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One of the ceiling bosses in the church, dating from 1470's. Some others have been lost to death-watch beetle damage.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2270292.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;19&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Market Harborough's grammar school building with covered market place beneath, dating from 1614 and leaning man dating from 1957.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2270293.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;20&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Market Harborough's corset factory building - now the library and museum with excellent social history exhibits.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, back to the main canal at Foxton, (Tony moved the swing bridge this time), through a length of canal which formed part of a Site of Special Scientific Interest. Another tunnel to negotiate....phew, no incidents to report!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a day of stressful double locks, we stopped for a lunch break and watched some rooks making nests in the trees opposite us. One of the rooks was seen to take twigs from one, well formed nest and add them to his meagre effort! Cheeky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robin joined us for a quick lunchtime cuppa then we went on to continue with our double locks, a total of 12 for that day. Our mooring for that night was Kilby Bridge, a scruffy little place. We didn't have the energy to explore but it wasn't very tempting anyway. We left first thing in the morning and completed another 12 locks to reach Leicester before the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P2280339.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;21&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Rainy day locking.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P3010363.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;22&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Inner city canals....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P3010364.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;23&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;....a different sort of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P3010368.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;24&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Weir letting water into the river beside the last lock before Leicester.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P3010369.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;25&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The last lock before Leicester.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n38/P3020375.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;26&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Leicester secure mooring at Castle Gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Watford Locks to Leicester</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Three Counties Tour</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/07/three-counties-tour.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Three Counties Tour" /><published>2019-03-07T20:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-07T20:39:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/07/three-counties-tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/03/07/three-counties-tour.html">&lt;h2&gt;Claydon to Watford Locks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;18th-24th February 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n37map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1853.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fenny Compton's Transparent Tunnel&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Fenny Compton's Transparent Tunnel&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1844.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Claydon Bottom Lock&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Claydon Bottom Lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chugged along for the next few days, when it wasn't too windy. Being half term, there were a few hire boats out and about so the canals were a bit busier than they have been of late. On one sharp corner we met three boats coming towards us so we stopped to allow them past. One of them was a hire boat with a family on board and they unfortunately steered too close to the edge and became grounded on the outside of the bend. The 'Dad' of the group moved to the bow with the barge pole to try and push it out of trouble. The boat did indeed get out of trouble but 'Dad' was suddenly on the boggy, eroded edge of the canal, soaked to the knees with the barge pole in hand and his glasses a few feet in front of him in mud! Oops! Luckily he saw the funny side and was able to clamber back onto the boat which cruised away around the corner... Needless to say his family found the whole thing hilarious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw plenty of wildlife including reed buntings, Canada geese and the occasional kingfisher. We managed to startle a muntjac deer asleep at the edge of a field next to the canal. He shot across the field at great speed in what seemed an over-dramatic fashion. Later we had a similar effect on a partridge...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began to see (and hear) lambs in the fields around us as we passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course we made time to visit a few villages on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Claydon  is the most northerly Oxfordshire village. It has an unusual church and 'brown stone' houses which look like they are made of biscuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/P2180024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;St James the Great in Claydon&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St James the Great in Claydon&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then into Warwickshire and more houses made of biscuits in Priors Hardwick, Priors Marston and Marston Doles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1859.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A stone carving of a winged beast biting a coiled snake in St Mary's Church, Priors Hardwick&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A stone carving of a winged beast biting a coiled snake in St Mary's Church, Priors Hardwick&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1861.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Where the good folk of Priors Hardwick gather to sharpen their arrow heads...&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Where the good folk of Priors Hardwick gather to sharpen their arrow heads...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1884.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This document shows the wording on a monument from the 1700's within St Leonard's Church in Priors Marston which references the speed of light.
The velocity of light from the sun is about 11473500 miles in one minute of time.
How amazing is that?&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This document shows the wording on a monument from the 1700's within St Leonard's Church in Priors Marston which references the speed of light.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;&quot;The velocity of light from the sun is about 11473500 miles in one minute of time&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;How amazing is that?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still in Warwickshire, we arrived at Napton-on-the-Hill, which brought back memories of our sofa bed delivery! We made sure we visited their excellent village shop/cafe and, of course, The Folly Inn before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/P2220052.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Folly Inn, Napton-on-the-Hill. Just what you want canal-side pubs to be and rarely are.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Folly Inn, Napton-on-the-Hill. Just what you want canal-side pubs to be and rarely are.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/P2220067.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The three bridges at the junction in Braunston.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The three bridges at the junction in Braunston.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Friday we had reached Braunston, which is in Northamptonshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time we were here is was raining, so it was good to see the village in the nice weather, although we have been told that the water levels are already low, so the canals will be struggling by Easter. Uh Oh...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robin joined us there on Saturday lunchtime. We stashed his bike in the front of the boat then, after eating, set off with Robin steering and Tony &amp;amp; myself working the locks. We went through Braunston tunnel which is over a mile long. Tony was confident that Robin wouldn't be able to steer the whole length without incident, especially as it isn't straight, so he bet him a pint of beer that he wouldn't be able to get through the tunnel without bashing into the sides. Twenty minutes or so later, Liberty Belle came out unscathed, despite Tony's underhand tactics, distracting Robin and shining lights into his eyes. (Maybe it had something to do with Tony having fixed the front light so that it now points forwards...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it turned out that we had to go out that evening in Norton Junction, to present Robin with his due! We went to the pub where drinkers had stood watching us nearly sinking Liberty Belle back in August...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1894.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robin keeping one eye closed as we approach the tunnel to give him an advantage in the dark...&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Robin keeping one eye closed as we approach the tunnel to give him an advantage in the dark...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1901.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A boat emerging from the Braunston tunnel.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A boat emerging from the Braunston tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/P2230083.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Robin at the helm.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Robin at the helm.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/P2240099.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Everything stops for tea!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Everything stops for tea!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday brought a flight of locks at Watford. I took the helm whilst Tony &amp;amp; Robin worked the locks with the volunteer lock keepers. I made a hash of getting into one of the locks. The lockeeper reassured me that &quot;we've all made a hash of getting into that lock in our time&quot;. I watched the boat behind and they didn't have any trouble at all! I suppose it is wrong to hope that someone makes mistakes and bashes their boat....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moored up before the Crick tunnel and Robin cycled back to where he had left his car. What a lovely weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/DSCN1909.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flight of locks.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Flight of locks.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n37/P2240110.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My excuse is that the angle the boats must come out of the previous lock is all wrong....&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;My excuse is that the angle the boats must come out of the previous lock is all wrong....&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Claydon to Watford Locks</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Banbury? Again?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/02/24/banbury-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Banbury? Again?" /><published>2019-02-24T17:52:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-24T17:52:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/02/24/banbury-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/02/24/banbury-again.html">&lt;h2&gt;Aynho, back to Banbury then forward to Cropredy, repeatedly!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;28th January-18th February 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n36map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we cruised closer, we could smell Banbury on the air!

&lt;p&gt;Banbury has several factories - Fine Lady Bakery, Jacobs (of cracker fame), Dowe Egberts amongst others. The combined smell from all of these is quite distinctive but unidentifiable. I think it smells of burnt molasses, Tony likens it to burnt jacket potato skins and Joe can pick out the coffee aroma. Depending on the wind strength and direction this smell can follow the canal for miles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had arrived a few days ahead of schedule but the precaution proved necessary as the canal did indeed re-freeze.
We had noticed some signs for the 'Banbury Fringe Walk' near the boat so we decided to investigate. It took us on a circular route through the countryside surrounding Banbury, including the village of Bodicote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1794.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A wide, shallow lock...1&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A wide, shallow lock...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1805.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;...and a deep, narrow lock&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...and a deep, narrow lock&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1814.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bodicote Church.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Bodicote Church.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1813.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An unusually pretty entrance to the church tower.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An unusually pretty entrance to the church tower.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left Liberty Belle in Banbury for a few days as we needed to get home for a family get-together to celebrate my Mum’s birthday. After a successful celebration - eating, drinking and catching up, we returned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the canal was again frozen we assumed that the ground would also be solid, so we thought we could go on a short country walk without fear of getting too muddy. How wrong we were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off thinking we would be back for lunch. Four and a half hours later my head ached, my feet ached and every muscle in between. Our lunch had been a shared packet of chilli coated peanuts in the porch of a church. We had walked across fields with mud so deep we had nearly lost our boots on several occasions. Being fed up with that we had taken a slightly different route along an old railway. This wide route soon became rough ground with fallen trees to clamber over. Finally, to descend to the road we had to scramble down a bramble covered bank then under a fence, booby trapped with barbed wire, into busy traffic. We sidled along behind the crash barrier until we rejoined the path. Finally we made it into Banbury via an industrial estate and confusing residential road network. I was so pleased to see Liberty Belle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1815.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One at a time, please!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;One at a time, please!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/P2050011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oh, Peter Rabbit, what have you done to deserve that?&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Oh, Peter Rabbit, what have you done to deserve that?&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/P2050005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;St Mary's in Warkworth - locked.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;St Mary's in Warkworth - locked.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/P2050006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An interesting 'guttering gargoyle'. (If that wasn't a term before, it is now.)&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An interesting 'guttering gargoyle'. (If that wasn't a term before, it is now.)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/P2050008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All Saints Church in Middleton Cheyney - locked&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;All Saints Church in Middleton Cheyney - locked&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/P2050012.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Glorious mud!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Glorious mud!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice had disappeared from the canal and, needing water, we moved the few yards up to the water tap which turned out not to be in working order. The next step was a lock which was full of dumped newspapers, piles of them. Tony used the boat hook to remove the paper to the lock edge whilst I and a helpful gentleman transported the heavy, dripping mess to the bins a few yards away. Just beyond the lock was a second tap which was, thankfully, working.  We filled up the water tank, passed under the lift bridge and moored up without further incident. The few hundred yards between moorings took an hour and a half....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1817.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the tap.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At the tap.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the rest of the week in the centre of Banbury then left Liberty Belle alone again whilst we went off to Stafford for the weekend. Tony attended a two day boat engineering course there and I did a bit of sightseeing. I liked Stafford. It has a small but very interesting (and free) museum; a pleasant public park with an aviary; a modern library with comfy(ish) seats and local history books; a handsome church which has regular Saturday concerts (also free); a rather delightful Wetherspoons in an old cinema (with the traditional free WiFi and free hot drinks top-ups); and friendly locals. What more could I want??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1820.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A street in Stafford with St Mary's Church in the background.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A street in Stafford with St Mary's Church in the background.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1828.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of Victoria Park.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A view of Victoria Park.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our return Tony was suddenly concerned about the welfare of Liberty Belle’s engine and started frantically trying to purchase essential bits and bobs. It was amazing how difficult it was to buy parts for boat engines in an area full of boats. Resorting in the end to ordering the engine oil he needed on Amazon, Tony had it delivered to an Amazon locker. What an excellent resource! The filters he needed were purchased locally. One of them, despite reassurances that it was compatible, wasn’t, so had to be returned after several attempts to attach the blessed thing. In this manner several days went by...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n36/DSCN1829.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dipstick! The give-away neatly pressed new overalls!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Dipstick! The give-away neatly pressed new overalls!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Tony had finished giving Liberty Belle's engine a well-earned spruce up we left Banbury for Cropedy. We moored up there for lunch and I spent the afternoon preparing for our much-anticipated visitors arriving over the next 2 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the weekend showing off Liberty Belle to our guests and travelling up and down a couple of miles of canal. We showed them how to steer and work the locks. Great fun and no accidents!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Monday morning we took Liberty Belle back along the now well known stretch of canal and beyond - heading in the general direction of Nottingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days we noticed that nature was looking ahead to spring. We saw a tiny, isolated patch of new hawthorn leaves; a little willow twig with tiny 'pussy-cat' paws; a single butterfly (I am tempted to say it was a Painted Lady, but don't quote me); and a rook carrying a twig. The rook didn't seem to know where to put this twig as he flew around in an undecided sort of way with it in his beak. Maybe he was new to this and felt the urge to collect twigs but wasn't yet sure why...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it is still jolly cold and we are still using coal at an alarming rate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Aynho, back to Banbury then forward to Cropredy, repeatedly!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ice-Breaker Belle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/02/17/ice-breaker-belle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ice-Breaker Belle" /><published>2019-02-17T19:42:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T19:42:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/02/17/ice-breaker-belle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/libertybellenewsletter/2019/02/17/ice-breaker-belle.html">&lt;h2&gt;Thrupp to Aynho&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23rd-27th January 2019&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/maps/n35map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our route&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Our route&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The snow was followed by a warmer, sunny day. We decided to walk to Kidlington again to investigate the church. The ground was still frozen so there was much less mud to contend with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1665.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Frozen ground in the sunshine&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Frozen ground in the sunshine&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1684.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kidlington Church&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Kidlington Church&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1667.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking as if it was carved yesterday.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Looking as if it was carved yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1670.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medieval window, painstakingly put back together from a jumble of pieces in 1951.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Medieval window, painstakingly put back together from a jumble of pieces in 1951.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1672.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The two oldest sections of the medieval window. King 1 and...&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The two oldest sections of the medieval window. King 1 and...&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1671.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;...King 2&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...King 2&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1668.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I do like a Rood screen.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I do like a Rood screen.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1674.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Possibly more than that, I do like to find the Green Man.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Possibly more than that, I do like to find the Green Man.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1677.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carved for the illiterate! Kidlington: Kid - goat, Ling - fish, Ton - wool sack&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Carved for the illiterate!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kidlington:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kid - goat&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ling - fish&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ton - wool sack&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1685.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A piece of the old, multi-tier pulpit from Kidlington Church being used as decoration over the door of one of the houses nearby. Waste not, want not!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A piece of the old, multi-tier pulpit from Kidlington Church being used as decoration over the door of one of the houses nearby. Waste not, want not!
&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following day we woke up to a frozen canal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to move on to get water and to make our way back to Banbury for a car hire at the beginning of February. Setting off from the mooring between boats was tricky as Liberty Belle does't like to travel sideways against ice. The lift bridge needed 2 attempts to open as it was frozen in place then the tap had to be defrosted, so things were off to a slow start. Then of course Liberty Belle had to break the ice as she went along. This made steering very tricky as she preferred to follow the line of the cracks she made rather than obey Tony’s steering. It was exciting though, smashing the ice into massive sheets and watching them slide over each other as we pushed them into the sides of the canal. The ice vibrated as we smashed our way through, making the light dance on the surface. The plants at the edge of the canal shivered violently as the ice sheets crunched into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1691.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Liberty Belle - Icebreaker!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Liberty Belle - Icebreaker!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped for lunch just before Pigeons lock. Another boat was in front of us so it would be a while before we could go through, and it was lunchtime. Over lunch we discussed our afternoon plan and decided not to do any more cruising that day. Steering Liberty Belle through the ice was hard work. I could have taken over from Tony to give him a rest but, to be honest, he would have to be on hand in case I got into difficulty so it would be just as stressful for him if not more so! By the time we had cooked and eaten we were half way through the afternoon anyway and would be in danger of trying to moor up in the dark.
So, we went for a walk instead to have a quick look at the nearby village of Tackley. According to the guide book it had just a church and a school, but a church is always worth a look. Tackley proved to be another delightful honey-coloured Oxfordshire village with a manorial estate and large farm buildings. The church was lovely and will need further investigation when we have more time, especially as it has an excellent exhibition detailing the history of the village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also pleasantly surprised to find a pub (no time for that!) and a village community shop which was exceptionally well stocked. Having tramped mud through the shop we felt obliged to buy something, so we purchased a large homemade fruit cake... that'll do nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1697.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tackley Church&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tackley Church&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1701.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A very pretty window.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A very pretty window.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1700.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tackley Church from the Rood Screen&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Tackley Church from the Rood Screen&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1698.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Rood Screen5&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Rood Screen&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1704.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A marvel of a find - they had good cake!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A marvel of a find - they had good cake!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1705.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;...amongst other things&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;...amongst other things&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up and off after breakfast the next morning. The canal was no longer frozen solid. I had a strained muscle in my back so Tony volunteered to do the locks and I took the helm. It made a pleasant change to swap duties. The day started as calm, grey and overcast but the conditions allowed us to see the fish swimming in the canal. There are loads of them! I suppose all those kingfishers, herons, cormorants and fishermen can’t be there for nothing! We also spotted a single roe deer with small, velvet covered antlers walking beside the canal and another seven of them in a field. Sadly, later in the day we also saw a dead muntjac deer floating in the canal. Whilst quietly contemplating these things as we chugged along, a train, passing by on the track near the canal, hooted it’s horn. The driver waved to us enthusiastically. Tony cheerfully waved back but I was too busy trying to push my heart back into my chest. During the day we came across some patches of canal which were still iced over but this didn't really prove to be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did catch up with the boat that had been in front of us the day before and he said he'd been living on board a narrowboat for 6 years and he had only just realised that you aren't supposed to travel when the canal is iced over as you are in danger of scratching the paint on your own and other people's boats. Oh. That would explain the black look we had had from one woman leaning out of the hatch from her moored boat. Oops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Proof, if proof were needed, that aliens have been landing in this area.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Proof, if proof were needed, that aliens have been landing in this area.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1712.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carrying on as normal, as if there were no aliens.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Carrying on as normal, as if there were no aliens.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next few days we did a bit of cruising when the weather was suitable, trying to get to Banbury before the canal re-froze. When the wind was too strong for cruising we filled in our time walking. Along the way we investigated:-
Somerton, another ancient and beautiful church in a pretty village with thatched stone houses;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Souldern, a pretty stone village with lots of footpaths, a Church and a pub;
Deddington, again.This time we set off with the whole day ahead of us so there was no danger of running out of daylight. However, we still didn't get to see the inside of the church as there was a Sunday service being held. We did delay our visit by going to the local hotel for tea and cake but managed to mis-time it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1719.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;How far off course are we???&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;How far off course are we???&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1759.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Phew, right on track.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Phew, right on track.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1717.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Somerton mooring&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Somerton mooring&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1748.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Somerton church&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Somerton church.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1728.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An impressive medieval 'Reredos' of The Last Supper.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An impressive medieval 'Reredos' of The Last Supper.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1733.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The ancient church clock without a face, relying on chimes.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The ancient church clock without a face, relying on chimes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1739.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A door that we can only assume is very old indeed. It is still on it's hinges but is no longer in use. A more recent door has been hung on the other side of the door frame.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A door that we can only assume is very old indeed. It is still on it's hinges but is no longer in use. A more recent door has been hung on the other side of the door frame.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1740.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An impressively twisted cherry tree!&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;An impressively twisted cherry tree!&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1764.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Somerton Deep Lock. Climbing 12 feet in one go&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Somerton Deep Lock. Climbing 12 feet in one go&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1769.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chisnell Lift Bridge&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Chisnell Lift Bridge&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1777.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Souldern village pond. How beautiful.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Souldern village pond. How beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1787.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Souldern village safe box...??&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Souldern village safe box...??&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1785.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;What looks like a massive damp patch in Souldern Church is apparently a painting of St Christopher.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;What looks like a massive damp patch in Souldern Church is apparently a painting of St Christopher.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1779.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Souldern Church&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Souldern Church.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1789.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Doing our bit for the local economy by partaking of refreshment in the local hostelry.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Doing our bit for the local economy by partaking of refreshment in the local hostelry.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1788.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It looks like a coconut shy but wooden logs are involved. The score board suggests it it an inter-pub game.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It looks like a coconut shy but wooden logs are involved. The score board suggests it it an inter-pub game.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Deddington Hotel experience was farcical...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scene - a room in an old hotel with a counter, a few tables and comfortable chairs. Archways through to two similar rooms and a restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;xmp&gt;
Enter 2 muddy hikers, wrapped up against the cold wind and rain. They remove their boots at the entrance and approach the counter in front of them, obviously pleased to see the choice of teas, coffees and cakes. At one of the tables are two young couples with a toddler chatting and relaxed.

The two hikers look at the offerings on the counter and discuss them. They wander around a little and find a menu which they look at at length and discuss. They discuss the seating options, choose a table near the counter and sit down. They wait.

In bustles the Woman in Orange, straight to the young couples to explain that there has been a bit of a mix up with the staff “No-one was sure which job they were meant to be doing. Your drinks are being prepared now&quot;
Woman in Orange indicates Waitress 1 who has appeared behind the counter at the coffee machine, preparing drinks. Waitress 1 delivers the drinks to the table.

Hiker 1, addressing the woman in orange as she bustles back towards the kitchen. &quot;Do we need to go to the counter to be served or should we wait for table service?&quot;

Woman in Orange - “Aren’t you being served?”

Hikers (in unison) - “No” 

Woman in Orange darts behind the counter - &quot;What would you like to order?&quot;

Having had plenty of time to discuss this Hiker 1 orders immediately. Indicating a chalk board on the counter detailing the contents of a cream tea - &quot; One cream tea and a latte, please&quot;.

Woman in Orange - “I will see if we have any”  

Woman in orange disappears into the kitchen behind the counter returning promptly.

Woman in Orange - &quot;We don't do cream teas at this time of year. You can order anything off the breakfast menu.”

The two Hikers share a confused look and glance back at the board offering cream teas.

Hiker 2, already knowing the menu off by heart - &quot;I'll have a croissant then.&quot;

Hiker 1 - One tea, one latte and two croissants then, please&quot;

Woman in Orange - “I will see if we have any.”

Hikers exchange a look.

Woman in Orange darts into the kitchen again and returns promptly.

Woman in Orange - “Sorry, we don’t have any croissants, we usually have some left over from breakfast, but not today.”

Hikers look at each other in disbelief and return to the counter to look at the display of cakes, choose an item each and return to their seats.

Woman in Orange plates up the cakes and delivers them to the waiting Hikers.

Woman in Orange lays out a tray on the counter with a cup &amp;amp; saucer, a teapot with a tea bag and it’s lid open wide to receive the hot water, a saucer waiting for the latte glass and a jug of milk.

Waitresses 2 &amp;amp; 3 arrive behind the counter; two young girls ready to start work.

The Woman in Orange indicates the tray and instructs Waitress 2 to finish the order.

Waitress 2 uses the machine to make a latte and places it on the waiting saucer.

The door opens and a Man, Woman, Boy &amp;amp; Girl walk in and approach the counter.

Waitress 2 - &quot;Hello, can I help you?&quot;

Woman - &quot;We have booked a table for lunch&quot;

Waitress 2 -&quot; Just a second and I will check your booking it for you&quot;

Waitress 2 quickly fetches a laptop from beneath the counter and confirms their reservation.

Waitress 2 escorts the family into another room.

Waitresses 2 &amp;amp; 3 confer then both start to move some furniture in the dining room.

The two Hikers look at each other in disbelief. They look at the tray in disbelief. Hiker 1 gets up and follows the waitresses. Hiker 2 follows Hiker 1.

Hiker 1 - “Excuse me! Aren’t you going to finish serving us first?”

Waitress 2 - “Are you the tea and coffee?”

Hikers 1 &amp;amp; 2 in unison - “Yes!”

Hiker 2 - “My coffee is sitting there getting cold waiting for you to make the tea! You shouldn’t  abandon one customer to serve the next.”

Waitress 2 calmly returns to the counter, pours hot water into the waiting teapot and delivers the tray to the Hikers. No sign of apology or embarrassment whatsoever.

Hikers look at each other in disbelief.
&lt;/xmp&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/libertybellenewsletter/image/small/n35/DSCN1793.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Deddington.&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Deddington.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Rachel Glombek</name></author><summary type="html">Thrupp to Aynho 23rd-27th January 2019</summary></entry></feed>